[
    {
        "id": "2de6e91b-22d8-435f-b44b-f56cc9ba5d27",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_001.txt",
        "created": 1737368927,
        "question": "What does 'endg\u00fcltig nicht bestanden' mean in the context of German universities?",
        "answer": "'Endg\u00fcltig nicht bestanden' means 'finally/definitively failed'. If you have finally failed a subject and you have therefore failed your degree, you are exempted from doing the same/similar degree anywhere else in Germany.",
        "request_id": "ef29f70fa26540bc2f96eca818c8bc04"
    },
    {
        "id": "8fca6b6b-6ad6-4249-bb5e-ae02a4dc662a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_001.txt",
        "created": 1737368927,
        "question": "What is the process to determine if a student who has 'endg\u00fcltig nicht bestanden' a degree can apply for a similar degree at TUM?",
        "answer": "The first step is to check whether the student's previous degree and the degree at TUM are similar enough ('fachverwandt'). This check needs to be done by the program heads at TUM, who need to know more details about the student's previous degree, such as the university and the modules that are part of the curriculum. If the two degrees are not similar enough, the student can apply with no problems. If the two degrees are highly similar, the student would likely be declined by TUM.",
        "request_id": "ef29f70fa26540bc2f96eca818c8bc04"
    },
    {
        "id": "972c1690-411d-4108-aa6d-55f866ef964c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_001.txt",
        "created": 1737368927,
        "question": "Would a situation of academic misconduct that resulted in a student's exmatriculation impact their application to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The first step is to check whether the student's previous degree and the AI in Society program at TUM are similar. If they are not similar, the student should be able to apply with no problems. If they are highly similar, the student will likely be declined by TUM.",
        "request_id": "ef29f70fa26540bc2f96eca818c8bc04"
    },
    {
        "id": "3947247c-229c-43e5-8c5a-849c5985d073",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_002.txt",
        "created": 1737368942,
        "question": "Would it be possible to consider an exemption for a student who was unable to complete only one class due to external circumstances?",
        "answer": "In this situation, it is really only about formalities from our university and cannot be decided by an interview with our admission committee or similar.",
        "request_id": "b1ae5c3c35ec86ea9c760955217a7ca9"
    },
    {
        "id": "9a3d7f5a-5b0d-4f8a-8b8a-5a9584911185",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_002.txt",
        "created": 1737368942,
        "question": "What does 'endg\u00fcltig nicht bestanden' mean in German universities?",
        "answer": "'Endg\u00fcltig nicht bestanden' means 'finally/definitively failed'. If you have finally failed a subject and you have therefore failed your degree, you are exempted from doing the same/similar degree anywhere else in Germany.",
        "request_id": "b1ae5c3c35ec86ea9c760955217a7ca9"
    },
    {
        "id": "14fdb72d-44e9-4063-9add-9bdc9e6709e7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_002.txt",
        "created": 1737368942,
        "question": "What is the process to check if a student who has 'endg\u00fcltig nicht bestanden' can apply to a similar degree program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The first step is to check whether your degree and our degree are similar enough ('fachverwandt'). This check needs to be done by our program heads, but for this we need to know more details about your previous degree, i.e. which university, which modules are part of the curriculum, etc. After we have done this check, there are two ways this could go: 1) Either we decide that the two degrees are not similar enough; then you can apply to us with no problems. Or: 2) We decide that the two degrees are highly similar; then you, unfortunately, would be declined by TUM.",
        "request_id": "b1ae5c3c35ec86ea9c760955217a7ca9"
    },
    {
        "id": "0447d623-6298-4594-9d77-9042bdc009ed",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_002.txt",
        "created": 1737368942,
        "question": "Would a situation of academic misconduct and subsequent exmatriculation impact an application to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "If you have finally failed a subject and you have therefore failed your degree, you are exempted from doing the same/similar degree anywhere else in Germany. The first step is to check whether your degree and our degree are similar enough ('fachverwandt'). If they are not similar, you should be able to apply with no problems. If they are highly similar, you will likely be declined by TUM.",
        "request_id": "b1ae5c3c35ec86ea9c760955217a7ca9"
    },
    {
        "id": "85cacc2f-c5a6-40f5-90ae-f7b0e051820b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_003.txt",
        "created": 1737368958,
        "question": "Regarding the practical project, would the Bachelor thesis be sufficient as I am writing about Industry 4.0 and its implementation?",
        "answer": "Yes, Bachelor\u2019s theses are also counted as practical projects, as long as the contents are suitable. The important thing is that the thesis meets the 18 ECTS requirement (if the thesis is the only project you\u2019re submitting), and that it is finished at the time of application. If it does not show up on your transcript, it cannot be counted.",
        "request_id": "e59a1545a2425294ffeebbe42eb21356"
    },
    {
        "id": "9a630edf-9a9b-4990-8088-ac7bd91528c9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_003.txt",
        "created": 1737368958,
        "question": "Is it necessary to submit an English proficiency certificate such as TOEFL or IELTS, or would my completed English and German courses be sufficient for this requirement?",
        "answer": "It is not necessary to submit English certificates, if instead you can prove your knowledge to us by \u201cEnglish as language of instruction\u201d during your Bachelor\u2019s studies, or if your thesis was written in English.",
        "request_id": "e59a1545a2425294ffeebbe42eb21356"
    },
    {
        "id": "bb33f14c-7e47-4d34-a367-6bb48f56eaf6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_003.txt",
        "created": 1737368958,
        "question": "Are there any other specific admission criteria I should be aware of or additional steps I might need to take?",
        "answer": "All of the relevant admission criteria and procedures can be found on the website.",
        "request_id": "e59a1545a2425294ffeebbe42eb21356"
    },
    {
        "id": "2e1036c0-62f2-4f26-84ae-9747b0400586",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_003.txt",
        "created": 1737368958,
        "question": "Is it possible to get a Letter of endorsement (Betreuungszusage) for a scholarship application?",
        "answer": "You should reach out to the study program head, Prof. [REDACTED]. She should be able to support you with this if you describe your situation well and that you are a prospective student.",
        "request_id": "e59a1545a2425294ffeebbe42eb21356"
    },
    {
        "id": "e2399d48-f21e-4651-91fa-c77917d39e58",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_004.txt",
        "created": 1737369124,
        "question": "Can students of various backgrounds apply to the Master\u2019s program?",
        "answer": "Yes, applications are open for students of various backgrounds. The field of the Bachelor\u2019s degree or work experience does not filter them.",
        "request_id": "eef4a4f1cf97785895e95d7178da4e02"
    },
    {
        "id": "9dba0738-bc8a-4ddb-abb3-5defbb1fec2c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_004.txt",
        "created": 1737369124,
        "question": "What are the application requirements for the Master\u2019s program?",
        "answer": "The application requirements can be found on the website. One of the requirements is that your previous study degree(s) should show at least 5 credit points from a mathematical/statistical subject.",
        "request_id": "eef4a4f1cf97785895e95d7178da4e02"
    },
    {
        "id": "b3800fb5-9e38-4c9b-9192-07e9cec86738",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_004.txt",
        "created": 1737369124,
        "question": "Is work experience relevant for fulfilling the practical project component of the Master\u2019s program?",
        "answer": "Yes, work experience is very relevant for fulfilling the practical project component.",
        "request_id": "eef4a4f1cf97785895e95d7178da4e02"
    },
    {
        "id": "eaffedc3-e80c-4fd4-9a7a-f82bf50ff639",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_005.txt",
        "created": 1737369131,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for M.Sc (AI in Society)?",
        "answer": "The format of the aptitude test is closed-book, so there are no additional aids allowed.",
        "request_id": "d161032783868c88470f9d8fc2cef775"
    },
    {
        "id": "90670d10-3d20-4f54-87e9-4620e5d7e520",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_006.txt",
        "created": 1737369134,
        "question": "What is the correct application period for the Master's program 'AI in Society' at TUM?",
        "answer": "The correct application period is 01-01 until 31-05.",
        "request_id": "446e872d622afb4d74e5b11857210c40"
    },
    {
        "id": "e286f599-1fa3-44f6-8fd5-73dd49b8df2f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_006.txt",
        "created": 1737369134,
        "question": "Is it possible to visit the TUM campus?",
        "answer": "The university campus is open at all times, so you can come and have a look anytime you want.",
        "request_id": "446e872d622afb4d74e5b11857210c40"
    },
    {
        "id": "658cb9ec-2c63-4045-91a1-f66e7ba2f9f2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_006.txt",
        "created": 1737369134,
        "question": "Where are the courses for the 'AI in Society' Master's program mainly held at TUM?",
        "answer": "The courses are dispersed across multiple buildings, mainly Richard-Wagner-Str. 1, Marsstr. 20-22, and Arcisstr. 21, which is the main campus of TUM.",
        "request_id": "446e872d622afb4d74e5b11857210c40"
    },
    {
        "id": "d8995d05-3e4b-4239-9b16-715c297fcabd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_006.txt",
        "created": 1737369134,
        "question": "Is it possible to talk to professors or students at TUM to get a deeper understanding of what the 'AI in Society' course is like?",
        "answer": "Talking to professors or students would need some organizing. However, if you have concrete questions, you can forward them to the email sender.",
        "request_id": "446e872d622afb4d74e5b11857210c40"
    },
    {
        "id": "2e451cb6-5ce9-4d29-8460-096d222b1c3a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_007.txt",
        "created": 1737369143,
        "question": "What are the requirements to enrol in the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "For all requirements, refer to the website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/. It contains all relevant information regarding application requirements, as well as the aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "fbd3c6f148b49b5bb3a86ad783250397"
    },
    {
        "id": "f548d061-b941-497d-b9e3-f1a8d7ce81a6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_007.txt",
        "created": 1737369143,
        "question": "Where can I find more information about the aptitude test and certain modules for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Information about the aptitude test and certain modules can be found on the website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/",
        "request_id": "fbd3c6f148b49b5bb3a86ad783250397"
    },
    {
        "id": "5c05f827-199d-4500-98a3-566472981e34",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_008.txt",
        "created": 1737369150,
        "question": "Can I apply for the Master AI in society program at TUM with a Bachelor's degree in Maschinenwesen?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can apply for the program with any Bachelor's degree. The final decision will depend on whether you meet the other admission requirements such as a practical project, entrance test, etc.",
        "request_id": "be9dc3c02e496bcddb9fa890d2170610"
    },
    {
        "id": "70c2b627-ed81-4a3e-b227-820fd98e3a9a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_008.txt",
        "created": 1737369150,
        "question": "Is a Bachelor's degree in social sciences, political sciences, economics, law, and psychology, or a related field a strict requirement for the MSc program in AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, it is not a strict requirement. You can apply with any Bachelor's degree.",
        "request_id": "be9dc3c02e496bcddb9fa890d2170610"
    },
    {
        "id": "59f86784-197f-4ce1-9eac-233530f506b6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_009.txt",
        "created": 1737369158,
        "question": "Should I select the 140 credits based on the best grades earned or the relevance to the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Please select the best grades. The relevance to AI in Society does not matter here.",
        "request_id": "305193c6fa34817625c2959acec0653f"
    },
    {
        "id": "e450b676-f633-4a39-a4be-1e7f9c68e6cc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_009.txt",
        "created": 1737369158,
        "question": "I have already completed a Master's degree. May I list the credits I earned during my master's study?",
        "answer": "No, please only list credits from your Bachelor\u2019s degree. We cannot actually take a Master\u2019s degree as basis for another Master\u2019s degree application. It will always be the Bachelor\u2019s degree that is relevant.",
        "request_id": "305193c6fa34817625c2959acec0653f"
    },
    {
        "id": "176d74ab-51a0-4193-a59c-39fdab34d523",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_010.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "Which courses did I apply for credit recognition in the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "You applied for credit recognition for the AI in Society courses \u201cFoundations of AI and [REDACTED]\u201d, \u201cIntroduction to Programming and [REDACTED]\u201d, \u201cLaw, Governance and Regulation of AI\u201d, and \u201cPsychology of Learning and [REDACTED] of AI-based Systems\u201d.",
        "request_id": "6a65314fe5e591fff50d0253057a3dd0"
    },
    {
        "id": "551cc123-07a6-4608-8b8d-e9056bac3950",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_010.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "Which course was granted recognition in the AI in Society program and what was the grade?",
        "answer": "The course \u201cIntroduction to Programming and [REDACTED]\u201d was granted recognition with grade 1.0.",
        "request_id": "6a65314fe5e591fff50d0253057a3dd0"
    },
    {
        "id": "62be1c66-ee06-4460-bc9c-95a99e12d4b4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_010.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "What was the decision on the rest of the cases for recognition in the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The rest of the cases for recognition were unfortunately declined.",
        "request_id": "6a65314fe5e591fff50d0253057a3dd0"
    },
    {
        "id": "4fa3fd8e-9736-4f9e-8f8c-de054aac85ee",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_011.txt",
        "created": 1737369172,
        "question": "What was the result of the credit recognition application for the AI in Society courses \u201cFoundations of AI and [REDACTED]\u201d, \u201cIntroduction to Programming and [REDACTED]\u201d and \u201cIntroduction to [REDACTED]\u201d?",
        "answer": "The credit recognition application for these courses was declined by the examination board.",
        "request_id": "cfdee4ce3f3e4da938ec7e626503102d"
    },
    {
        "id": "d486b10a-92bd-4d68-938d-75341545d58a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_012.txt",
        "created": 1737369175,
        "question": "What was the result of the credit recognition application for the AI in Society courses \u201cFoundations of AI and [REDACTED]\u201d and \u201cIntroduction to Programming and [REDACTED]\u201d?",
        "answer": "The credit recognition application for the AI in Society courses \u201cFoundations of AI and [REDACTED]\u201d and \u201cIntroduction to Programming and [REDACTED]\u201d was declined by the examination board.",
        "request_id": "40bbd973ad76dd1c2d90eb3be1d23205"
    },
    {
        "id": "4c4fa50e-dba9-49e8-8ee3-38a509a2dca9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_013.txt",
        "created": 1737369179,
        "question": "Could you kindly provide the individual scores for my academic performance and the writing test from the first stage of the application process?",
        "answer": "You had received 18 points based on your grades (academic performance) and 29 points in the written test. This led to 47 points in total, after which you were invited to the interview.",
        "request_id": "83c263551c5744e1554d8abfa58dcc97"
    },
    {
        "id": "0efdb33d-685b-41e8-bb1e-74b40c21050d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_014.txt",
        "created": 1737369183,
        "question": "Based on my academic and language qualifications, am I eligible to apply for the Master of Science \u201cAI in Society\u201d at your university?",
        "answer": "For language qualifications, you can look up the minimum scores here: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/application/application-info-portal/admission-requirements/language-certificates. For example, for IELTS, the minimum passing score is 6.5. Your English skills are also recognized if either a) English was the language of instruction at your home university, or b) your thesis is written in English. More info can be found on the website here at the bottom under \u201c[REDACTED]\u201d: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/",
        "request_id": "0c5f6035b8e5e252ed3e2ff8a69c250b"
    },
    {
        "id": "ca5c90e1-561a-431c-9a16-7c528463eb1d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_014.txt",
        "created": 1737369183,
        "question": "Could you please provide details about the application procedure?",
        "answer": "The entire application procedure can be found on the website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/",
        "request_id": "0c5f6035b8e5e252ed3e2ff8a69c250b"
    },
    {
        "id": "aeefd4c7-7d04-4fd9-8def-08b929f42d82",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_014.txt",
        "created": 1737369183,
        "question": "What is the earliest date I can submit my application, and what are the deadlines for the upcoming intake?",
        "answer": "The application portal opens on January 1st and closes on May 31st.",
        "request_id": "0c5f6035b8e5e252ed3e2ff8a69c250b"
    },
    {
        "id": "197eb241-83dc-4dac-8416-eb075815d7f2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_014.txt",
        "created": 1737369183,
        "question": "Could you share information about the tuition fees or any other costs associated with the program?",
        "answer": "The tuition fees per semester for students outside of the EU currently amount to 4000 euros. You can find more information about this here: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/fees/tuition",
        "request_id": "0c5f6035b8e5e252ed3e2ff8a69c250b"
    },
    {
        "id": "caa54bf0-0d1c-4ad6-a828-b8425dbdf108",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_015.txt",
        "created": 1737369195,
        "question": "Would being exmatriculated due to academic misconduct from a previous masters degree at a german university affect the application to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The first step is to check whether your previous degree and the MSc. AI in Society are similar. If they are not similar, you should be able to apply with no problems. If they are highly similar, you will likely be declined by TUM.",
        "request_id": "b122587d327dfc4298e9611a28df5e21"
    },
    {
        "id": "0b8f1058-6042-4ff1-8003-19b8a44b9608",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_016.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "When will the applications for the next admission period for the MSc. AI in Society program at TUM open and what is the deadline?",
        "answer": "The next admissions period will range from January 1st to May 31st, 2025.",
        "request_id": "3dd68400e5ac4fef3b4cea7911a97a60"
    },
    {
        "id": "c8de4356-ad28-4317-be2c-ed508aa61b0d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_016.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "When and how will the admissions test for the MSc. AI in Society program at TUM be conducted, and what will it consist of?",
        "answer": "The date for the next admissions test has not been set yet. However, last year it was at the end of June, with two more dates following in July and September. The contents of the test can be found on the program's website. Previous tests will not be handed out for practice.",
        "request_id": "3dd68400e5ac4fef3b4cea7911a97a60"
    },
    {
        "id": "146e8d26-074a-4b16-91ee-3db4ce308b28",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_016.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "Do I need to explicitly apply for scholarships for international students at TUM and if so, where and how can I apply for them?",
        "answer": "For all questions regarding scholarships, you should reach out to TUM\u2019s scholarship office. More information can be found on their website.",
        "request_id": "3dd68400e5ac4fef3b4cea7911a97a60"
    },
    {
        "id": "6a6bba38-0a35-4a5f-a1c7-2243a14cdb76",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_017.txt",
        "created": 1737369211,
        "question": "Should I take another English proficiency exam if my current certificate was issued in 2019?",
        "answer": "A more recent English certificate would be better. However, there are some other options to prove your English knowledge, which might apply to you. Please read through the information about English language proof at the bottom of the AI in Society application website.",
        "request_id": "e309a05e7bc3f04a50de45b4ed19fd60"
    },
    {
        "id": "e8b6168e-f6a8-4a59-8a7c-058ec733fdfc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_017.txt",
        "created": 1737369211,
        "question": "Is it acceptable to apply with 114 ECTS credits completed, expecting to have over the required 140 by February?",
        "answer": "If, at the point of your application, your transcript of records shows at least 140 passed ECTS, this is enough. Applications are open until May 31st.",
        "request_id": "e309a05e7bc3f04a50de45b4ed19fd60"
    },
    {
        "id": "bc0e91d1-c1e2-4a97-83d0-8ce503d1927b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_017.txt",
        "created": 1737369211,
        "question": "Will it be a problem if my thesis, which is a practical one on AI, only accounts for 12 ECTS credits instead of the recommended 18 in the application requirements?",
        "answer": "If you cannot provide at least 18 ECTS worth of practical experience with your application, the application will unfortunately be declined. However, practical experience outside of the university context, for example in the form of work experience, is also counted.",
        "request_id": "e309a05e7bc3f04a50de45b4ed19fd60"
    },
    {
        "id": "b130e751-3e34-4176-b478-94a2e927fb10",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_018.txt",
        "created": 1737369220,
        "question": "Does my practical course project of building an app to measure and manage the sustainability of business processes meet the program's requirements for practical projects?",
        "answer": "Both your projects are suitable for an application. Please list both of them in your application and describe them as best as possible. The decision in the end is not made by me, so I can\u2019t give you a 100% guarantee. Please take this as an informed estimate from my side.",
        "request_id": "343c9aa8e6fdd51699beb044074f8b98"
    },
    {
        "id": "7a570c02-783b-4d88-be47-9b1c841dce1a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_018.txt",
        "created": 1737369220,
        "question": "Does my bachelor\u2019s thesis project of implementing a GenAI app prototype for the [REDACTED] Department at Mercedes-Benz meet the criteria for admission?",
        "answer": "Both your projects are suitable for an application. Please list both of them in your application and describe them as best as possible. The decision in the end is not made by me, so I can\u2019t give you a 100% guarantee. Please take this as an informed estimate from my side.",
        "request_id": "343c9aa8e6fdd51699beb044074f8b98"
    },
    {
        "id": "c6956fd6-63e3-4283-8ef8-c64ece889793",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_018.txt",
        "created": 1737369220,
        "question": "Could you provide more insight into the assessment of political and social sciences in the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "I can\u2019t give out detailed information about the contents of the test, unfortunately, at least not beyond of what can be found on our website. However, I can tell you that we will not be asking very specific questions (like business law or similar). The test will be multiple choice, so you should be able to recognize the correct answers with general knowledge.",
        "request_id": "343c9aa8e6fdd51699beb044074f8b98"
    },
    {
        "id": "0a3e4401-c92f-4de2-a937-eb7ac84ac2f8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_019.txt",
        "created": 1737369232,
        "question": "Regarding the practical project, would the Bachelor thesis be sufficient as I am writing about Industry 4.0 and its implementation?",
        "answer": "Yes, Bachelor\u2019s theses are counted as practical projects, as long as the contents are suitable. The thesis must meet the 18 ECTS requirement (if the thesis is the only project you\u2019re submitting), and it must be finished at the time of application. If it does not show up on your transcript, it cannot be counted.",
        "request_id": "dbaeefa7feb117904e52e5aff6a41b6f"
    },
    {
        "id": "b6eb503e-8c95-4c27-951a-06b42b182ad0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_019.txt",
        "created": 1737369232,
        "question": "Is it necessary to submit an English proficiency certificate such as TOEFL or IELTS, or would my completed English and German courses be sufficient for this requirement?",
        "answer": "It is not necessary to submit English certificates, if instead you can prove your knowledge to us by \u201cEnglish as language of instruction\u201d during your Bachelor\u2019s studies, or if your thesis was written in English.",
        "request_id": "dbaeefa7feb117904e52e5aff6a41b6f"
    },
    {
        "id": "16106527-930f-4528-a5c3-5f3dbde4c461",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_019.txt",
        "created": 1737369232,
        "question": "Are there any other specific admission criteria I should be aware of or additional steps I might need to take?",
        "answer": "All of the relevant admission criteria and procedures can be found on the website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/",
        "request_id": "dbaeefa7feb117904e52e5aff6a41b6f"
    },
    {
        "id": "47ba381e-1893-4bbf-9657-3b4279ba6f89",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_020.txt",
        "created": 1737369245,
        "question": "Is it possible to get a waiver for the 140 ECTS credit requirement for the MSc. AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, exceptions cannot be made regarding the 140 ECTS credits \u2013 this is a hard requirement. It is a requirement to earn at least 2 more credits by the time of application at TUM (such that they are officially visible on the transcript of records).",
        "request_id": "4a402f2254597e8323d3125024abb2f4"
    },
    {
        "id": "cc75c904-3851-447d-92ce-8dc1bdc813f1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_020.txt",
        "created": 1737369245,
        "question": "Can courses with heavy coursework count as practical experience for the MSc. AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes, courses with heavy coursework could count as practical experience, depending on the contents. Practical projects outside of university, for example in the form of work experience, are also recognized. The important thing is to be able to prove this, for example, with a work certificate stating how long you have worked and what exactly you have done.",
        "request_id": "4a402f2254597e8323d3125024abb2f4"
    },
    {
        "id": "34f4c772-4f2d-483f-9d6c-134d0b50943a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_020.txt",
        "created": 1737369245,
        "question": "What can be done to address a shortfall in the required ECTS credits for the MSc. AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "You need to earn at least 2 more credits by the time of your application at TUM (such that they are officially visible on your transcript of records). Applications are open until May 31st, so possibly you can collect 2 more credits by then.",
        "request_id": "4a402f2254597e8323d3125024abb2f4"
    },
    {
        "id": "50233411-febf-4bf0-88b6-62b4a0daf5c4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_021.txt",
        "created": 1737369256,
        "question": "Which country does the applicant for the scholarship need to be from?",
        "answer": "The scholarship is open only for certain European countries.",
        "request_id": "a0e9a280b9ed90d58032ffcb530801ca"
    },
    {
        "id": "ea06a90d-b2fb-4ba9-99c4-258eea6bde7b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_021.txt",
        "created": 1737369256,
        "question": "Can applicants who have done their Bachelor\u2019s in Germany apply for the scholarship?",
        "answer": "No, only applicants without prior degrees from Germany can be considered for the scholarship.",
        "request_id": "a0e9a280b9ed90d58032ffcb530801ca"
    },
    {
        "id": "520c3dee-e9b7-4e56-9342-33e67aa1edd5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_021.txt",
        "created": 1737369256,
        "question": "Who needs to nominate the applicant for the scholarship?",
        "answer": "The applicant needs to be nominated by a professor.",
        "request_id": "a0e9a280b9ed90d58032ffcb530801ca"
    },
    {
        "id": "96a96cf9-c63c-4063-aa88-b7c19b1824bc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_023.txt",
        "created": 1737369264,
        "question": "Can I apply at the beginning of the application period next year if I have already completed modules worth 140 ECTS, but some of them are only rated as 'passed' or 'not passed'?",
        "answer": "No, that's not a problem. For us, it is only important that you have completed at least 140 ECTS. If some modules are only rated as passed/not passed, that's not a problem. For the calculation of the average grade, we only consider the actually graded modules, and weight accordingly.",
        "request_id": "569084e30794625702568b6210454e32"
    },
    {
        "id": "f28396e9-4e32-46e3-80f5-16b053d28410",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_025.txt",
        "created": 1737369271,
        "question": "What degree students are eligible to apply for this course?",
        "answer": "There is no restriction regarding Bachelor\u2019s degree programs \u2013 we welcome students from all backgrounds. It is only important that you fulfil the requirements which are listed on our website.",
        "request_id": "1533aca3d455bb919a1eb0deaf10a828"
    },
    {
        "id": "8a99be1e-68ed-49ac-9286-f029ff7d6e26",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_029.txt",
        "created": 1737369289,
        "question": "What is the content of the course '[REDACTED]: Hands-on with bootstrap and [REDACTED]' at LMU?",
        "answer": "The course covers empirical analyses through permutation- and bootstrap-based techniques. It offers a blend of theoretical foundation, computational principles, and key applications essential for causal inference. Using real-world examples, students will apply these methods to uncover causal relationships and draw robust conclusions. The course also includes hands-on projects for coding practice.",
        "request_id": "a16958ae86d065e90061d2dcb19a2d66"
    },
    {
        "id": "d4a7348b-eb24-4fb7-a04c-cb530067e3ad",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_029.txt",
        "created": 1737369289,
        "question": "How is the course '[REDACTED]: Hands-on with bootstrap and [REDACTED]' at LMU evaluated?",
        "answer": "The final grade is entirely based on an oral exam. Students will be evaluated based on applying basic mathematical tools, analyzing a real-world problem using the tools covered in class, and interpreting the empirical results and having a rigorous discussion about it.",
        "request_id": "a16958ae86d065e90061d2dcb19a2d66"
    },
    {
        "id": "9174f600-64af-4de0-914f-db46ae3763f0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_030.txt",
        "created": 1737369296,
        "question": "What can be done if the (project) modules taken do not make up 18 ECTS for the Master\u2019s program \u201cAI in Society\u201d at TUM?",
        "answer": "If the (project) modules you have taken do not make up 18 ECTS, you might also have work or internship experience we can count. If your program does not use ECTS, that is no problem \u2013 we receive a lot of international applications, which do not use ECTS either. In this case, we recalculate this ourselves. As an estimate, you can assume that 1 ECTS corresponds to 30 hours of work.",
        "request_id": "43201b37ec922e8b853d4464d7927206"
    },
    {
        "id": "e9282543-3789-422a-b77b-69d4621320a0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_030.txt",
        "created": 1737369296,
        "question": "Can projects that do not specifically and formally correspond to ECTS, but were part of the final grade, be considered for the 18 ECTS practical project requirement for the Master\u2019s program \u201cAI in Society\u201d at TUM?",
        "answer": "You should list all the projects you have done during your studies. It is only important that we can see those modules as passed modules on your grade transcript.",
        "request_id": "43201b37ec922e8b853d4464d7927206"
    },
    {
        "id": "c45bbbc0-43c3-4e82-9cb5-87c8b20bfabe",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_030.txt",
        "created": 1737369296,
        "question": "Can work experience be submitted as proof for the practical project requirement for the Master\u2019s program \u201cAI in Society\u201d at TUM?",
        "answer": "If you choose to submit possible work experience as proof for practical project, we will need to see a work certificate from your employer.",
        "request_id": "43201b37ec922e8b853d4464d7927206"
    },
    {
        "id": "5ea932c2-3f5e-44bf-96d0-ab364cb05205",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_031.txt",
        "created": 1737369310,
        "question": "Is there an estimation time for the decision regarding credit recognition?",
        "answer": "The decisions are finalized, we have just not sent them out yet.",
        "request_id": "d824d3dcb3bf673b1290e2aac9666ab9"
    },
    {
        "id": "6b9969fd-7a3a-417c-a24e-5ba8815a9734",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_031.txt",
        "created": 1737369310,
        "question": "What is the reason for the decline of my applications for credit recognition?",
        "answer": "Your applications have been declined because the courses you have attached stem from your Bachelor\u2019s degree, which was counted for your application to our Master\u2019s. There is a regulation which forbids us from recognizing such courses twice (i.e. additionally for our Master\u2019s).",
        "request_id": "d824d3dcb3bf673b1290e2aac9666ab9"
    },
    {
        "id": "4818018f-0305-48a0-9aff-3c77b03b9faa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_031.txt",
        "created": 1737369310,
        "question": "Can I apply for credit recognition for AI in Society courses with courses I have completed previously?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can apply for credit recognition for AI in Society courses with courses you have completed previously. However, if the courses were counted for your application to the Master's program, they cannot be recognized again for the Master's program.",
        "request_id": "d824d3dcb3bf673b1290e2aac9666ab9"
    },
    {
        "id": "98687bc8-04b1-4a39-9208-d9d48576a530",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_032.txt",
        "created": 1737369317,
        "question": "What is the process for selecting student representatives for the new AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Students are asked to vote for their preferred candidate via an anonymous poll. The three candidates with the most votes will be selected as student representatives.",
        "request_id": "7f117bd74d440c43769ae581c6dd02cc"
    },
    {
        "id": "7fae03ea-8193-4a81-a574-04bd7f837a8c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_032.txt",
        "created": 1737369317,
        "question": "Is there a deadline for voting in the student representative election for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Yes, the deadline for voting is the end of Friday, November 29th.",
        "request_id": "7f117bd74d440c43769ae581c6dd02cc"
    },
    {
        "id": "7aa47e85-2659-446f-b073-a072a63481f7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_032.txt",
        "created": 1737369317,
        "question": "What measures are in place to prevent cheating in the student representative election for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The number of eligible students is known, so if there are more votes than this number, it will be clear that something is wrong.",
        "request_id": "7f117bd74d440c43769ae581c6dd02cc"
    },
    {
        "id": "16270bfd-7b1a-431c-85d8-4a132a8e8fa8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_032.txt",
        "created": 1737369317,
        "question": "Can anyone vote in the student representative election for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The voting link allows anyone to vote without restrictions, but the organizers are counting on the integrity of the students to prevent cheating.",
        "request_id": "7f117bd74d440c43769ae581c6dd02cc"
    },
    {
        "id": "f004c667-808d-47f7-87e8-4f5b40e50296",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_033.txt",
        "created": 1737369326,
        "question": "What is the process for selecting student representatives for the Master\u2019s program 'AI in Society'?",
        "answer": "The program heads invite students to select 2-3 representatives. Candidates can introduce themselves in a document. The deadline for this will be Sunday, and the voting will be completed by Wednesday at 6 PM.",
        "request_id": "8b7d1787c8bebaa78bd6cf4d86e41573"
    },
    {
        "id": "c7c4664d-4897-4d48-8e25-7b74e097d9f7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_033.txt",
        "created": 1737369326,
        "question": "What is the role of the student representatives in the Master\u2019s program 'AI in Society'?",
        "answer": "The aim is to hold regular meetings with the elected representatives to discuss current matters and explore initiatives that can further enhance the quality of the program. Once elected, the representatives should reach out to the program heads to schedule an initial meeting.",
        "request_id": "8b7d1787c8bebaa78bd6cf4d86e41573"
    },
    {
        "id": "089ed286-9940-4182-8ba8-09fda4904e13",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_033.txt",
        "created": 1737369326,
        "question": "When will the results of the student representative election for the Master\u2019s program 'AI in Society' be available?",
        "answer": "The results of the student representative election will be available after the voting is completed by Wednesday at 6 PM.",
        "request_id": "8b7d1787c8bebaa78bd6cf4d86e41573"
    },
    {
        "id": "312ddc6b-aeca-4f52-8a89-9db5c20d0cae",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_034.txt",
        "created": 1737369335,
        "question": "What are the details of the proposed AI in Society master student gathering?",
        "answer": "The gathering is planned to be a Thanksgiving potluck. It is scheduled for the 28th from 5\u20139 p.m. The attendees will be AIS master's degree students and their acquaintances, as well as AIS faculties. The preferred location is one of the HfP areas, specifically the 1st floor big room. The organizers will comply with existing rules, including noise control and alcohol consumption, and will be responsible for cleaning up and waste management.",
        "request_id": "7bc066b049e453c55d1ba43f920730b9"
    },
    {
        "id": "b41d5720-40c9-495e-9a6a-31176cf874b8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_035.txt",
        "created": 1737369341,
        "question": "Which are the criteria to comply for the project week?",
        "answer": "The program heads decide which project weeks are suitable. The participation in a project week is mandatory for the AI in Society curriculum, and you need to complete one in order to graduate. There is no limit of project weeks you can participate in, but places are limited, and the participation in a project week needs you to dedicate (at least) a full week of your time during the semester.",
        "request_id": "0ee3d75d6273b6bd32ac8f1ef1abab58"
    },
    {
        "id": "0a979a11-5286-43ea-8263-639af1c7e0ce",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_035.txt",
        "created": 1737369341,
        "question": "Could these following project weeks count for our Master (AI in Society) as well?",
        "answer": "The first project week would comply, however the second one would not.",
        "request_id": "0ee3d75d6273b6bd32ac8f1ef1abab58"
    },
    {
        "id": "6e18746b-2008-4c4b-b904-28b44e23a4d3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_035.txt",
        "created": 1737369341,
        "question": "Will we have classes during this week of the Project Week?",
        "answer": "Yes, there will still be lectures during the project weeks. However, the concept of the project weeks is that there will be no critical contents (as far as possible) during this week in the lectures.",
        "request_id": "0ee3d75d6273b6bd32ac8f1ef1abab58"
    },
    {
        "id": "4d517fc1-0676-43ea-a747-ba524316bfb7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_035.txt",
        "created": 1737369341,
        "question": "I am doing several extras courses that are not in our list of electives, what should I do to count those as electives?",
        "answer": "You can send the courses you are taking to the program heads. However, AIS students are intended to choose from the electives that are listed. You are free to take up additional courses, but they can\u2019t be counted if they\u2019re not part of the study degree.",
        "request_id": "0ee3d75d6273b6bd32ac8f1ef1abab58"
    },
    {
        "id": "ee9b49e9-6ebb-4a90-9463-8d70c9b60d70",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_036.txt",
        "created": 1737369354,
        "question": "Is a grade of 2,2 and 210 credit points sufficient to get into the Masters program of AI in Society at TU Munich?",
        "answer": "The requirement is that you have at least 140 completed credits at the point of your application. If this holds, this is sufficient. Grade-wise, it's not the only factor for admission. The grade only makes up one part of the point calculation. The other part is made up of the aptitude test, which you will need to take.",
        "request_id": "f6860042b89517c4e5d71a6f96c9dfd1"
    },
    {
        "id": "4828c4ec-4013-424f-a380-2d1c6223b93f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_036.txt",
        "created": 1737369354,
        "question": "How can I satisfy the requirement of a project worth at least 18 credit points for the Masters program of AI in Society at TU Munich, if I don't have a single project worth that much?",
        "answer": "You don\u2019t need to provide one single project worth 18 credits, you can also specify multiple ones which in sum make up 18 credits. However, regarding your thesis: keep in mind that we can only count your thesis as a project module if it will be completed at the point of your application (i.e. the 15 ECTS are officially part of your transcript at that point).",
        "request_id": "f6860042b89517c4e5d71a6f96c9dfd1"
    },
    {
        "id": "a4b734a0-568d-4968-b97e-532d09b966a9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_037.txt",
        "created": 1737369363,
        "question": "Could these following project weeks count for our Master (AI in Society) as well?",
        "answer": "The first project week would comply with us, however the second one would not.",
        "request_id": "5ae24bebb40dcc12249210a9c2d8c971"
    },
    {
        "id": "e69de086-c9ef-4dd1-b3ac-6518a8059cf1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_037.txt",
        "created": 1737369363,
        "question": "Will we have classes during this week of the Project Week?",
        "answer": "Yes, there will still be lectures. However, the concept of the project weeks is that there will be no critical contents (as far as possible) during this week in the lectures.",
        "request_id": "5ae24bebb40dcc12249210a9c2d8c971"
    },
    {
        "id": "f406ee8d-76bd-4ac7-8bf4-9412df8a598f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_037.txt",
        "created": 1737369363,
        "question": "When does the project week at TUM usually take place?",
        "answer": "The project week at TUM (usually) takes place during a week in January.",
        "request_id": "5ae24bebb40dcc12249210a9c2d8c971"
    },
    {
        "id": "847cf7d5-961d-4192-ae3c-eea687ada886",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_037.txt",
        "created": 1737369363,
        "question": "Is participation in a project week mandatory for the AI in Society curriculum?",
        "answer": "In the AI in Society curriculum, the participation in a project week is mandatory, so you need to complete one in order to graduate.",
        "request_id": "5ae24bebb40dcc12249210a9c2d8c971"
    },
    {
        "id": "0a815149-aa4f-4370-b630-2baf78ce645f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_037.txt",
        "created": 1737369363,
        "question": "Is there a limit to the number of project weeks a student can participate in?",
        "answer": "There is no limit of project weeks you can participate in, so if you really want to do multiple, you can. Keep in mind, however, that places are limited, and the participation in a project week needs you to dedicate (at least) a full week of your time during the semester.",
        "request_id": "5ae24bebb40dcc12249210a9c2d8c971"
    },
    {
        "id": "756f5607-5810-4c9c-b322-243832a22012",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_038.txt",
        "created": 1737369375,
        "question": "Is it required to officially book a venue if we want to use one of the rooms for a potluck event?",
        "answer": "Yes, it would be best if you officially booked a room for this, but you cannot do that yourself.",
        "request_id": "d2b4f69be87c814fe34011d26646cdd2"
    },
    {
        "id": "f4f8eb71-d480-40a2-b586-edfd3bc3872a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_038.txt",
        "created": 1737369375,
        "question": "Who should be contacted for assistance in booking a room for an event?",
        "answer": "You should reach out to the student representatives of the department and ask for their assistance, since they must have experience in organizing such events.",
        "request_id": "d2b4f69be87c814fe34011d26646cdd2"
    },
    {
        "id": "f5b5f6be-d820-4634-a94c-3d3e53f463c1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_038.txt",
        "created": 1737369375,
        "question": "Can I ask for your help in the process of organizing this event?",
        "answer": "If you need any of my help in the process, please let me know (also for announcing this get-together via email for everybody).",
        "request_id": "d2b4f69be87c814fe34011d26646cdd2"
    },
    {
        "id": "aee55072-c4ab-4a4a-beb0-82499180a103",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_039.txt",
        "created": 1737369380,
        "question": "Does the course \u201cResearch and Methods\u201d meet the requirement of having 5 ECTS in mathematics/statistics for the 'AI in Society' program?",
        "answer": "The course \u201cResearch and Methods\u201d would pass as sufficient, if a description of what has been taught in the course is provided, so it can be seen that there were indeed statistical methods taught.",
        "request_id": "dff5a1d127517f815caed5fe0260db13"
    },
    {
        "id": "b8258a9c-666e-40c4-9140-c4e47872b7e4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_039.txt",
        "created": 1737369380,
        "question": "What is meant with \u2019technical tools\u2019 or \u2019similar\u2019 in relation to the 18 ECTS practical project for the 'AI in Society' program?",
        "answer": "The project should involve a practical aspect, e.g. you should have investigated or worked on a societal problem with technical tools, for example programming, statistical analysis, or similar.",
        "request_id": "dff5a1d127517f815caed5fe0260db13"
    },
    {
        "id": "cb7dcd59-94ef-4319-9766-59344c7ae9ca",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_039.txt",
        "created": 1737369380,
        "question": "Does it matter during which period of the application opening (between February and May 31st) I apply for the 'AI in Society' program?",
        "answer": "It technically does not matter when in this period you send your application. However, due to the big amount of applications, the aptitude test might be split up into multiple dates. It is recommended to submit your application rather sooner than later.",
        "request_id": "dff5a1d127517f815caed5fe0260db13"
    },
    {
        "id": "359e3e95-9ab9-4b2f-87b2-4772970ba196",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_039.txt",
        "created": 1737369380,
        "question": "What is the recommended preparation for the 'AI in Society' program?",
        "answer": "It is highly suggested to brush up on mathematical knowledge, especially statistics, linear algebra, and calculus. These are topics to help you study machine learning and data science, which will already be taught from the first semester onwards.",
        "request_id": "dff5a1d127517f815caed5fe0260db13"
    },
    {
        "id": "1388598d-536b-4ef8-815c-e5554fb6006e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_039.txt",
        "created": 1737369380,
        "question": "Can a BA thesis be used as \u2018proof\u2019 of a practical project for the 'AI in Society' program?",
        "answer": "The project described might be a bit insufficient, regarding the technical aspect. It is up to the selection committee to decide in the end, but it is encouraged to apply and describe your projects as best as possible. It is also suggested to submit all of the practical experience you have \u2013 you don\u2019t have to choose only one of them.",
        "request_id": "dff5a1d127517f815caed5fe0260db13"
    },
    {
        "id": "1dbe2932-9b93-4ee9-9335-b0f3a7d66bef",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_040.txt",
        "created": 1737369398,
        "question": "Did the student forget to attach the document for the Sociology module in the email?",
        "answer": "Yes, the student forgot to attach the document for the Sociology module in the email.",
        "request_id": "9c516167dd5942583dae535a427de80c"
    },
    {
        "id": "3202fffc-5362-4121-9c5e-c934bb6cf409",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_040.txt",
        "created": 1737369398,
        "question": "Has the student's application for recognition of the \u201cIntroduction to Programming\u201d course been approved?",
        "answer": "Yes, the professors have approved the recognition for the \u201cIntroduction to Programming\u201d course.",
        "request_id": "9c516167dd5942583dae535a427de80c"
    },
    {
        "id": "ef0f282d-ec45-40d8-b1e8-ccf8a83e0063",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_040.txt",
        "created": 1737369398,
        "question": "Will the \u201cFoundations of AI and [REDACTED]\u201d lecture be recognized for the student?",
        "answer": "No, the \u201cFoundations of AI and [REDACTED]\u201d lecture will not be recognized, so the student will have to attend and write the exam as usual.",
        "request_id": "9c516167dd5942583dae535a427de80c"
    },
    {
        "id": "b6eeae90-cdbd-4347-9651-e56ce956bee7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_040.txt",
        "created": 1737369398,
        "question": "What is missing from the student's application for recognition of credits?",
        "answer": "Module descriptions from the student's courses are missing from the application for recognition of credits.",
        "request_id": "9c516167dd5942583dae535a427de80c"
    },
    {
        "id": "6c793478-d81d-4722-85f7-7fb647ff736d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_040.txt",
        "created": 1737369398,
        "question": "Has the student sent the curriculum for the Sociology class?",
        "answer": "Yes, the student has sent the curriculum for the Sociology class.",
        "request_id": "9c516167dd5942583dae535a427de80c"
    },
    {
        "id": "528cf337-69af-463c-8f29-274722e0b66e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_041.txt",
        "created": 1737369407,
        "question": "Can I discuss the 'AI in Society' Master program and its admission requirements in person?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can discuss the program and its requirements in person. Available meeting slots are between 14-17 on the next day, Wednesday between 11-12 or 14-17, or next Tuesday from 14-17. The meeting location is Richard-Wagner-Str. 1 (rightmost entrance), 3rd floor, room B.359.",
        "request_id": "6f910297f1bee5d58beb1b7184c2ae4c"
    },
    {
        "id": "f62ddf1c-ac23-4c87-9585-85ce6a58d6e4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_041.txt",
        "created": 1737369407,
        "question": "What should I bring to the meeting to discuss the 'AI in Society' Master program?",
        "answer": "You should bring any documents you have, like transcripts of your studies, to the meeting.",
        "request_id": "6f910297f1bee5d58beb1b7184c2ae4c"
    },
    {
        "id": "a71536f4-6ae4-4b33-b430-f897601b9993",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_041.txt",
        "created": 1737369407,
        "question": "Is a meeting at 15:00 the next day acceptable to discuss the 'AI in Society' Master program?",
        "answer": "Yes, a meeting at 15:00 the next day is acceptable.",
        "request_id": "6f910297f1bee5d58beb1b7184c2ae4c"
    },
    {
        "id": "d5099d2f-f165-4e27-949e-b148ce572bca",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_042.txt",
        "created": 1737369414,
        "question": "Are the requirements and acceptance criteria for enrolling in the Master\u2019s program met with a previously completed bachelor's in computer science from EPITA in France?",
        "answer": "Technically, your degree will be sufficient for applying to us. However, we cannot find EPITA as an accredited institution in our databases. Therefore, along with your application, we would highly recommend you to also get a Confirmation of accreditation from the [REDACTED] of Education.",
        "request_id": "795e814610fb279c06c303304c066cac"
    },
    {
        "id": "8b5c0fb8-31db-4a56-ab23-7ccae2ec4d14",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_044.txt",
        "created": 1737369420,
        "question": "What platform does TUM use for online examinations?",
        "answer": "TUM uses moodle for online examinations.",
        "request_id": "113707f98c3d1baccf4ed526b2e7673d"
    },
    {
        "id": "ac3335b1-ee57-4b22-abdf-40419173ffa9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_044.txt",
        "created": 1737369420,
        "question": "How can a test be created on Moodle?",
        "answer": "To create a test on Moodle, first go to the course and click on 'Edit' in the top right corner. Then, in the respective week where you want to insert the test, click on 'Create activity or material'. From there, you can select 'Test' and set it up as desired.",
        "request_id": "113707f98c3d1baccf4ed526b2e7673d"
    },
    {
        "id": "a809e09a-0d60-4b80-b28f-e6fc3bc8b1d6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_044.txt",
        "created": 1737369420,
        "question": "Is there a software known for conducting tests (MC and [REDACTED])?",
        "answer": "For such tests, moodle is usually used.",
        "request_id": "113707f98c3d1baccf4ed526b2e7673d"
    },
    {
        "id": "4800ee58-62bf-46b9-8b6a-a495653aac7e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_045.txt",
        "created": 1737369427,
        "question": "Can I discuss the admission requirements and course recognition for the 'AI in Society' Master program in person?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can discuss your questions in person. Available appointment slots include tomorrow between 14-17, Wednesday between 11-12 or 14-17, or next Tuesday from 14-17. The meeting location is Richard-Wagner-Str. 1 (rightmost entrance), 3rd floor, room B.359. It would be best if you could bring along any documents you have, like transcripts of your studies.",
        "request_id": "1dffc54433ba936b55e3a81351bf7d71"
    },
    {
        "id": "5cce9f52-c41e-4cef-b6da-c32754b85e1b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_046.txt",
        "created": 1737369431,
        "question": "Can a student be manually added into a course after the registration period has expired?",
        "answer": "Yes, a student can be manually added into a course after the registration period has expired.",
        "request_id": "4393c14ac4eb8ce3c7cf8f76e3edd5b6"
    },
    {
        "id": "02cc54f6-a523-4ca3-9f5b-75f744a43008",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_046.txt",
        "created": 1737369431,
        "question": "What software is used for creating tests at TUM?",
        "answer": "Moodle is used for creating tests at TUM.",
        "request_id": "4393c14ac4eb8ce3c7cf8f76e3edd5b6"
    },
    {
        "id": "008e4877-d395-4090-a862-0b58c7eeb5fb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_046.txt",
        "created": 1737369431,
        "question": "How can a test be created on Moodle?",
        "answer": "To create a test on Moodle, first go to the course and click on 'Edit' at the top right. Then in the respective week where you want to insert the test, click on 'Create activity or material'. From there, you can select 'Test' and customize it as desired.",
        "request_id": "4393c14ac4eb8ce3c7cf8f76e3edd5b6"
    },
    {
        "id": "5bbaf086-c50f-4882-909c-d3f566d32b11",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_048.txt",
        "created": 1737369439,
        "question": "Are applications for the MSc. AI in Society only open for the winter semester?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can only apply for the MSc. AI in Society for a winter semester; the studies don\u2019t start in a summer semester.",
        "request_id": "67a35edf3bd759648439f11edfdb872e"
    },
    {
        "id": "239e7d75-fe1c-4d1b-b280-8cd5037c658a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_048.txt",
        "created": 1737369439,
        "question": "When do applications open for the next winter semester for the MSc. AI in Society?",
        "answer": "The applications for the next winter semester (starting in October 2025) will open in January/February 2025.",
        "request_id": "67a35edf3bd759648439f11edfdb872e"
    },
    {
        "id": "05353ba1-0a30-4da9-8ed7-80530405522b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_051.txt",
        "created": 1737368934,
        "question": "Can I have my Bachelor's courses recognized?",
        "answer": "If the courses are from the Bachelor's degree you applied with and were counted towards that degree, they cannot be recognized again. However, additional courses that were not counted towards the degree but were taken during the Bachelor's program could potentially be recognized, provided they were not used in the evaluation during the Master's application process.",
        "request_id": "23c7d76c890e3c536cbd588decd0384e"
    },
    {
        "id": "fb607399-b299-40af-a1cd-f4f3f1fcebc3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_051.txt",
        "created": 1737368934,
        "question": "Is there a maximum number of courses/ECTS that can be recognized?",
        "answer": "There is no maximum number, however, if the sum of the recognized ECTS is higher than 21, the student must be upgraded.",
        "request_id": "23c7d76c890e3c536cbd588decd0384e"
    },
    {
        "id": "4d440e5b-0f4e-453d-adbe-8525df992b7b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_051.txt",
        "created": 1737368934,
        "question": "As my previous Dutch university uses a different grading system, I am not sure about the grade conversion. If during the meeting with the departmental student academic advisor it turns out that the conversion is very disadvantageous for me, can I still withdraw my application?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can withdraw a recognition if the grade conversion is unfavorable. However, you cannot submit a recognition for a module in which you have already attempted the examination. Prior achievements can only be submitted once in total.",
        "request_id": "23c7d76c890e3c536cbd588decd0384e"
    },
    {
        "id": "ffe91613-f2a2-4658-8c77-296247e39f12",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_051.txt",
        "created": 1737368934,
        "question": "If an application is approved and a course I have already passed is recognized and its grade is transferred, can I still take the equivalent course at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, not in the same degree program.",
        "request_id": "23c7d76c890e3c536cbd588decd0384e"
    },
    {
        "id": "9de1e55b-b67c-4ab1-8ff2-469603274e8b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_051.txt",
        "created": 1737368934,
        "question": "Can I improve the grade of the already recognized achievement through the TUM course?",
        "answer": "No.",
        "request_id": "23c7d76c890e3c536cbd588decd0384e"
    },
    {
        "id": "4fdce0f0-9e5f-4896-b72e-c39b1091eb59",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_051.txt",
        "created": 1737368934,
        "question": "Can I keep the grade of the recognized achievement in case I get a worse grade in the TUM course?",
        "answer": "No.",
        "request_id": "23c7d76c890e3c536cbd588decd0384e"
    },
    {
        "id": "b140898a-6526-4ca6-a504-0b35f25f74a0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_054.txt",
        "created": 1737368950,
        "question": "What is the minimum number of credits required for successful graduation from the program?",
        "answer": "The program requires 120 ECTS for graduation.",
        "request_id": "bdba78e943c25815a85055c99538dd6c"
    },
    {
        "id": "fe98173f-bc5e-4cfe-946e-f786e52e522d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_054.txt",
        "created": 1737368950,
        "question": "Can credits from two different project weeks be counted cumulatively?",
        "answer": "Yes, the credits from two project weeks can be counted cumulatively.",
        "request_id": "bdba78e943c25815a85055c99538dd6c"
    },
    {
        "id": "1d7a1321-6eef-4659-99dd-65def19c7c87",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_054.txt",
        "created": 1737368950,
        "question": "When does the project week at TUM usually take place?",
        "answer": "The project week at TUM usually takes place during a week in January.",
        "request_id": "bdba78e943c25815a85055c99538dd6c"
    },
    {
        "id": "8e89c4bb-7f5a-42f6-9037-a4ed200ffaed",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_054.txt",
        "created": 1737368950,
        "question": "Is participation in a project week mandatory in the AI in Society curriculum?",
        "answer": "Yes, participation in a project week is mandatory in the AI in Society curriculum.",
        "request_id": "bdba78e943c25815a85055c99538dd6c"
    },
    {
        "id": "5d1e3cd0-1486-4275-8e30-ac1734f23298",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_054.txt",
        "created": 1737368950,
        "question": "Is there a limit to the number of project weeks a student can participate in?",
        "answer": "No, there is no limit to the number of project weeks a student can participate in, but places are limited and participation requires dedicating at least a full week of your time during the semester.",
        "request_id": "bdba78e943c25815a85055c99538dd6c"
    },
    {
        "id": "3f17ce40-55bb-4a9c-8743-ccafede909fa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_055.txt",
        "created": 1737368958,
        "question": "What are the admission requirements for the AI in [REDACTED]'s Program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The program welcomes students from all kinds of backgrounds, including psychology. It is important that you bring along some technical understanding, such as statistics. An engineering background is not required per se, though it is listed as a field of the aptitude test \u2013 these fields also refer to a high school graduate level.",
        "request_id": "27dd482f718f93b59a5c9f1ee64ce16e"
    },
    {
        "id": "b2359d42-0c69-4126-b5e7-5629bcf1d77d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_055.txt",
        "created": 1737368958,
        "question": "Is the AI in [REDACTED]'s Program at TUM suitable for a psychology graduate with a strong interest in digital mental health?",
        "answer": "Yes, the program could be a good fit for a psychology graduate with a strong interest in digital mental health, as long as they have some technical understanding.",
        "request_id": "27dd482f718f93b59a5c9f1ee64ce16e"
    },
    {
        "id": "01279815-59d7-4caa-b571-fb1806d509f8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_057.txt",
        "created": 1737368972,
        "question": "Can I discuss the 'AI in Society' Master program and its admission requirements in person?",
        "answer": "Yes, there is an option to discuss the program and its requirements in person or via a zoom meeting.",
        "request_id": "485a1e329c388b5cc7553e0521df797e"
    },
    {
        "id": "56baef0e-a619-4e88-b95e-5f9c7cf03755",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_058.txt",
        "created": 1737368975,
        "question": "Do I meet the requirement of having 5 ECTS in mathematics/statistics passed if I successfully completed a 7.5 ECTS module on \u201cResearch and Methods\u201d?",
        "answer": "Your course \u201cResearch and Methods\u201d would pass as sufficient, if you also provide us a description of what has been taught in the course, so we can see that there were indeed statistical methods taught.",
        "request_id": "4fedd8b24029bbbd8ee255f66ec8de7c"
    },
    {
        "id": "a4a05b68-aea3-4296-91e1-330d07d9058d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_058.txt",
        "created": 1737368975,
        "question": "Would you be able to tell me whether (one of the) following courses does/does not meet this requirement?",
        "answer": "From the other courses you mentioned, I would actually recommend you to follow [REDACTED] with R, just for your own sake, so you have a bit more background knowledge to help you when you start in AI in Society.",
        "request_id": "4fedd8b24029bbbd8ee255f66ec8de7c"
    },
    {
        "id": "44c6a596-9836-4a3b-b0fc-a232d3fba8fe",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_058.txt",
        "created": 1737368975,
        "question": "Does it matter during which period of the application opening (between February and May 31st) I apply for the program?",
        "answer": "It technically does not matter when in this period you send your application. However, due to the big amount applications, this year we had to split up the aptitude test into multiple dates. Please don\u2019t take \u201cfirst come, first serve\u201d as a solid rule here, but I would recommend submitting your application rather sooner than later.",
        "request_id": "4fedd8b24029bbbd8ee255f66ec8de7c"
    },
    {
        "id": "0d670ffd-cc33-4452-9498-483fdc19bca2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_059.txt",
        "created": 1737368988,
        "question": "Where can I find the modules \u201cModule of Social and [REDACTED] (Sociology)\u201d and \u201cModule of Social and [REDACTED] ([REDACTED])\u201d in the module descriptions?",
        "answer": "The modules were found in the attached documents.",
        "request_id": "f3055d22908b3cf5be1b65c8a87b9e5a"
    },
    {
        "id": "30ff54c9-6f74-4bdd-80f4-dadd2299cc9e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_059.txt",
        "created": 1737368988,
        "question": "What documents are missing from my application?",
        "answer": "Module descriptions from your courses are missing from your application.",
        "request_id": "f3055d22908b3cf5be1b65c8a87b9e5a"
    },
    {
        "id": "87e49948-bc29-4a3c-9fc5-c29e04d863cb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_059.txt",
        "created": 1737368988,
        "question": "What is the purpose of the module descriptions in the application?",
        "answer": "The module descriptions are needed to understand the contents of your courses.",
        "request_id": "f3055d22908b3cf5be1b65c8a87b9e5a"
    },
    {
        "id": "ee517c90-4232-4f06-af85-ce0890a2e1dc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_059.txt",
        "created": 1737368988,
        "question": "What subjects am I applying for recognition of credits for?",
        "answer": "You are applying for recognition of credits for the following subjects: \"Foundations of AI and [REDACTED]\" course, \"Psychology of Learning and [REDACTED] of AI-based System\", and \"Governance, law and regulation of AI\".",
        "request_id": "f3055d22908b3cf5be1b65c8a87b9e5a"
    },
    {
        "id": "08eb98ef-e443-4ae9-9424-5e6474357369",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_059.txt",
        "created": 1737368988,
        "question": "How many hours per week did I study for these subjects?",
        "answer": "You estimated approximately 8 hours per week, but you are waiting for confirmation from your university.",
        "request_id": "f3055d22908b3cf5be1b65c8a87b9e5a"
    },
    {
        "id": "75ef55be-efde-4cd3-8206-9e504d1cc992",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_060.txt",
        "created": 1737368998,
        "question": "What additional documents are required for the application for recognition of credits?",
        "answer": "Module descriptions from your courses are required for the application for recognition of credits.",
        "request_id": "afd4c686aeed21c191d918ab1b89942d"
    },
    {
        "id": "034759a3-f934-436e-9712-2351aa8329b8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_060.txt",
        "created": 1737368998,
        "question": "Why are module descriptions needed for the application for recognition of credits?",
        "answer": "Module descriptions are needed to understand the contents of your courses.",
        "request_id": "afd4c686aeed21c191d918ab1b89942d"
    },
    {
        "id": "804f509b-d9b6-4d0f-82cc-b0b1cf983bb6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_060.txt",
        "created": 1737368998,
        "question": "What subjects are being considered for recognition of credits?",
        "answer": "The subjects being considered for recognition of credits are 'Foundations of AI and [REDACTED]', 'Psychology of Learning and [REDACTED] of AI-based System', and 'Governance, law and regulation of AI'.",
        "request_id": "afd4c686aeed21c191d918ab1b89942d"
    },
    {
        "id": "243d3a20-0cb0-463a-b937-48cbf236c031",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_060.txt",
        "created": 1737368998,
        "question": "How were the hours studied per week calculated for the application for recognition of credits?",
        "answer": "The hours studied per week were calculated by the applicant as approximately 8 hours, but they are clarifying it with the university where they took the course and waiting for their confirmation.",
        "request_id": "afd4c686aeed21c191d918ab1b89942d"
    },
    {
        "id": "ca7d4524-a5f7-4ae1-ab44-efe86f3daa68",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_061.txt",
        "created": 1737369006,
        "question": "What additional documents are needed for the application for recognition of credits?",
        "answer": "Module descriptions from your courses are needed for the application for recognition of credits.",
        "request_id": "0fc339b2c31cdd36dad2f748740433d2"
    },
    {
        "id": "69fde613-770e-4876-b1ff-f542291ea34e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_061.txt",
        "created": 1737369006,
        "question": "Why are module descriptions needed for the application?",
        "answer": "Module descriptions are needed to understand the contents of your courses.",
        "request_id": "0fc339b2c31cdd36dad2f748740433d2"
    },
    {
        "id": "517f1c56-eaf6-41ca-ae82-b70fb4548f14",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_061.txt",
        "created": 1737369006,
        "question": "How are the hours studied per week calculated for the subjects?",
        "answer": "The hours studied per week for the subjects are calculated by the applicant, but should be confirmed by the university where the course was taken.",
        "request_id": "0fc339b2c31cdd36dad2f748740433d2"
    },
    {
        "id": "1b494843-c7ed-48fb-a822-0184d93c796b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_065.txt",
        "created": 1737369017,
        "question": "What should a student do if they can't see the registration button?",
        "answer": "The student should send an email to the course administrator.",
        "request_id": "e2449036883b6e2034e7baf82a659781"
    },
    {
        "id": "4e62b1e7-f1f4-49a1-bbfe-611aa65c0c34",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_065.txt",
        "created": 1737369017,
        "question": "What could be wrong if a student still can't see the registration button?",
        "answer": "The registration period might have ended.",
        "request_id": "e2449036883b6e2034e7baf82a659781"
    },
    {
        "id": "24d36dd4-6779-4335-a50c-e7c65080cd8b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_065.txt",
        "created": 1737369017,
        "question": "What should a student do if they have just enrolled successfully but the system shows registration expired?",
        "answer": "The student should seek help to be manually added into the course.",
        "request_id": "e2449036883b6e2034e7baf82a659781"
    },
    {
        "id": "42580d74-572c-469e-8843-ed62f24cc3cc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_065.txt",
        "created": 1737369017,
        "question": "What is the solution if the registration period has ended and a student still needs to register?",
        "answer": "The course administrator can extend the registration period.",
        "request_id": "e2449036883b6e2034e7baf82a659781"
    },
    {
        "id": "b960e9c3-7a7d-49b7-b0b5-c635eb0b9b63",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_066.txt",
        "created": 1737369022,
        "question": "Why can't a student see the registration button?",
        "answer": "The registration period might have ended.",
        "request_id": "335818b05525a0ed0a7a6fb5692c863a"
    },
    {
        "id": "ccfbd620-4fc9-4659-9904-a3d7e8121809",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_066.txt",
        "created": 1737369022,
        "question": "What is the solution if a student can't see the registration button?",
        "answer": "The registration period can be extended.",
        "request_id": "335818b05525a0ed0a7a6fb5692c863a"
    },
    {
        "id": "9755eaf7-9a97-4acb-a439-64b745efe782",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_066.txt",
        "created": 1737369022,
        "question": "What should a student do if they have enrolled successfully but the system shows registration expired?",
        "answer": "The student might need help to be manually added into the course.",
        "request_id": "335818b05525a0ed0a7a6fb5692c863a"
    },
    {
        "id": "bbd2f2c6-f089-4f90-89fd-01a2228dd2ba",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_067.txt",
        "created": 1737369027,
        "question": "How can I apply for recognition of credits for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "To apply for recognition of credits, you need to fill the form provided on the TUM website and collect the documents listed on the TUM website. Then, send them to the provided email address. If you have modules you need to recognize as soon as possible, please send your documents by October 25th.",
        "request_id": "e9d771b8d7347d16e3cbbe868015a0b0"
    },
    {
        "id": "daf1caad-331c-4a85-b53e-1053a5130fb6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_068.txt",
        "created": 1737369039,
        "question": "Who should be contacted for questions regarding the project week, including the number of ECTS?",
        "answer": "For all questions around this project week, please contact Ms. [REDACTED] directly.",
        "request_id": "fefd8e84d86f770c5c2cc9c8e6168298"
    },
    {
        "id": "1182d759-ef71-4193-8a42-2a32777cab66",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_068.txt",
        "created": 1737369039,
        "question": "What is the goal of the new project week introduced for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The goal is to create a chatbot that provides accurate answers to frequently asked questions from students and prospective applicants using curated information.",
        "request_id": "fefd8e84d86f770c5c2cc9c8e6168298"
    },
    {
        "id": "3146a167-d740-49dc-8ce4-032e344edda8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_068.txt",
        "created": 1737369039,
        "question": "What will students do during the AI-based chatbot development project?",
        "answer": "During this project, students will work with cutting-edge technologies in AI and NLP to design a user-friendly solution, learn and apply key AI concepts in a hands-on, practical setting, and help position the AI in Society program at the forefront of responsible AI-powered study counseling.",
        "request_id": "fefd8e84d86f770c5c2cc9c8e6168298"
    },
    {
        "id": "8b4d2233-fa4a-4011-8a2a-486c9e95f6aa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_068.txt",
        "created": 1737369039,
        "question": "How can students register for the AI-based chatbot development course?",
        "answer": "Students can register for the course at https://campus.tum.de/tumonline/ee/ui/ca2/app/desktop/#/slc.tm.cp/student/courses/[NUMBER_REDACTED_AUTOMATICALLY]",
        "request_id": "fefd8e84d86f770c5c2cc9c8e6168298"
    },
    {
        "id": "4e4f4dbc-8973-4568-b480-baf32e9351a3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_070.txt",
        "created": 1737369052,
        "question": "Can I have my bachelor's courses credited?",
        "answer": "If you have previously completed a module which is very similar to the contents of one of the AI in Society modules, you might want to apply for recognition of this course.",
        "request_id": "f61783309af7006f7b398efcf4939623"
    },
    {
        "id": "f11520ea-509e-41c4-bc85-414041d1dd53",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_070.txt",
        "created": 1737369052,
        "question": "How do I apply for recognition of credits?",
        "answer": "You need to fill the form provided on the AI in Society website and collect the documents listed on the TUM website. Send them to the provided email address. If you have modules you need to recognize as soon as possible, please send your documents by October 25th.",
        "request_id": "f61783309af7006f7b398efcf4939623"
    },
    {
        "id": "0404b93e-497c-4ff9-b1fb-9024240f0b98",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_071.txt",
        "created": 1737369067,
        "question": "Can a student still defer their study admission after accepting the study place and matriculating?",
        "answer": "Yes, a student can defer their study admission even after accepting the study place and matriculating. They would need to write to the matriculation office and tell them they would like to reject the study place again (\u201cR\u00fccktritt vom Studienplatz\u201d).",
        "request_id": "9ec5872f2be10fc2f2500025d4f6a46f"
    },
    {
        "id": "47fbb099-147d-4ee1-829f-90468e3812f0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_071.txt",
        "created": 1737369067,
        "question": "What is the deadline to reject the study place for deferring admission?",
        "answer": "The deadline to reject the study place for deferring admission is November 15th.",
        "request_id": "9ec5872f2be10fc2f2500025d4f6a46f"
    },
    {
        "id": "40ba01b4-ddea-4b26-b2ce-6e1f62601780",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_071.txt",
        "created": 1737369067,
        "question": "Is it necessary to provide reasons for rejecting the study place for deferring admission?",
        "answer": "No, it is not necessary to provide reasons for rejecting the study place for deferring admission.",
        "request_id": "9ec5872f2be10fc2f2500025d4f6a46f"
    },
    {
        "id": "30820613-b13a-4b6f-9ae0-1239e420e9f4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_071.txt",
        "created": 1737369067,
        "question": "Will the admission still be valid if a student decides to reject the study place for deferring admission?",
        "answer": "Yes, the admission will still be valid for an indefinite time, so if the student decides to take the study place up again in one or two years, the university will still admit them.",
        "request_id": "9ec5872f2be10fc2f2500025d4f6a46f"
    },
    {
        "id": "52428733-1a99-4b77-ac60-5d76db260bc3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_073.txt",
        "created": 1737369075,
        "question": "What is the new project week about?",
        "answer": "The new project week is about developing an AI-based chatbot for study counseling, with the AI in Society program serving as the first use case. The goal is to create a chatbot that provides accurate answers to frequently asked questions from students and prospective applicants using curated information.",
        "request_id": "34cc064d00f2a0ad568c80302f9cf528"
    },
    {
        "id": "848f50ba-4119-4d5d-9b8c-de70cd45ec0a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_073.txt",
        "created": 1737369075,
        "question": "What will I do during this project week?",
        "answer": "During this project, you will work with cutting-edge technologies in AI and NLP to design a user-friendly solution, learn and apply key AI concepts in a hands-on, practical setting, and help position the AI in Society program at the forefront of responsible AI-powered study counseling.",
        "request_id": "34cc064d00f2a0ad568c80302f9cf528"
    },
    {
        "id": "5b1d42fd-9cb5-4715-bc57-768fcbb86bb7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_073.txt",
        "created": 1737369075,
        "question": "Who is the project week suitable for?",
        "answer": "The project week is suitable for students who are passionate about programming and enthusiastic about exploring natural language processing and chatbot development.",
        "request_id": "34cc064d00f2a0ad568c80302f9cf528"
    },
    {
        "id": "57be3517-fb08-4381-9d5e-0dbe4deb55fc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_073.txt",
        "created": 1737369075,
        "question": "How can I register for the course?",
        "answer": "You can register for the course at https://campus.tum.de/tumonline/ee/ui/ca2/app/desktop/#/slc.tm.cp/student/courses/[NUMBER_REDACTED_AUTOMATICALLY]?$scrollTo=toc_overview.",
        "request_id": "34cc064d00f2a0ad568c80302f9cf528"
    },
    {
        "id": "6cbe26b7-4753-4f55-b3a3-ed49f56e2b96",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_073.txt",
        "created": 1737369075,
        "question": "Who can I contact if I have any questions about the project week?",
        "answer": "For any questions, please reach out to [REDACTED], who is responsible for this project week.",
        "request_id": "34cc064d00f2a0ad568c80302f9cf528"
    },
    {
        "id": "72abb169-a94e-489a-b839-8e6fd003f61c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_075.txt",
        "created": 1737369088,
        "question": "How many SWS am I currently in the negative?",
        "answer": "You should not be in the negative at all, as 0 SWS are currently entered in SAP.",
        "request_id": "43e97efdcf3186dfa4ac4fcd004aadcc"
    },
    {
        "id": "cd2c0f56-9b8e-4f77-af17-ef45a0cda2e1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_075.txt",
        "created": 1737369088,
        "question": "Does the 0 SWS apply generally and concern the period from 1.7.23 to 31.1.25?",
        "answer": "Yes, the 0 SWS applies generally and concerns the period from 1.7.23 to 31.1.25.",
        "request_id": "43e97efdcf3186dfa4ac4fcd004aadcc"
    },
    {
        "id": "93524fdc-6a0a-446f-807c-67e64a3f94ba",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_075.txt",
        "created": 1737369088,
        "question": "Are 0 SWS currently entered for me in general, summed up for all previous semesters? Or does this only concern the course coordination office (50% of my contract)?",
        "answer": "0 SWS are currently entered in SAP, which should apply generally. There was a reduction from the dean due to study coordination tasks.",
        "request_id": "43e97efdcf3186dfa4ac4fcd004aadcc"
    },
    {
        "id": "129a38f5-06bd-491c-9ecd-402228740097",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_075.txt",
        "created": 1737369088,
        "question": "How should the teaching obligation for the semester in which I started at TUM be calculated?",
        "answer": "The teaching obligation for this semester should be calculated proportionally to the lecture days that were still left in this summer semester. Regularly you have a 2.5 SWS teaching obligation per semester, but for the summer semester 2023 it should be less.",
        "request_id": "43e97efdcf3186dfa4ac4fcd004aadcc"
    },
    {
        "id": "4a3d8e63-8407-47d0-b1a2-929f890fc259",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_076.txt",
        "created": 1737369099,
        "question": "Can I take a course from my other Masters\u2019 degree and let it count for a module in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can take a course from your other Masters\u2019 degree and let it count for a module in AI in Society. The module needs to be checked by the professor of the respective module in AI in Society according to its contents.",
        "request_id": "26001672ddd7dcb8cd20db8a80ae77e1"
    },
    {
        "id": "0aa7f6d4-6be3-42e9-9844-9d5ee68c8e02",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_076.txt",
        "created": 1737369099,
        "question": "What should I do if the modules I want to transfer are mandatory in my other study program?",
        "answer": "You should take the mandatory modules, write the exam, and afterwards reach out for course recognition.",
        "request_id": "26001672ddd7dcb8cd20db8a80ae77e1"
    },
    {
        "id": "0c0f5259-b26e-486e-8479-492d906e59c5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_076.txt",
        "created": 1737369099,
        "question": "Can I know beforehand whether a course will be recognized by the AI in Society program or not?",
        "answer": "You can write to the professor of the module in AI in Society and ask, but they won\u2019t give you a 100% sure answer, because these cases need to be checked properly and formally.",
        "request_id": "26001672ddd7dcb8cd20db8a80ae77e1"
    },
    {
        "id": "212e1a9a-883b-4d2f-9eb8-ee4a4f282c1d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_077.txt",
        "created": 1737369106,
        "question": "What is the goal of the new project week introduced for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The goal of the new project week is to develop an AI-based chatbot for study counseling, with the AI in Society program serving as the first use case. The chatbot should provide accurate answers to frequently asked questions from students and prospective applicants using curated information.",
        "request_id": "b8103972aff85830326273f03cbc406f"
    },
    {
        "id": "4e7730cb-de17-4b46-af64-d2e5faad0b6f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_077.txt",
        "created": 1737369106,
        "question": "What will students do during this project week?",
        "answer": "During this project week, students will work with cutting-edge technologies in AI and NLP to design a user-friendly solution, learn and apply key AI concepts in a hands-on, practical setting, and help position the AI in Society program at the forefront of responsible AI-powered study counseling.",
        "request_id": "b8103972aff85830326273f03cbc406f"
    },
    {
        "id": "68d13401-b67b-4fac-8f9a-2ef8153d05ee",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_077.txt",
        "created": 1737369106,
        "question": "Who is the project week suitable for?",
        "answer": "The project week is suitable for students who are passionate about programming and enthusiastic about exploring natural language processing and chatbot development.",
        "request_id": "b8103972aff85830326273f03cbc406f"
    },
    {
        "id": "08193eb1-1b22-44f9-9c59-2aff9a4bc697",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_077.txt",
        "created": 1737369106,
        "question": "How can students register for the course?",
        "answer": "Students can register for the course at the provided URL on the TUM Online Campus.",
        "request_id": "b8103972aff85830326273f03cbc406f"
    },
    {
        "id": "0ffeaf9a-d0fc-4877-bac1-4ebc28c12b77",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_077.txt",
        "created": 1737369106,
        "question": "Who should be contacted for any questions about the project week?",
        "answer": "For any questions, students should reach out to the person responsible for the project week.",
        "request_id": "b8103972aff85830326273f03cbc406f"
    },
    {
        "id": "473a3270-e0a4-4072-84ee-844c04af567d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_078.txt",
        "created": 1737369117,
        "question": "Can you please help me to check my case? I'm still not enrolled given all the required information has been received at your end.",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, it is not possible to give an exact statement about the processing time. All documents are scrupulously checked by the admissions office staff. Due to the current situation and large amount of applications, there are delays in the processing times. If you have uploaded documents or sent them via postal delivery, there may currently be a delay of several weeks until they have been processed. If you have submitted the documents within the deadline, please wait until you are notified.",
        "request_id": "e31d56288da29cf941ff86973f8bb4e3"
    },
    {
        "id": "3df83006-6617-4962-9b05-abfff8e4f673",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_078.txt",
        "created": 1737369117,
        "question": "I'm writing to ask for a verification of the deadline of student semester fees and tuition for international students. Inside my enrollment instruction there's a description mentioning 15th of Sep is the deadline but the actual invoice of both Semester fee and tuition mentioned 15th of Nov. Can you help me to check on this one?",
        "answer": "The payment deadline for the tuition fees for first-time enrollment for the summer semester is March 15, for the winter semester September 15. You have time until the 15.11.2024 to pay the semester fees.",
        "request_id": "e31d56288da29cf941ff86973f8bb4e3"
    },
    {
        "id": "a0223da6-08d8-4352-b325-a9483e7a73ed",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_079.txt",
        "created": 1737369131,
        "question": "What is the proposed solution to facilitate the student's enrollment?",
        "answer": "The student proposed obtaining proof from the original AIS admission committee stating that their study place/admission was not contingent on their MBA degree. This document might facilitate the student's enrollment without further issues, as the TUM Center for Study and Learning is primarily concerned with verifying the documents on which the student's admission was based.",
        "request_id": "dd54c56d37360599bbd3aa4ba68b838d"
    },
    {
        "id": "2934ad43-28b9-4693-8f01-81b3c816b46a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_079.txt",
        "created": 1737369131,
        "question": "What can the student do while they are not matriculated?",
        "answer": "The student can still attend their courses as normal. They should connect with their classmates, so they can help them obtain the lecture materials while they do not have access to them online (due to not being enrolled officially). The course registrations are open until mid-November.",
        "request_id": "dd54c56d37360599bbd3aa4ba68b838d"
    },
    {
        "id": "cbdfccde-7083-4bdd-a52f-1d61f5bc425a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_079.txt",
        "created": 1737369131,
        "question": "What is the deadline for the payment of tuition fees for first-time enrollment for the winter semester?",
        "answer": "The payment deadline for the tuition fees for first-time enrollment for the winter semester is September 15.",
        "request_id": "dd54c56d37360599bbd3aa4ba68b838d"
    },
    {
        "id": "af1800d9-f0ac-4ae4-8cb7-94ab14f6584a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_079.txt",
        "created": 1737369131,
        "question": "What are the steps to complete enrollment at TUM?",
        "answer": "To complete enrollment, the student must officially accept the offer of admission in TUMonline, transfer the semester fee by the deadline, and submit any missing documents, including the signed enrollment application, to the Admissions and Enrollment Office within the designated timeframe. Some documents can be directly uploaded in TUMonline, while others must be sent in hardcopy by mail.",
        "request_id": "dd54c56d37360599bbd3aa4ba68b838d"
    },
    {
        "id": "e363ec4a-2118-4a8b-a9e7-cede44eeddaa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_080.txt",
        "created": 1737369143,
        "question": "Can you please help me to check my case? I'm still not enrolled given all the required information has been received at your end.",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, it is not possible to give an exact statement about the processing time. All documents are scrupulously checked by the admissions office staff. Due to the current situation and large amount of applications, there are delays in the processing times. If you have uploaded documents or sent them via postal delivery, there may currently be a delay of several weeks until they have been processed. If you have submitted the documents within the deadline, please wait until you are notified.",
        "request_id": "a0a512a26952db6a0ef855e1dc377749"
    },
    {
        "id": "e549e31a-4a75-4a50-b535-bed78d847eee",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_080.txt",
        "created": 1737369143,
        "question": "What is the deadline of student semester fees and tuition for international students?",
        "answer": "The payment deadline for the tuition fees for first-time enrollment for the summer semester is March 15, for the winter semester September 15. You have time until the 15.11.2024 to pay the semester fees.",
        "request_id": "a0a512a26952db6a0ef855e1dc377749"
    },
    {
        "id": "d2b4c179-e961-44bd-af08-b0adb2ae507e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_080.txt",
        "created": 1737369143,
        "question": "What are the steps to enroll at TUM?",
        "answer": "To enroll at TUM, please send in a signed application for enrollment form, together with the other required hardcopy documents listed in your TUMonline account. Please enroll as soon as possible, preferably until the first day of the semester. You will receive your student status and will be able to register for classes and exams only after enrollment. Before you are enrolled, it is not possible to participate in any classes or coursework, and you will not receive your TUM student card. All steps towards enrollment (postal delivery and processing) take time. Please act in a timely manner, so that you can be enrolled at the beginning of the semester.",
        "request_id": "a0a512a26952db6a0ef855e1dc377749"
    },
    {
        "id": "40cdd79f-94c8-4844-9128-b97b7c4dc041",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_081.txt",
        "created": 1737369158,
        "question": "Can I attend classes in person from the first week of December while participating in online sessions via Moddle until then?",
        "answer": "It is not a problem if you arrive in person to Munich in December and participate online until then. In fact, several people have a similar situation as you, so this is ok.",
        "request_id": "e20bfb878b7d04342b06c4c831953ab8"
    },
    {
        "id": "615731d3-ad51-4808-92c3-f1f2f2bb993e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_081.txt",
        "created": 1737369158,
        "question": "Do I need to know German for my program?",
        "answer": "We can issue a letter stating that German knowledge is not required for our program.",
        "request_id": "e20bfb878b7d04342b06c4c831953ab8"
    },
    {
        "id": "f60d5ce7-23ba-4c57-bb1c-88c9e24ab2a3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_082.txt",
        "created": 1737369167,
        "question": "Can I attend/join late for classes physically and till then participate in online classes?",
        "answer": "It is not a problem if you arrive in person to Munich in December and participate online until then. In fact, several people have a similar situation as you, so this is ok.",
        "request_id": "b62df7d72f695c794092f7ae1ac0832f"
    },
    {
        "id": "7f8aa027-14d8-45af-a2dd-f5850bf5a2fb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_082.txt",
        "created": 1737369167,
        "question": "Can you issue a letter stating that German knowledge is not required for our program?",
        "answer": "We can issue a letter stating that German knowledge is not required for our program.",
        "request_id": "b62df7d72f695c794092f7ae1ac0832f"
    },
    {
        "id": "4101d467-67cf-45b1-81cd-7d67eeff3168",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_082.txt",
        "created": 1737369167,
        "question": "Given the estimated 30-day processing period for the visa, would it be acceptable for me to begin attending classes in person from the first week of December while participating in online sessions via Moddle until then?",
        "answer": "It is not a problem if you arrive in person to Munich in December and participate online until then. In fact, several people have a similar situation as you, so this is ok.",
        "request_id": "b62df7d72f695c794092f7ae1ac0832f"
    },
    {
        "id": "432c6176-3e94-453c-974d-f29fced13904",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_083.txt",
        "created": 1737369175,
        "question": "Are there currently 0 SWS registered for me, summed up for all previous semesters? Or does this only apply to the course coordination office (50% of my contract)?",
        "answer": "You should not be in the negative at all, as 0 SWS are currently entered in SAP (as far as I know there was a reduction from the dean due to the study coordination tasks).",
        "request_id": "229cb52023652fc5aaefd1b47d7421a0"
    },
    {
        "id": "bb6f9349-681f-44e5-b33f-20c49087611e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_083.txt",
        "created": 1737369175,
        "question": "Could you please help me understand my teaching assignment? I would need to know how many SWS I am currently in the negative.",
        "answer": "You should not be in the negative at all, as 0 SWS are currently entered in SAP.",
        "request_id": "229cb52023652fc5aaefd1b47d7421a0"
    },
    {
        "id": "78b41d03-fd0e-45c0-b2a5-424e6eb143cd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_083.txt",
        "created": 1737369175,
        "question": "Specifically, I am also concerned about the semester in which I started at TUM: The contract start was 1.7.2023. That means the teaching assignment for this semester should be calculated proportionally to the lecture days that were still left in this summer semester. I usually have a 2.5 SWS teaching obligation per semester, but for the summer semester 2023 it should be less.",
        "answer": "As far as I know there was a reduction from the dean due to the study coordination tasks. The central department confirmed 0 until 01.2.2025, then it is 2.5 SWS.",
        "request_id": "229cb52023652fc5aaefd1b47d7421a0"
    },
    {
        "id": "6a36bb96-9ee6-4948-9b46-33f174c1bc9e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_086.txt",
        "created": 1737369190,
        "question": "What should a student do if they have completed their Bachelor's degree but have not yet received any email or document confirming the completion of their degree?",
        "answer": "The student should reach out to the relevant department at their university, in this case the TUM School of Management, and request assistance in obtaining the official graduation certificate or guidance on how to find it through the university's online system.",
        "request_id": "40bc1a8015c1a27a351f6c2e9459dc0e"
    },
    {
        "id": "28192f1b-76bc-4cd6-b23f-8355b0b99ebe",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_086.txt",
        "created": 1737369190,
        "question": "What happens after a student confirms the completion of their studies at the TUM School of Management?",
        "answer": "After the student provides positive feedback, the TUM School of Management will forward their documents to the central examination office for the preparation of certificates. The student's study status in TUMonline/their transcript of records will only be listed as completed when their final documents have been created and their studies have been closed in the system.",
        "request_id": "40bc1a8015c1a27a351f6c2e9459dc0e"
    },
    {
        "id": "768b91f3-408a-49f2-a12e-7e314cb1f0cc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_086.txt",
        "created": 1737369190,
        "question": "What should be done if a student is waiting for their Bachelor's degree confirmation and cannot be enrolled in a Master's program because of this?",
        "answer": "The student's confirmation email about their degree completion can be forwarded to the Office for Application and Matriculation, who can then directly recognize the degree completion.",
        "request_id": "40bc1a8015c1a27a351f6c2e9459dc0e"
    },
    {
        "id": "6a01fde4-4722-47e9-b4ee-6ebf5eda1879",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_086.txt",
        "created": 1737369190,
        "question": "What information is needed when sending emails about specific students to the Office for Application and Matriculation?",
        "answer": "When sending such emails, it is requested to include the student's matriculation number to facilitate the search process.",
        "request_id": "40bc1a8015c1a27a351f6c2e9459dc0e"
    },
    {
        "id": "37f183ea-f703-48bb-957c-caa19c54f621",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_087.txt",
        "created": 1737369203,
        "question": "What should a student do if they have completed their Bachelor's degree but have not received any confirmation?",
        "answer": "The student should contact the relevant department at their university. In this case, the student reached out to the TUM School of Management for confirmation of their graduation.",
        "request_id": "4fb2bb17f6e0242fee1e0d1954c5d891"
    },
    {
        "id": "3e01c4e7-574e-4f43-832f-d4491bc1af7c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_087.txt",
        "created": 1737369203,
        "question": "What happens after a student confirms the details of their transcript of records?",
        "answer": "After the student provides positive feedback in response to the email, their documents will be forwarded to the central examination office for the preparation of certificates.",
        "request_id": "4fb2bb17f6e0242fee1e0d1954c5d891"
    },
    {
        "id": "8d726980-7abd-46b7-bd2b-729e4f261a16",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_087.txt",
        "created": 1737369203,
        "question": "What happens if a student does not reply to the email about their transcript of records within two weeks?",
        "answer": "If the student does not reply within two weeks, their current transcript data will be forwarded for final preparation and completion.",
        "request_id": "4fb2bb17f6e0242fee1e0d1954c5d891"
    },
    {
        "id": "12446f2c-307b-4442-b225-22b3169479f6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_087.txt",
        "created": 1737369203,
        "question": "When will a student's study status be listed as completed in TUMonline?",
        "answer": "A student's study status in TUMonline will only be listed as completed when their final documents have been created and their studies have been closed in the system.",
        "request_id": "4fb2bb17f6e0242fee1e0d1954c5d891"
    },
    {
        "id": "9a07db83-552f-4fe3-b822-9bf706ac212d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_087.txt",
        "created": 1737369203,
        "question": "Where can a student find information about their degree and the corresponding documents?",
        "answer": "Information about a student's degree and the corresponding documents can be found on the website of the TU Munich.",
        "request_id": "4fb2bb17f6e0242fee1e0d1954c5d891"
    },
    {
        "id": "b50a6f11-088a-484c-a6ae-d13086a889a3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_088.txt",
        "created": 1737369215,
        "question": "Is there any way I could still register for the other courses as '[REDACTED]' and gain access to the Moodle content while my enrollment is pending?",
        "answer": "You should have received an email from TUM/your study coordinator, congratulating you about finishing your Bachelor\u2019s degree. Please forward me this email. I will them forward it to the matriculation office. For them, this will be counted as proof of you having completed your studies, so you do not have to wait for your official certificates. After this, you should be matriculated pretty quickly, allowing you to register for our courses as an AI in Society student.",
        "request_id": "8c742add613f31bdd62f25400d3876fc"
    },
    {
        "id": "9388ac8b-fa56-4c0b-8bab-57267b359a9c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_092.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "Is there a mandatory attendance requirement for the course 'Foundations of AI & [REDACTED]'?",
        "answer": "There is no mandatory attendance requirement for the course 'Foundations of AI & [REDACTED]'.",
        "request_id": "a9ac3475ecaa2e5ac8f9d8b019c4a2e3"
    },
    {
        "id": "64f4d7e7-7ec1-4b9d-8d88-5b2e4eb2c8c3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_092.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "Is there a mandatory attendance requirement for other courses?",
        "answer": "The information is not explicitly provided for other courses. It is recommended to inquire directly with the respective lecturers.",
        "request_id": "a9ac3475ecaa2e5ac8f9d8b019c4a2e3"
    },
    {
        "id": "c567318c-341e-47e9-82a1-1776172df459",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_092.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "When and where can I register for courses?",
        "answer": "You can register for courses on the TUMonline platform from October 1st.",
        "request_id": "a9ac3475ecaa2e5ac8f9d8b019c4a2e3"
    },
    {
        "id": "7912473c-4a39-4c2c-9606-a5bafdecc11a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_092.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "Is it possible to attend courses from a higher semester in earlier semesters?",
        "answer": "Yes, it is possible to attend courses from a higher semester in earlier semesters.",
        "request_id": "a9ac3475ecaa2e5ac8f9d8b019c4a2e3"
    },
    {
        "id": "64c9a69f-713a-4ae8-b6b0-770e9a5fd625",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_092.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "Where can I find more detailed information and conditions for a semester abroad?",
        "answer": "For more detailed information and conditions for a semester abroad, refer to the following link: https://www.international.tum.de/global/auslandsaufenthalte/. If you have specific questions, feel free to contact the staff of Global & [REDACTED].",
        "request_id": "a9ac3475ecaa2e5ac8f9d8b019c4a2e3"
    },
    {
        "id": "66429c85-4284-48eb-b38a-88ffa89385e5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_092.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "When will the lecture schedules be available?",
        "answer": "The lecture schedules are not yet finalized and will be published on the website in due course before the start of the semester.",
        "request_id": "a9ac3475ecaa2e5ac8f9d8b019c4a2e3"
    },
    {
        "id": "d4a5b949-a7bf-4fdb-98c1-6dcf7065dd79",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_093.txt",
        "created": 1737369236,
        "question": "At TUM Online, do we have classes on the 16.10 for Foundations of AI and [REDACTED]?",
        "answer": "No, the first tutorial for Foundations of AI & [REDACTED] won't take place on 16.10 since there will be nothing to discuss yet. The first lecture is on 18.10 and the first regular tutorial will be on 23.10.",
        "request_id": "c3861f7bcb414d81c82833a042ac1417"
    },
    {
        "id": "bdcfc218-c2f2-41a9-bd3b-05f4550ba9d1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_094.txt",
        "created": 1737369242,
        "question": "Can I begin attending classes in person from the first week of December while participating in online sessions via Moddle until then?",
        "answer": "It is not a problem if you arrive in person to Munich in December and participate online until then. In fact, several people have a similar situation as you, so this is ok.",
        "request_id": "c33f6d6f7846874b62b4eeba5f99f4d3"
    },
    {
        "id": "9cfcc354-ff07-4d79-ada2-1a20dc35bb72",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_094.txt",
        "created": 1737369242,
        "question": "Do I need a letter confirming the exemption from the German language requirement for my program for my visa application?",
        "answer": "We can issue a letter stating that German knowledge is not required for our program.",
        "request_id": "c33f6d6f7846874b62b4eeba5f99f4d3"
    },
    {
        "id": "033bfee3-b0e1-48f1-9b58-3ce19e9df735",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_095.txt",
        "created": 1737369250,
        "question": "Can you send me more information about the Master's Program AI in Society from TUM?",
        "answer": "You can find all relevant information about the program\u2019s contents on our website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/. If you click on \u201cStudies\u201d on the left-hand side, you will see more information on the curriculum and courses.",
        "request_id": "c867b1e17fa58e0807e96a87cbf05b53"
    },
    {
        "id": "2c2089a4-cc45-40f7-9123-481fd4126595",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_095.txt",
        "created": 1737369250,
        "question": "What kind of courses can I expect in the Master's Program AI in Society's curriculum?",
        "answer": "You can find information on the curriculum and courses for the Master's Program AI in Society on our website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/. Click on \u201cStudies\u201d on the left-hand side for more details.",
        "request_id": "c867b1e17fa58e0807e96a87cbf05b53"
    },
    {
        "id": "4692abdb-fa3c-4e12-9d11-8e3046d728ff",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_096.txt",
        "created": 1737369259,
        "question": "When will the 2 missing lectures be available online?",
        "answer": "The 2 missing lectures will be available online any day before October 14th.",
        "request_id": "f174ab4122dceee25e090ddc76d09ecd"
    },
    {
        "id": "fd725d11-56d1-4227-adc1-81dfc0636877",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_096.txt",
        "created": 1737369259,
        "question": "When will the schedule of courses be available?",
        "answer": "The first semester schedule is available on the website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/studies/",
        "request_id": "f174ab4122dceee25e090ddc76d09ecd"
    },
    {
        "id": "8cd2c602-8bbb-4496-ae6a-2dfa5a7bd329",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_096.txt",
        "created": 1737369259,
        "question": "How can I get information about the companies or institutions that the program has partnerships with?",
        "answer": "You should reach out to the program head for information about partnerships.",
        "request_id": "f174ab4122dceee25e090ddc76d09ecd"
    },
    {
        "id": "a7079c78-4a0a-4c8f-a443-06542ba51037",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_098.txt",
        "created": 1737369266,
        "question": "Is there an AIS Whatsapp group for incoming students?",
        "answer": "Yes, there is an AIS Whatsapp group for incoming students.",
        "request_id": "87931ccacf98d885cc9d2e66fed4ec17"
    },
    {
        "id": "30d14fb2-fc4c-4c4a-8d5a-a8be43f00a4d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_098.txt",
        "created": 1737369266,
        "question": "Will there be another AIS Whatsapp group opened and advertised at the welcome event on Friday?",
        "answer": "Yes, another AIS Whatsapp group is planned to be opened and advertised at the welcome event on Friday.",
        "request_id": "87931ccacf98d885cc9d2e66fed4ec17"
    },
    {
        "id": "f6b24417-1145-473a-842c-3f9e57536741",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_098.txt",
        "created": 1737369266,
        "question": "Can the invitation link for the new AIS Whatsapp group be shared?",
        "answer": "Yes, the invitation link for the new AIS Whatsapp group can be shared via slides at the welcome event and via email with all students.",
        "request_id": "87931ccacf98d885cc9d2e66fed4ec17"
    },
    {
        "id": "4e7c8c87-dff7-42a4-a403-8f4425761f02",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_102.txt",
        "created": 1737368941,
        "question": "Is it possible for me to participate in the event (and potentially AIS courses) without official enrollment at this stage?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can still participate in the event despite your matriculation being pending.",
        "request_id": "97a2e640190fdcb7fc72e73ed1b6603d"
    },
    {
        "id": "33b092de-dc6e-46a4-a94d-83ecffe7f62b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_104.txt",
        "created": 1737368946,
        "question": "When and where can I register for courses?",
        "answer": "You can register for courses on the TUMonline platform starting from October 1st, as soon as you are enrolled.",
        "request_id": "61317737d25951d617a09a6749b4214f"
    },
    {
        "id": "db877297-03ec-4b47-9059-705cb0a11ba4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_104.txt",
        "created": 1737368946,
        "question": "Is it possible to attend courses from a higher semester in earlier semesters?",
        "answer": "Yes, it is possible.",
        "request_id": "61317737d25951d617a09a6749b4214f"
    },
    {
        "id": "fade2597-b2ce-44ae-b12d-f7857f8e748d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_104.txt",
        "created": 1737368946,
        "question": "Where can I find more detailed information and conditions for a semester abroad?",
        "answer": "You can refer to this website for more information about studying abroad: https://www.international.tum.de/global/auslandsaufenthalte/. If you have specific questions, feel free to contact the staff of Global & [REDACTED].",
        "request_id": "61317737d25951d617a09a6749b4214f"
    },
    {
        "id": "abfa9aa3-4fd3-413c-8231-68a176e7d90e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_104.txt",
        "created": 1737368946,
        "question": "When will the exact schedules for the courses be available?",
        "answer": "The schedules are still being planned and will be published on the website before the start of the semester.",
        "request_id": "61317737d25951d617a09a6749b4214f"
    },
    {
        "id": "b5ac24c9-3498-41ec-aae1-f2f9656b09da",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_105.txt",
        "created": 1737368956,
        "question": "Do I need to have a Bachelor\u2019s in a STEM subject in order to apply for the Master of Science in AI in Society at the Technical University of Munich (TUM)?",
        "answer": "No, you do not need to have a Bachelor\u2019s in a STEM subject in order to apply \u2013 all backgrounds are welcome.",
        "request_id": "bab58db46b6c66599e49a3c42bc1a76f"
    },
    {
        "id": "10238c10-2be8-4eb8-bdec-9c6d18fcf81e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_105.txt",
        "created": 1737368956,
        "question": "What are the application requirements for the Master of Science in AI in Society at the Technical University of Munich (TUM)?",
        "answer": "The application requirements can be found on the program's website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/",
        "request_id": "bab58db46b6c66599e49a3c42bc1a76f"
    },
    {
        "id": "98792a19-5864-4bb3-85cb-8a171fcbf972",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_106.txt",
        "created": 1737368963,
        "question": "Do I meet the requirement of having 5 ECTS in mathematics/statistics passed if I successfully completed a 7.5 ECTS module on \u201cResearch and Methods\u201d?",
        "answer": "Your course \u201cResearch and Methods\u201d would pass as sufficient, if you also provide us a description of what has been taught in the course, so we can see that there were indeed statistical methods taught.",
        "request_id": "9b12719001f0b0d7b3ab946d78046e20"
    },
    {
        "id": "ba09202d-8b65-4b02-ae58-c69a59e292db",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_106.txt",
        "created": 1737368963,
        "question": "Does it matter during which period of the application opening (between February and May 31st) I apply for the program?",
        "answer": "It technically does not matter when in this period you send your application. However, due to the big amount applications, this year we had to split up the aptitude test into multiple dates. Please don\u2019t take \u201cfirst come, first serve\u201d as a solid rule here, but I would recommend submitting your application rather sooner than later.",
        "request_id": "9b12719001f0b0d7b3ab946d78046e20"
    },
    {
        "id": "00742de0-b863-41eb-a322-5af60feb55f1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_107.txt",
        "created": 1737368972,
        "question": "What does the 'edit preference' section in the course registration for 'Introduction to programming' indicate?",
        "answer": "The preference section indicates your preference regarding groups, for example if there were 3 different groups, you could indicate which group you would most like to visit (preference 1), or least (preference 3).",
        "request_id": "b39aa34a508e9361a748f66e1053f039"
    },
    {
        "id": "e2e60594-78b9-4299-9306-a0b147be8630",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_107.txt",
        "created": 1737368972,
        "question": "Should I choose my preference according to my previous programming knowledge?",
        "answer": "No, it has nothing to do with your previous programming knowledge.",
        "request_id": "b39aa34a508e9361a748f66e1053f039"
    },
    {
        "id": "3b0177a6-8de8-4e55-83d0-bfd185ea5e60",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_108.txt",
        "created": 1737368976,
        "question": "Are we gonna have both options of doing it before the semester or during the semester? Or will we have the option of just during the semester?",
        "answer": "We shifted the plan to doing the course during the semester only.",
        "request_id": "9ed36d7acbe9b8fff6d1565bf2427046"
    },
    {
        "id": "d8357c18-08f2-416e-8142-999649d77f11",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_108.txt",
        "created": 1737368976,
        "question": "What to do if you are not able to attend the course 'Introduction to Programming & [REDACTED]' because it was scheduled before the official beginning of the semester?",
        "answer": "The course has been shifted to take place during the semester, on Tuesdays from 09:00 - 16:00, from October 15 to November 12. You will be able to attend this course in person, as well as online.",
        "request_id": "9ed36d7acbe9b8fff6d1565bf2427046"
    },
    {
        "id": "1708460a-d490-4910-a635-a35b041eca83",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_111.txt",
        "created": 1737368985,
        "question": "Where can I find the academic calendar for the MSc AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "You can find the academic calendar on our website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/. The lecture periods you can find here, under \u201csemester structure -> Winter semester 2024/25\u201d: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/application/application-info-portal/dates-periods-and-deadlines",
        "request_id": "888cfec1dea3c2d6af63f4ebb6393d6a"
    },
    {
        "id": "ac7469ad-5f30-4d0f-886f-3dcb71251771",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_111.txt",
        "created": 1737368985,
        "question": "Can I request the syllabus for the MSc AI in Society program, including details on the learning plan, competency standards, core competencies, main topics/materials, learning activities, competency achievement indicators for assessment, time allocation, and learning resources?",
        "answer": "For this, I can send you the relevant part of our study program documentation. Please find the relevant information in the document.",
        "request_id": "888cfec1dea3c2d6af63f4ebb6393d6a"
    },
    {
        "id": "6859b3ee-01b2-49b5-93f8-7a35adc2606f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_111.txt",
        "created": 1737368985,
        "question": "I have not yet secured accommodation, which is required for my visa. I have contacted several student dormitories, but they are either full, have closed their applications, or haven't responded to my messages. Could you assist me with this?",
        "answer": "If you cannot find a place in a dormitory, you can look for shared flats for example on wg-gesucht.de",
        "request_id": "888cfec1dea3c2d6af63f4ebb6393d6a"
    },
    {
        "id": "bf4ecef2-a178-442f-b88e-899aba8f6f09",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_111.txt",
        "created": 1737368985,
        "question": "The name on all my documents is different from the name on my passport. The embassy has requested that I renew my passport to match the name on my birth certificate. Could I update my name in TUMOnline and my Letter of Admission to reflect my new name?",
        "answer": "For this matter, you need to contact TUM\u2019s student information service desk: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/support-and-advice/support-during-studies/student-information",
        "request_id": "888cfec1dea3c2d6af63f4ebb6393d6a"
    },
    {
        "id": "afa1851d-e064-4b4f-8601-3f8b25e96436",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_111.txt",
        "created": 1737368985,
        "question": "Is it possible to defer my admission? How to do that?",
        "answer": "If you want to defer your admission to next year, you can do so. In this case, you now need to decline the offer online. Then, next year you apply again with all documents, however, you will be automatically admitted by the matriculation office since you already had received an offer. So, you won\u2019t go through the selection process again next year.",
        "request_id": "888cfec1dea3c2d6af63f4ebb6393d6a"
    },
    {
        "id": "bae3b3de-78bd-4f81-b28b-ed7fe23ff34a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_112.txt",
        "created": 1737369000,
        "question": "Where can I find the academic calendar for the MSc AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "You can find the academic calendar on our website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/. The lecture periods you can find here, under \u201csemester structure -> Winter semester 2024/25\u201d: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/application/application-info-portal/dates-periods-and-deadlines",
        "request_id": "06c93f1311dee14e403c19f233e644d0"
    },
    {
        "id": "a6292881-79b8-4cfc-9754-64329179b8a8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_112.txt",
        "created": 1737369000,
        "question": "I would like to request the syllabus for the MSc AI in Society program, including details on the learning plan, competency standards, core competencies, main topics/materials, learning activities, competency achievement indicators for assessment, time allocation, and learning resources.",
        "answer": "For this, I can send you the relevant part of our study program documentation. Please find the relevant information in the document.",
        "request_id": "06c93f1311dee14e403c19f233e644d0"
    },
    {
        "id": "473ce2a1-24fc-49cc-8ee6-70599c41bb47",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_112.txt",
        "created": 1737369000,
        "question": "I have not yet secured accommodation, which is required for my visa. I have contacted several student dormitories, but they are either full, have closed their applications, or haven't responded to my messages. Could you assist me with this?",
        "answer": "If you cannot find a place in a dormitory, you can look for shared flats for example on wg-gesucht.de",
        "request_id": "06c93f1311dee14e403c19f233e644d0"
    },
    {
        "id": "70386e48-ba3f-4668-a2a9-b5380fe87eed",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_112.txt",
        "created": 1737369000,
        "question": "The name on all my documents is different from the name on my passport. The embassy has requested that I renew my passport to match the name on my birth certificate. Could I update my name in TUMOnline and my Letter of Admission to reflect the new name?",
        "answer": "For this matter, you need to contact TUM\u2019s student information service desk: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/support-and-advice/support-during-studies/student-information",
        "request_id": "06c93f1311dee14e403c19f233e644d0"
    },
    {
        "id": "e0aa0977-4968-416f-86f0-51d3217b7569",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_112.txt",
        "created": 1737369000,
        "question": "Is it possible to defer my admission? How to do that?",
        "answer": "If you want to defer your admission to next year, you can do so. In this case, you now need to decline the offer online. Then, next year you apply again with all documents, however, you will be automatically admitted by the matriculation office since you already had received an offer. So, you won\u2019t go through the selection process again next year.",
        "request_id": "06c93f1311dee14e403c19f233e644d0"
    },
    {
        "id": "38153a11-f299-4732-be06-a40fdefaabe0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_114.txt",
        "created": 1737369017,
        "question": "Has the acceptance letter been issued after clearing the interview round?",
        "answer": "Yes, the acceptance letter has been issued and an automatic email from TUM should have been received.",
        "request_id": "a34af1cb046f768feda79113ec7f9847"
    },
    {
        "id": "9c4b5de9-632f-486f-a9c8-7e0034d2c216",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_114.txt",
        "created": 1737369017,
        "question": "When is the next scheduled event after the interview round?",
        "answer": "The next scheduled event is on the 19th of September.",
        "request_id": "a34af1cb046f768feda79113ec7f9847"
    },
    {
        "id": "62d8ec83-ac1f-40ac-be35-e3f1998c9766",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_120.txt",
        "created": 1737369033,
        "question": "What should I do if I am unable to start studying from 1st October due to visa delays?",
        "answer": "The lectures are offered in a hybrid format, i.e. they are streamed online in parallel. You will be able to follow them from your home country. Therefore, if you arrive 1-2 months later, it will not be a problem.",
        "request_id": "5b5e71a82df5590cf0202e6b2d54c0f4"
    },
    {
        "id": "c0d35179-0a06-4bcf-9ec1-0082e7819f23",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_121.txt",
        "created": 1737369037,
        "question": "Is the interview on site or online?",
        "answer": "The interview will be held online.",
        "request_id": "701c86c96b7f3a4857d50ceed46464e7"
    },
    {
        "id": "af74ee23-7c17-4582-8933-5b7a16d7f038",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_121.txt",
        "created": 1737369037,
        "question": "Shall I bring written information such as CV or is that not necessary?",
        "answer": "There is no need to prepare any documents for the interview.",
        "request_id": "701c86c96b7f3a4857d50ceed46464e7"
    },
    {
        "id": "da046e73-e223-477b-b2a2-507225a5cfd2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_121.txt",
        "created": 1737369037,
        "question": "What is the purpose of the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program. They will also explore your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations. The focus is on understanding your motivation for the study program, not testing your knowledge on specific subjects.",
        "request_id": "701c86c96b7f3a4857d50ceed46464e7"
    },
    {
        "id": "1a9ed1d8-6c14-4849-a4e0-252c576e09d3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_121.txt",
        "created": 1737369037,
        "question": "When will the interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place on September 16th.",
        "request_id": "701c86c96b7f3a4857d50ceed46464e7"
    },
    {
        "id": "d762ee5b-d03d-4550-962c-f1ec5d1e7f22",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_121.txt",
        "created": 1737369037,
        "question": "What are the available timeslots for the interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The available timeslots are from 09:30 \u2013 11:00 and 13:00 \u2013 17:00 CEST (Germany time). The interview spans a time of 30 minutes.",
        "request_id": "701c86c96b7f3a4857d50ceed46464e7"
    },
    {
        "id": "2bb8d41b-f6ab-4943-abf7-0b1ab3728b8d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_122.txt",
        "created": 1737369050,
        "question": "What is the purpose of the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program. They will also explore your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations. The focus is on understanding your motivation for the study program, not testing your knowledge on specific subjects.",
        "request_id": "e4c5e3b54d9004f127dbc5cf0bada387"
    },
    {
        "id": "a119c16b-55e8-4083-874d-09847745fed6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_122.txt",
        "created": 1737369050,
        "question": "When will the aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place on September 16th.",
        "request_id": "e4c5e3b54d9004f127dbc5cf0bada387"
    },
    {
        "id": "b3fd6cd2-879b-494d-af50-b5f3d3f8fff6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_122.txt",
        "created": 1737369050,
        "question": "What are the available timeslots for the aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The available timeslots are from 09:30 \u2013 11:00 and 13:00 \u2013 17:00 CEST (Germany time). Each interview spans a time of 30 minutes.",
        "request_id": "e4c5e3b54d9004f127dbc5cf0bada387"
    },
    {
        "id": "d3fd2375-1bf9-4d56-865b-112de703285f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_122.txt",
        "created": 1737369050,
        "question": "What is the latest date to inform about the preferred timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The latest date to inform about the preferred timeslot is by September 12th, 23:59.",
        "request_id": "e4c5e3b54d9004f127dbc5cf0bada387"
    },
    {
        "id": "4edaccc2-5a17-4070-9489-ec76a6fb8d8f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_122.txt",
        "created": 1737369050,
        "question": "What is the earliest timeslot available for the aptitude interview on the day?",
        "answer": "The earliest timeslot available on the day is 14:30 \u2013 15:00.",
        "request_id": "e4c5e3b54d9004f127dbc5cf0bada387"
    },
    {
        "id": "b0951170-206c-4765-aa9b-d66a72cf05fa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_123.txt",
        "created": 1737369062,
        "question": "Do you accept the French equivalent of bachelors degree (3 years) in electronics, electric energy and automation, for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "TUM does not filter by specific bachelor\u2019s backgrounds. You can apply with your French degree, as long as it spanned at least 6 semesters, and you fulfilled at least 140 ECTS credits.",
        "request_id": "fe683c610880aa0586832a161aa642f0"
    },
    {
        "id": "2f8b33fe-2946-4e39-ade4-b3686962210b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_123.txt",
        "created": 1737369062,
        "question": "Do you offer a working student program in parallel to the AI in Society program at TUM, or any of your engineering master\u2019s programs?",
        "answer": "TUM doesn\u2019t specifically offer working student programs. Normally what people do in Germany, is to apply for working student jobs on their own, independently from the study program.",
        "request_id": "fe683c610880aa0586832a161aa642f0"
    },
    {
        "id": "a3af4273-4be8-40f0-bee1-4a0b9cfda898",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_125.txt",
        "created": 1737369073,
        "question": "Is it possible to submit independent or other project work that I have completed for other parties for admission to the AI in Society - MSc course?",
        "answer": "The practical project does not exclusively need to be from your bachelor\u2019s studies. Work experience or internships are also counted. It is important that there is some sort of proof of your project, i.e. that it can be seen that you did not just invent it. For example, a statement from your employer, or a certificate of participation in any external projects.",
        "request_id": "736d5b8e5bf38e84114ace7a381cd626"
    },
    {
        "id": "44589ca1-4cb9-4291-85c8-11fed9f7ec2f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_126.txt",
        "created": 1737369081,
        "question": "Where can I find the form for the list of best credits when applying for a Masters in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "The list of best credits is a form you will find as soon as you start the application. It will be available inside the portal. You don\u2019t need to download it externally anywhere.",
        "request_id": "9232fca428625bc97d0f93fe286771b9"
    },
    {
        "id": "a692da29-2747-44b1-b508-8fd85b9dd46f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_127.txt",
        "created": 1737369086,
        "question": "Is the department planning any online orientation?",
        "answer": "Yes, an introductory event for all incoming AI in Society students is being planned. The professors will introduce themselves and information around the program will be provided. This will be in October, at some point before the start of the semester.",
        "request_id": "2d8923fe09e1dd3bb45c99ef5c9b7b31"
    },
    {
        "id": "cdd366f9-c107-4761-b7cd-2762fd1baef7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_128.txt",
        "created": 1737369089,
        "question": "What is the second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second stage of the aptitude assessment is an interview. During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program. They will also explore your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations. The focus is on understanding your motivation for the study program, not testing your knowledge on specific subjects.",
        "request_id": "8a689e7a9dc0b88ff86d1d455b529cf0"
    },
    {
        "id": "cf1778e0-1172-4016-8d36-52da89e35ea2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_128.txt",
        "created": 1737369089,
        "question": "When will the aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place on September 16th. Timeslots are offered from 09:30 \u2013 11:00 and 13:00 \u2013 17:00 CEST (Germany time). The interview spans a time of 30 minutes.",
        "request_id": "8a689e7a9dc0b88ff86d1d455b529cf0"
    },
    {
        "id": "89adc34e-42d4-49ff-bf13-d9b2a2d492ae",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_128.txt",
        "created": 1737369089,
        "question": "When will the final decision be made after the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The final decision will be made right at the end of the interview. If admission is granted, it can be issued on the same day.",
        "request_id": "8a689e7a9dc0b88ff86d1d455b529cf0"
    },
    {
        "id": "e1fbea2c-229a-4ad8-84ef-cb6629ca84d5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_128.txt",
        "created": 1737369089,
        "question": "What is the preferred time slot for the interview by the applicant?",
        "answer": "The applicant prefers the time slot of 10am to 11am (10:00- 10:30 or 10:30 to 11:00) German time on Monday for the aptitude interview.",
        "request_id": "8a689e7a9dc0b88ff86d1d455b529cf0"
    },
    {
        "id": "881d3e64-8a87-4747-8be9-2f6bebd22c79",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_128.txt",
        "created": 1737369089,
        "question": "What is the final scheduled time for the applicant's interview?",
        "answer": "The final scheduled time for the applicant's interview is 10:00 \u2013 10:30AM.",
        "request_id": "8a689e7a9dc0b88ff86d1d455b529cf0"
    },
    {
        "id": "3b1aa50d-96b1-495b-abf3-51a718c10ee3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_129.txt",
        "created": 1737369103,
        "question": "Is the interview on site or online?",
        "answer": "The interview will be held online.",
        "request_id": "cee434e5091d1a705725b7a1b851620c"
    },
    {
        "id": "06b9a5be-4c8e-422c-9cd9-4816ac52bceb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_129.txt",
        "created": 1737369103,
        "question": "Shall I bring written information such as CV or is that not necessary?",
        "answer": "There is no need to prepare any documents for the interview.",
        "request_id": "cee434e5091d1a705725b7a1b851620c"
    },
    {
        "id": "610187a1-b24e-4059-98d1-b62b639162bd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_129.txt",
        "created": 1737369103,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program. They will also explore your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations. The focus is on understanding your motivation for the study program, not testing your knowledge on specific subjects.",
        "request_id": "cee434e5091d1a705725b7a1b851620c"
    },
    {
        "id": "23d421ec-2a85-4c53-96b5-b23e9c7e14ac",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_129.txt",
        "created": 1737369103,
        "question": "When will the interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place on September 16th.",
        "request_id": "cee434e5091d1a705725b7a1b851620c"
    },
    {
        "id": "f370c752-abb3-47bb-a13d-7785c20d0cdc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_129.txt",
        "created": 1737369103,
        "question": "What are the available timeslots for the interview?",
        "answer": "The available timeslots are from 09:30 \u2013 11:00 and 13:00 \u2013 17:00 CEST (Germany time). The interview spans a time of 30 minutes.",
        "request_id": "cee434e5091d1a705725b7a1b851620c"
    },
    {
        "id": "f9e00fcd-e1cc-4c52-9e65-7a337870297f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_130.txt",
        "created": 1737369114,
        "question": "What is the process if I haven't accepted the study offer so far?",
        "answer": "You can simply decline the offer online without providing any reason. You will need to apply again in the next application period and upload all documents to us again. However, you will be issued an admission from us right away (we can see in the system that we offered you a study place a year prior. You do not need to go through the selection process again).",
        "request_id": "9724ee76fd6672ff97a0e4f71f3148ea"
    },
    {
        "id": "1e260186-a5f8-4b21-9186-a0cfaa803f6a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_130.txt",
        "created": 1737369114,
        "question": "What should I do if I want to defer my admission to next year?",
        "answer": "If you want to defer your admission to next year, you can do so. In this case, you now need to decline the offer online. Then, next year you apply again with all documents, however, you will be automatically admitted by the matriculation office since you already had received an offer. So, you won\u2019t go through the selection process again next year.",
        "request_id": "9724ee76fd6672ff97a0e4f71f3148ea"
    },
    {
        "id": "79630702-c61c-4dff-8008-bf8cad11e4de",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_130.txt",
        "created": 1737369114,
        "question": "Where can I find the academic calendar for the MSc AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "You can find the academic calendar on our website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/. The lecture periods you can find here, under \u201csemester structure -> Winter semester 2024/25\u201d: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/application/application-info-portal/dates-periods-and-deadlines",
        "request_id": "9724ee76fd6672ff97a0e4f71f3148ea"
    },
    {
        "id": "199ee3c1-351f-4656-a3ea-4926b5a14908",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_130.txt",
        "created": 1737369114,
        "question": "Where can I find information about the syllabus for the MSc AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "For this, I can send you the relevant part of our study program documentation. Please find the relevant information in the document.",
        "request_id": "9724ee76fd6672ff97a0e4f71f3148ea"
    },
    {
        "id": "90ed90ad-98a7-4973-86c3-2c84ecbbcbfb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_130.txt",
        "created": 1737369114,
        "question": "What should I do if I have not yet secured accommodation, which is required for my visa?",
        "answer": "If you cannot find a place in a dormitory, you can look for shared flats for example on wg-gesucht.de",
        "request_id": "9724ee76fd6672ff97a0e4f71f3148ea"
    },
    {
        "id": "66b08417-40df-456d-b699-9a3586b7c30f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_131.txt",
        "created": 1737369127,
        "question": "When and where can I register for courses?",
        "answer": "You can register for courses on the TUMonline platform from October 1st.",
        "request_id": "70cdafe1030d3cd959b02d9dce0e821b"
    },
    {
        "id": "df8416cd-0c20-4649-8e7a-6a9c3740c06a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_131.txt",
        "created": 1737369127,
        "question": "Is it possible to attend courses from a higher semester in earlier semesters?",
        "answer": "Yes, it is possible.",
        "request_id": "70cdafe1030d3cd959b02d9dce0e821b"
    },
    {
        "id": "a33c85c5-4e4f-4af0-8803-5aa7a2f0c20c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_131.txt",
        "created": 1737369127,
        "question": "Where can I find more detailed information and conditions for a semester abroad?",
        "answer": "You can refer to this link for information about studying abroad: https://www.international.tum.de/global/auslandsaufenthalte/. If you have specific questions, feel free to contact the staff of Global & [REDACTED].",
        "request_id": "70cdafe1030d3cd959b02d9dce0e821b"
    },
    {
        "id": "06fafb3e-19b8-43df-badf-d5d0b19deadc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_131.txt",
        "created": 1737369127,
        "question": "When will the timetable for the first semester be available on the website?",
        "answer": "The timetable will be available on the website before the start of the semester.",
        "request_id": "70cdafe1030d3cd959b02d9dce0e821b"
    },
    {
        "id": "07990822-58f5-46da-8cc9-f0711eddd679",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_131.txt",
        "created": 1737369127,
        "question": "Why can't I find any of the modules for the first semester of the 'AI in Society' program on the course portal?",
        "answer": "Not all lecture plans have been completed yet, which is why you can't find them on TUMonline. A timetable for the first semester will be posted on the website soon.",
        "request_id": "70cdafe1030d3cd959b02d9dce0e821b"
    },
    {
        "id": "67f96502-d064-445e-ba3b-839111f4599d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_132.txt",
        "created": 1737369138,
        "question": "Is the interview on site or online?",
        "answer": "The interview will be held online.",
        "request_id": "0daca7d9550118325026a4ebdc79b63b"
    },
    {
        "id": "cb1686ca-07b6-4f20-8a79-01d7cafbbfc1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_132.txt",
        "created": 1737369138,
        "question": "Shall I bring written information such as CV or is that not necessary?",
        "answer": "There is no need to prepare any documents for the interview.",
        "request_id": "0daca7d9550118325026a4ebdc79b63b"
    },
    {
        "id": "fbeb42c9-1417-4f0d-b51f-64aebf1b46f6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_132.txt",
        "created": 1737369138,
        "question": "What is the purpose of the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program. They will also explore your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations. The focus is on understanding your motivation for the study program, not testing your knowledge on specific subjects.",
        "request_id": "0daca7d9550118325026a4ebdc79b63b"
    },
    {
        "id": "abbc4493-387a-482b-ae28-f95010eb6cb6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_132.txt",
        "created": 1737369138,
        "question": "When will the interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place and how long will they last?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place on September 16th. The interview spans a time of 30 minutes.",
        "request_id": "0daca7d9550118325026a4ebdc79b63b"
    },
    {
        "id": "748dd124-ebc0-4c5a-b9b7-21db03398b0d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_132.txt",
        "created": 1737369138,
        "question": "By when should I let you know my preferred timeslot for the interview?",
        "answer": "Please let me know your preferred timeslot (30 minutes within the above times) by September 12th, 23:59.",
        "request_id": "0daca7d9550118325026a4ebdc79b63b"
    },
    {
        "id": "3f50065d-8de1-4a5a-8e20-d02816b7d729",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_133.txt",
        "created": 1737369150,
        "question": "What is the second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second stage of the aptitude assessment is an interview. During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program. They will also explore your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations.",
        "request_id": "72501a4ccfe4db098fd02fd61a6002af"
    },
    {
        "id": "c685b040-01d0-406c-b5a9-23ff8871117a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_133.txt",
        "created": 1737369150,
        "question": "What will be the focus of the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The focus of the aptitude interview will be on understanding your motivation for the study program, not testing your knowledge on specific subjects.",
        "request_id": "72501a4ccfe4db098fd02fd61a6002af"
    },
    {
        "id": "68896e23-36f7-4194-8b7e-74cee71ba5ca",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_133.txt",
        "created": 1737369150,
        "question": "When and how long will the aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place on September 16th. The interview spans a time of 30 minutes.",
        "request_id": "72501a4ccfe4db098fd02fd61a6002af"
    },
    {
        "id": "2f067887-29f1-4a41-9976-97c4c58820a3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_133.txt",
        "created": 1737369150,
        "question": "When will the final decision be made after the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The final decision will be made right at the end of the interview. If an admission is decided, it can be issued on the same day.",
        "request_id": "72501a4ccfe4db098fd02fd61a6002af"
    },
    {
        "id": "c0c3db7a-5807-4c55-8dea-f023702bf478",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_134.txt",
        "created": 1737369162,
        "question": "What is the second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM is an interview. During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program. They will also explore your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations. The focus is on understanding your motivation for the study program, not testing your knowledge on specific subjects.",
        "request_id": "b149744ea7d5df0e602d30e3c41b5f52"
    },
    {
        "id": "0d462c4b-f817-45e8-b9f8-5835147ba63e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_134.txt",
        "created": 1737369162,
        "question": "When will the interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place and how long will they last?",
        "answer": "The interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM will take place on September 16th. They are offering timeslots in the time from 09:30 \u2013 11:00 and 13:00 \u2013 17:00 CEST (Germany time). The interview spans a time of 30 minutes.",
        "request_id": "b149744ea7d5df0e602d30e3c41b5f52"
    },
    {
        "id": "09e50c9e-9eea-42a3-9391-80788172fdd9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_134.txt",
        "created": 1737369162,
        "question": "When will the final decision be made after the interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The final decision will be made right at the end of the interview. If the decision is for admission, it can be issued on the same day.",
        "request_id": "b149744ea7d5df0e602d30e3c41b5f52"
    },
    {
        "id": "93a0fcee-3b4b-4d07-a04e-317999b5e945",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_135.txt",
        "created": 1737369171,
        "question": "What is the second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second stage of the aptitude assessment is an interview with two members of the selection committee.",
        "request_id": "a76625c5cadcead1a6b413cf4f99eb91"
    },
    {
        "id": "c55e509f-318a-43f7-8975-09d2a2840dde",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_135.txt",
        "created": 1737369171,
        "question": "What will be discussed during the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude interview, the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program, your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations.",
        "request_id": "a76625c5cadcead1a6b413cf4f99eb91"
    },
    {
        "id": "cae3422e-2a6a-4a33-a58e-6ae666b82653",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_135.txt",
        "created": 1737369171,
        "question": "When will the interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place on September 16th, with timeslots available from 09:30 \u2013 11:00 and 13:00 \u2013 17:00 CEST (Germany time).",
        "request_id": "a76625c5cadcead1a6b413cf4f99eb91"
    },
    {
        "id": "b4df45a7-a03a-43e5-8e4f-aa44e6859c8d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_135.txt",
        "created": 1737369171,
        "question": "How long will the interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM last?",
        "answer": "The interview spans a time of 30 minutes.",
        "request_id": "a76625c5cadcead1a6b413cf4f99eb91"
    },
    {
        "id": "97a782aa-32dc-4152-8cd4-3fc194e3ff78",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_135.txt",
        "created": 1737369171,
        "question": "By when should I let you know my preferred timeslot for the interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "You should let us know your preferred timeslot by September 12th, 23:59.",
        "request_id": "a76625c5cadcead1a6b413cf4f99eb91"
    },
    {
        "id": "67abc46f-d954-4040-9a7a-068af9340be8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_137.txt",
        "created": 1737369184,
        "question": "What is the result of my application?",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, your candidacy has led to a rejection. The points you scored in the test and from your degree grades do not pass our thresholds.",
        "request_id": "fbaee5a72f5b2944ae7fc20369771ad5"
    },
    {
        "id": "186cd2f4-ccf9-40e0-9ed8-6095e08f75e5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_137.txt",
        "created": 1737369184,
        "question": "Can I proceed to the interview phase despite the initial rejection?",
        "answer": "Given your high motivation and great performance in the written test, the program heads have decided to let you proceed to the interview phase.",
        "request_id": "fbaee5a72f5b2944ae7fc20369771ad5"
    },
    {
        "id": "7fa39eba-120f-4867-b433-bacaf0389c04",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_139.txt",
        "created": 1737369196,
        "question": "Can TUM provide an official document confirming the duration of the 'AI in Society' course and the tuition fee per semester?",
        "answer": "TUM can provide a signed statement about the duration of the study program. However, for the statement about tuition fees, you should contact TUM\u2019s fees and scholarships office.",
        "request_id": "416fa0a71109a4b5af0ab824f48a5a8a"
    },
    {
        "id": "aabeab48-aaa8-4cd0-be3f-a903cb26f221",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_139.txt",
        "created": 1737369196,
        "question": "Where can I get an official statement about tuition fees at TUM?",
        "answer": "You can get an official statement about tuition fees from TUM\u2019s fees and scholarships office. You can reach them through this link: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/fees",
        "request_id": "416fa0a71109a4b5af0ab824f48a5a8a"
    },
    {
        "id": "c6c5e7bb-41a9-4b6e-8939-cc67ea80b09a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_140.txt",
        "created": 1737369202,
        "question": "What is the second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second stage of the aptitude assessment is an interview with two members of the selection committee.",
        "request_id": "2302cc3d0f61a1022fa4089e07405a8d"
    },
    {
        "id": "f9ab5307-f20d-4ae9-b861-399b73ccdc5d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_140.txt",
        "created": 1737369202,
        "question": "What topics will be discussed during the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude interview, the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program, your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations.",
        "request_id": "2302cc3d0f61a1022fa4089e07405a8d"
    },
    {
        "id": "83ab7d46-40b4-46d7-ad1f-fddda8c11861",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_140.txt",
        "created": 1737369202,
        "question": "When will the aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place on September 16th, with timeslots available from 09:30 \u2013 11:00 and 13:00 \u2013 17:00 CEST (Germany time).",
        "request_id": "2302cc3d0f61a1022fa4089e07405a8d"
    },
    {
        "id": "dcec9bc9-a0ce-4f23-9fa3-628356e7e9b7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_140.txt",
        "created": 1737369202,
        "question": "How long is the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The interview spans a time of 30 minutes.",
        "request_id": "2302cc3d0f61a1022fa4089e07405a8d"
    },
    {
        "id": "817a54b6-cd13-4cd2-baec-12b37605d129",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_140.txt",
        "created": 1737369202,
        "question": "By when should I let you know my preferred timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "You should let us know your preferred timeslot by September 12th, 23:59.",
        "request_id": "2302cc3d0f61a1022fa4089e07405a8d"
    },
    {
        "id": "8ac1642d-f259-423a-8b84-2476932ae4bb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_141.txt",
        "created": 1737369215,
        "question": "What is the second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM is an interview.",
        "request_id": "d9e1f3dbf3958a361616f93c5cd693ce"
    },
    {
        "id": "5c1fcdaa-eb1a-4fc0-a080-bb553301b9aa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_141.txt",
        "created": 1737369215,
        "question": "What topics will be discussed during the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program, your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations.",
        "request_id": "d9e1f3dbf3958a361616f93c5cd693ce"
    },
    {
        "id": "5f8b172f-42d1-4298-ae09-e4c23cc581c6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_141.txt",
        "created": 1737369215,
        "question": "When will the aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM will take place on September 16th, with timeslots available from 09:30 \u2013 11:00 and 13:00 \u2013 17:00 CEST (Germany time).",
        "request_id": "d9e1f3dbf3958a361616f93c5cd693ce"
    },
    {
        "id": "6247140a-9a37-464f-b514-f164630dd941",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_141.txt",
        "created": 1737369215,
        "question": "How long is the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM spans a time of 30 minutes.",
        "request_id": "d9e1f3dbf3958a361616f93c5cd693ce"
    },
    {
        "id": "7bb2fe45-cc38-46e3-9568-2c9ac2fcf925",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_141.txt",
        "created": 1737369215,
        "question": "By when should I let you know my preferred timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "You should let us know your preferred timeslot for the aptitude interview by September 12th, 23:59.",
        "request_id": "d9e1f3dbf3958a361616f93c5cd693ce"
    },
    {
        "id": "690b2bbe-b86b-46b2-aa4a-f6a7b8030acd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_142.txt",
        "created": 1737369228,
        "question": "Can I get an early admission decision due to my visa appointment?",
        "answer": "The admission decision has been expedited due to the urgency of the visa appointment.",
        "request_id": "cbc804fbac1164a5dadf2063e61032c4"
    },
    {
        "id": "1035dcce-bb59-4985-ab2c-210a3a9399c2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_142.txt",
        "created": 1737369228,
        "question": "What is the result of my application?",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, your candidacy has led to a rejection. The points you scored in the test and from your degree grades do not pass our thresholds.",
        "request_id": "cbc804fbac1164a5dadf2063e61032c4"
    },
    {
        "id": "ede6d278-0bcd-4ed3-8aef-ddce363bde84",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_143.txt",
        "created": 1737369236,
        "question": "What kind of document should I prepare for enrollment to the MSc AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "You can find the required documents for enrollment under the 'documents required for enrollment' section on the TUM website: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/degree-programs/detail/ai-in-society.",
        "request_id": "c6ada749e07a6f4c9668bd5491fcdcf8"
    },
    {
        "id": "9845043a-cf9c-4eab-a3c0-ac190625e635",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_143.txt",
        "created": 1737369236,
        "question": "Where can I find the academic calendar for the MSc AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "You can find the academic calendar on the TUM website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/. The lecture periods can be found under 'semester structure -> Winter semester 2024/25' on the following page: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/application/application-info-portal/dates-periods-and-deadlines.",
        "request_id": "c6ada749e07a6f4c9668bd5491fcdcf8"
    },
    {
        "id": "0eb4c0f5-3a50-42b7-b2e5-7aae854910fd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_143.txt",
        "created": 1737369236,
        "question": "How can I get the syllabus for the MSc AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The relevant part of the study program documentation can be sent to you upon request.",
        "request_id": "c6ada749e07a6f4c9668bd5491fcdcf8"
    },
    {
        "id": "a7e07b2f-ac68-4d4b-b230-d909fb857dac",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_143.txt",
        "created": 1737369236,
        "question": "What should I do if I cannot find a place in a dormitory for the MSc AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "If you cannot find a place in a dormitory, you can look for shared flats, for example on wg-gesucht.de.",
        "request_id": "c6ada749e07a6f4c9668bd5491fcdcf8"
    },
    {
        "id": "995aa5e0-5c99-4918-a88b-8ba3cdbf2753",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_143.txt",
        "created": 1737369236,
        "question": "How can I update my name in TUMOnline and my Letter of Admission?",
        "answer": "For this matter, you need to contact TUM\u2019s student information service desk: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/support-and-advice/support-during-studies/student-information.",
        "request_id": "c6ada749e07a6f4c9668bd5491fcdcf8"
    },
    {
        "id": "cae8e17d-1753-47ec-b1c6-a5c1ef1a66d2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_143.txt",
        "created": 1737369236,
        "question": "Is it possible to defer my admission to the MSc AI in Society program at TUM to next year? How can I do that?",
        "answer": "If you want to defer your admission to next year, you can do so. In this case, you now need to decline the offer online. Then, next year you apply again with all documents, however, you will be automatically admitted by the matriculation office since you already had received an offer. So, you won\u2019t go through the selection process again next year.",
        "request_id": "c6ada749e07a6f4c9668bd5491fcdcf8"
    },
    {
        "id": "72853a0d-e9ae-42ac-97c5-4b98141b4f0c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_144.txt",
        "created": 1737369258,
        "question": "What is the standard duration of the 'AI in Society' program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The standard duration for the 'AI in Society' program at TUM is 4 semesters.",
        "request_id": "589c1bb80e2c4cbf380d337d2abc4f79"
    },
    {
        "id": "61243a17-1d75-4bec-af70-48834e878251",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_144.txt",
        "created": 1737369258,
        "question": "What is the tuition fee for each semester in the 'AI in Society' program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The tuition fee for each semester in the 'AI in Society' program at TUM is \u20ac4,085.",
        "request_id": "589c1bb80e2c4cbf380d337d2abc4f79"
    },
    {
        "id": "a6258477-e899-40c4-9d15-e1e67794d138",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_144.txt",
        "created": 1737369258,
        "question": "Who should be contacted for confirmation about the tuition fee for the 'AI in Society' program at TUM?",
        "answer": "For confirmation about the tuition fee, one should contact the TUM Beitragsmanagement.",
        "request_id": "589c1bb80e2c4cbf380d337d2abc4f79"
    },
    {
        "id": "58fc5edf-3483-466c-a1b6-87e070868a7b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_145.txt",
        "created": 1737369268,
        "question": "What is the format of the AI in Society aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The test will consist of 35 multiple choice questions spanned over 90 minutes, and will be held over TUM's internal moodle platform. The topics will span Politics, Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, and Engineering.",
        "request_id": "9a10294aa3b2476c2eae9dfaf86c28b1"
    },
    {
        "id": "fc92d6f4-f462-40d4-9b29-8254298063c1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_145.txt",
        "created": 1737369268,
        "question": "What are the options for taking the AI in Society aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You can choose between an on-campus and an off-campus (online) variant. The online variant requires you to pay a fee of 25$ for the proctoring software Proctorio, as well as ensure a working webcam and microphone. The on-campus variant does not require any fee, as you will be monitored by staff in person. It will take place in Marsstr. 20-22, Munich, room 605, 6th floor. You will need to bring your laptop to take the test in the on-campus variant.",
        "request_id": "9a10294aa3b2476c2eae9dfaf86c28b1"
    },
    {
        "id": "a67f1dc9-49b7-4127-9607-54e5eb05fb90",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_145.txt",
        "created": 1737369268,
        "question": "What should I do if I can't bring a laptop for the on-campus AI in Society aptitude test?",
        "answer": "If you are unable to bring a laptop for the test, you should let the committee know in advance. They will provide you with a laptop in this case.",
        "request_id": "9a10294aa3b2476c2eae9dfaf86c28b1"
    },
    {
        "id": "55fd9c6c-11fb-49ce-bfcf-9bc7c56b66f3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_145.txt",
        "created": 1737369268,
        "question": "What materials am I allowed to use during the AI in Society aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You will be allowed to use a calculator, as well as a piece of paper and pen to help you during the test.",
        "request_id": "9a10294aa3b2476c2eae9dfaf86c28b1"
    },
    {
        "id": "dafa2e5b-1b44-41bd-a086-d99c5a01898c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_146.txt",
        "created": 1737369283,
        "question": "Can I apply with an expired passport?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can apply with an expired passport under certain circumstances. However, you may need to provide a recently renewed passport if requested.",
        "request_id": "d8df6e1058308a3e520e064aee43566f"
    },
    {
        "id": "df6883b6-58dd-428f-a274-576434c6be49",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_146.txt",
        "created": 1737369283,
        "question": "When is the AI in Society aptitude test and what does it consist of?",
        "answer": "The AI in Society aptitude test is on September 3rd, from 11:00-12:30 CEST. It consists of 35 multiple choice questions over 90 minutes, covering topics such as Politics, Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, and Engineering. The test will be held over TUM's internal moodle platform.",
        "request_id": "d8df6e1058308a3e520e064aee43566f"
    },
    {
        "id": "9bd97928-81f6-43d1-9bda-2d3974dbe052",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_146.txt",
        "created": 1737369283,
        "question": "What are the options for taking the AI in Society aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You can choose between an on-campus and an off-campus (online) variant. The off-campus variant requires a fee of 25$ for the proctoring software Proctorio and a working webcam and microphone. The on-campus variant does not require any fee, as you will be monitored by staff in person. It will take place in Marsstr. 20-22, Munich, room 605, 6th floor. You will need to bring your laptop to take the test in the on-campus variant.",
        "request_id": "d8df6e1058308a3e520e064aee43566f"
    },
    {
        "id": "8c595f2a-1ec4-4b30-989a-76517db9953c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_146.txt",
        "created": 1737369283,
        "question": "What should I do to prepare for the AI in Society aptitude test?",
        "answer": "In the coming days, you will receive the link to the moodle test. There, you should 1) choose your preferred exam modality (on-/off-campus) and 2) take the demo test to make yourself familiar with the test environment. If you choose the off-campus version, you will also be guided through the Proctorio installation and payment process.",
        "request_id": "d8df6e1058308a3e520e064aee43566f"
    },
    {
        "id": "8e1ce9d3-5d92-470c-a2dd-e63b2bb36c3f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_148.txt",
        "created": 1737369301,
        "question": "Can I know the schedule for the lectures (hour/day) for the upcoming winter semester?",
        "answer": "The dates and times for the lectures are currently being finalized and are subject to change. Once finalized, the information can be found on the website.",
        "request_id": "5e648f20eb267a45db05b7a3c995f888"
    },
    {
        "id": "189912fb-0bab-4781-aaba-ca76fc4e99f0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_150.txt",
        "created": 1737369309,
        "question": "When is the third aptitude test scheduled?",
        "answer": "The third aptitude test is being set up for September 3rd.",
        "request_id": "137575186997e89328ed7bc21a890a83"
    },
    {
        "id": "db42d02c-b55b-4442-9361-5b7c84df910e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_150.txt",
        "created": 1737369309,
        "question": "Will there be an online option for taking the test?",
        "answer": "Yes, there will be both an online option and an in-person option for taking the test.",
        "request_id": "137575186997e89328ed7bc21a890a83"
    },
    {
        "id": "3f91705f-83c6-4a09-88a9-91db0bfc7f1e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_150.txt",
        "created": 1737369309,
        "question": "What is the status of my application?",
        "answer": "Your application seems to be all good now. You will be invited to the third aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "137575186997e89328ed7bc21a890a83"
    },
    {
        "id": "82764448-9d64-40ce-9cb4-fe3582bc5e6c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_150.txt",
        "created": 1737369309,
        "question": "Why haven't I been invited to the test on July 16th?",
        "answer": "Some documents in your application are still not marked as \u201cOK\u201d. The matriculation office needs to be consulted about this. The documents won\u2019t be assessed fast enough to invite you to the test tomorrow. However, you will be invited to a third test date, should all your documents be sufficient in the end.",
        "request_id": "137575186997e89328ed7bc21a890a83"
    },
    {
        "id": "4276f868-7f36-4279-b3f2-e1d738b5897a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_151.txt",
        "created": 1737369018,
        "question": "Could you please confirm on which campus all my subjects will be held?",
        "answer": "The majority of the subjects will be held in the city center. Specifically, you will have your lectures in Richard-Wagner-Str.1, Marsstr. 20-22, and Arcisstr. 21.",
        "request_id": "7f3bf9b158ed74c32a640ae86801c2bb"
    },
    {
        "id": "e2af74f1-8da9-4355-b7f0-92d959db9e1c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_151.txt",
        "created": 1737369018,
        "question": "Could you provide details on the evaluation system for each subject? For example, will there be a combination of assignments, projects, and a final exam? Additionally, what percentage of the final grade will be based on the final exam?",
        "answer": "The lecture type modules usually end with a final exam making up the entire grade. Some lectures also have an accompanying exercise with assignments, which can give bonus points to the final exam. In the seminar type modules, the examination can consist of a presentation, a small group project, or similar. This depends on the final decision of the lecturer.",
        "request_id": "7f3bf9b158ed74c32a640ae86801c2bb"
    },
    {
        "id": "24bd0a13-36eb-4cf7-a511-066ffc96d6dc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_151.txt",
        "created": 1737369018,
        "question": "Does the master\u2019s program include internships to gain practical work experience in Germany? If so, when would these internships typically take place?",
        "answer": "Our program does not include internships in a fixed manner, i.e. they are not explicitly integrated into the study program and are not mandatory. However, you are of course welcome to complete an internship regardless during your studies, which is also highly recommended. Many students also work part-time in companies as so called \u201cWerkstudent\u201d.",
        "request_id": "7f3bf9b158ed74c32a640ae86801c2bb"
    },
    {
        "id": "50348b1d-6e28-412c-8580-0c18557e82b6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_151.txt",
        "created": 1737369018,
        "question": "I will need to travel to my home country from December 10th to 20th aprox. Would it be possible to attend classes online during this period without negatively affecting my performance?",
        "answer": "No, this will not be a problem. You will be able to follow the content online, as the lectures will be streamed in parallel (e.g. via Zoom).",
        "request_id": "7f3bf9b158ed74c32a640ae86801c2bb"
    },
    {
        "id": "5b4cf1ef-b109-4607-993b-bfb8613bea25",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_151.txt",
        "created": 1737369018,
        "question": "How relevant is proficiency in German for succeeding in the Master\u2019s program and securing job opportunities related to the field? Also, does TUM offer German language courses as an extracurricular option included in the Master's program fees?",
        "answer": "German language is not required for our Master\u2019s program, as all modules are taught in English. But, of course, some knowledge of German will make life here easier for you. Please feel free to check out TUM\u2019s language center: https://www.sprachenzentrum.tum.de/en/sz/homepage/",
        "request_id": "7f3bf9b158ed74c32a640ae86801c2bb"
    },
    {
        "id": "fadb1764-e939-43ad-9820-e59c677d6131",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_152.txt",
        "created": 1737369039,
        "question": "Where will the main classes for the AI in Society program be held?",
        "answer": "The main classes will be held in different campuses in the city center. Specifically, they will be in Marsstr. 20-22, Richard-Wagner-Str. 1, and Arcisstr. 21.",
        "request_id": "b34e6483b231abe0ec7a6816a6218043"
    },
    {
        "id": "b164c1b9-3190-4962-8ffe-ad14e56f0a2d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_152.txt",
        "created": 1737369039,
        "question": "When do the lectures for the AI in Society program officially start?",
        "answer": "The lectures officially start on October 14th.",
        "request_id": "b34e6483b231abe0ec7a6816a6218043"
    },
    {
        "id": "8e6db99b-7178-45c4-919d-70b14e63cbe0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_153.txt",
        "created": 1737369045,
        "question": "Where can I find the academic calendar for the MSc AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "You can find the academic calendar on our website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/. The lecture periods you can find here, under \u201csemester structure -> Winter semester 2024/25\u201d: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/application/application-info-portal/dates-periods-and-deadlines",
        "request_id": "714c0212b3121d8b0cc1e5464a4b57eb"
    },
    {
        "id": "577513a2-9cc0-4fbd-9947-f70beaec35fd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_153.txt",
        "created": 1737369045,
        "question": "I would like to request the syllabus for the MSc AI in Society program, including details on the learning plan, competency standards, core competencies, main topics/materials, learning activities, competency achievement indicators for assessment, time allocation, and learning resources.",
        "answer": "For this, I can send you the relevant part of our study program documentation. Please find the relevant information in the document.",
        "request_id": "714c0212b3121d8b0cc1e5464a4b57eb"
    },
    {
        "id": "890afcca-6667-4553-935d-c76829f1d314",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_153.txt",
        "created": 1737369045,
        "question": "I have not yet secured accommodation, which is required for my visa. I have contacted several student dormitories, but they are either full, have closed their applications, or haven't responded to my messages. Could you assist me with this?",
        "answer": "If you cannot find a place in a dormitory, you can look for shared flats for example on wg-gesucht.de.",
        "request_id": "714c0212b3121d8b0cc1e5464a4b57eb"
    },
    {
        "id": "b915c7c4-7f37-4200-bb06-1e69e63afb6f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_153.txt",
        "created": 1737369045,
        "question": "The name on all my documents ([REDACTED]) is different from the name on my passport ([REDACTED]). The embassy has requested that I renew my passport to match the name on my birth certificate. Could I update my name in TUMOnline and my Letter of Admission to reflect '[REDACTED]'?",
        "answer": "For this matter, you need to contact TUM\u2019s student information service desk: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/support-and-advice/support-during-studies/student-information",
        "request_id": "714c0212b3121d8b0cc1e5464a4b57eb"
    },
    {
        "id": "02142f2c-80eb-48d0-a17f-c3bdd8002d10",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_153.txt",
        "created": 1737369045,
        "question": "Is it possible to Defer my admission? How to do that?",
        "answer": "If you want to defer your admission to next year, you can do so. In this case, you now need to decline the offer online. Then, next year you apply again with all documents, however, you will be automatically admitted by the matriculation office since you already had received an offer. So, you won\u2019t go through the selection process again next year.",
        "request_id": "714c0212b3121d8b0cc1e5464a4b57eb"
    },
    {
        "id": "19b4d961-cf9f-479f-8078-950b30f7e7a3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_154.txt",
        "created": 1737369064,
        "question": "If I complete the first year of my AI Master's program at Utrecht University in the Netherlands and then wish to transfer to the AI Master's program at TUM, would I need to provide a VPD (preliminary documentation review) certification?",
        "answer": "When you started studying at Utrecht, if you submitted a VPD there, you can submit the same one to us. If not, please refer to the information stated here: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/application/application-info-portal/uni-assist. All applicants for a master's degree who did not obtain their qualification for postgraduate studies (usually a bachelor's degree) in a country within the EU/EEA have to apply via uni-assist.",
        "request_id": "f90049676fd469429dc2c910dd8cb667"
    },
    {
        "id": "48e13571-8532-498d-bb5b-baae9b72c659",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_156.txt",
        "created": 1737369073,
        "question": "Can an applicant who failed the aptitude test retake the test in the same semester?",
        "answer": "No, the phrase 'those who did not pass the aptitude assessment can repeat the test' means that the applicant can reapply in the next winter semester, not that they can retake the test in the current semester.",
        "request_id": "ce8ceaef77fc149204f6965a67c46734"
    },
    {
        "id": "eb434b59-ef7a-4615-b0b4-47a06060032c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_156.txt",
        "created": 1737369073,
        "question": "Can an applicant who has been rejected after the interview be re-evaluated or offered a new interview?",
        "answer": "No, exceptions cannot be made to re-evaluate people again after they have already gone through the interview and were rejected by the selection committee members.",
        "request_id": "ce8ceaef77fc149204f6965a67c46734"
    },
    {
        "id": "1fec488a-5cf9-47f4-bff0-eac7363c7cbf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_156.txt",
        "created": 1737369073,
        "question": "Can the committee reconsider an application after it has been rejected?",
        "answer": "No, the decision made by the committee is final and cannot be reconsidered.",
        "request_id": "ce8ceaef77fc149204f6965a67c46734"
    },
    {
        "id": "426d11b3-9ffb-4548-ae1c-13ff34e281c1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_157.txt",
        "created": 1737369080,
        "question": "Can a rejected applicant retake the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The aptitude assessment PDF states that those who did not pass the aptitude assessment can repeat the test. However, the university cannot make exceptions and re-evaluate people again after they have already gone through the interview and were rejected by the selection committee members.",
        "request_id": "f2ffffb8c78742f3f76b24003e48ac77"
    },
    {
        "id": "4b963c16-0bf2-464e-8340-338a7eafe523",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_157.txt",
        "created": 1737369080,
        "question": "Can the selection committee reconsider a rejected application?",
        "answer": "The selection committee cannot offer a new interview or reconsider an application once the decision has already been made.",
        "request_id": "f2ffffb8c78742f3f76b24003e48ac77"
    },
    {
        "id": "cbd1c33c-3e99-40e5-a738-fc1c95a7b046",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_157.txt",
        "created": 1737369080,
        "question": "Does having a previous master's degree affect an applicant's chances of acceptance?",
        "answer": "During the interview, the applicant was informed that because they already have a master's degree, the preference was to give the opportunity to applicants who do not yet have a master's degree.",
        "request_id": "f2ffffb8c78742f3f76b24003e48ac77"
    },
    {
        "id": "f219ed99-fb8f-4443-849f-aa645e589ba9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_158.txt",
        "created": 1737369089,
        "question": "Do I need to provide a VPD (preliminary review documentation) certification as part of my application process for transferring to the AI Master's program at LMU?",
        "answer": "Since you are transferring to the LMU, and not TUM, you should contact them instead.",
        "request_id": "b0b697636733371483bf5946be68e84a"
    },
    {
        "id": "4c25115c-7a90-401c-a7d1-1f1ac920ce98",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_159.txt",
        "created": 1737369092,
        "question": "Would it be possible for the university to assist by writing to the German consulate or embassy on my behalf?",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, we cannot contact the embassy in this matter.",
        "request_id": "991edec4cd91860cc0145b91350a02fe"
    },
    {
        "id": "987359db-e967-45cc-b9a3-089ea1145937",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_159.txt",
        "created": 1737369092,
        "question": "What steps should I take if I receive my visa later than expected?",
        "answer": "If you will be in Munich physically a bit later, it should be no problem since we will be offering the first semester lectures online. This way, you will not miss any content.",
        "request_id": "991edec4cd91860cc0145b91350a02fe"
    },
    {
        "id": "e4e9420d-e8df-4091-bb5e-622b25976a23",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_160.txt",
        "created": 1737369097,
        "question": "Where will most of the lectures for the AI in Society course take place?",
        "answer": "Most of the lectures will take place in the city center, specifically at the following locations: Richard-Wagner-Str. 1, Marsstr., and Arcisstr. 21 (Main building). In the second and third semesters, there is one module each that usually takes place in Garching, but that is the exception. You can expect most of your time to be spent in the city center.",
        "request_id": "375f2ba0c1da95f1e0ac643d0ca38a3a"
    },
    {
        "id": "ec928401-1c14-4cef-bb8f-c62defe6d249",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_160.txt",
        "created": 1737369097,
        "question": "Will all the lectures for the AI in Society course take place at the Garching campus?",
        "answer": "No, most of the lectures will take place in the city center. Only one module each in the second and third semesters usually takes place in Garching.",
        "request_id": "375f2ba0c1da95f1e0ac643d0ca38a3a"
    },
    {
        "id": "b1d95719-8722-47d2-bc27-6971d23effcd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_161.txt",
        "created": 1737369104,
        "question": "Can a rejected applicant request a re-evaluation or a new interview?",
        "answer": "No, exceptions cannot be made to re-evaluate people again after they have already gone through the interview and were rejected by the selection committee members.",
        "request_id": "90c5ae162e2beaba4a7a00c751c0aa49"
    },
    {
        "id": "3156d13d-c5dc-484f-8d49-6a27d942f52e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_162.txt",
        "created": 1737369129,
        "question": "Is the practical project from my current master's program also taken into account for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Yes, the practical project from your Master\u2019s degree will be acknowledged for the AI in Society program.",
        "request_id": "40b1b6eff53d19420e13d82f16687523"
    },
    {
        "id": "c53a7064-7024-41dc-8579-3e65ed81a8b8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_162.txt",
        "created": 1737369129,
        "question": "Since this will be my second master's program, will I have to pay the tuition fee?",
        "answer": "For information about tuition fees, refer to the TUM student information: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/support-and-advice/support-during-studies/student-information",
        "request_id": "40b1b6eff53d19420e13d82f16687523"
    },
    {
        "id": "2f8a178c-5640-413e-8a37-2ca8c4b6c5a1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_163.txt",
        "created": 1737369134,
        "question": "Are there any introductory and orientation events for new AI in Society students before the courses start?",
        "answer": "Yes, a welcome event for all new AI in Society students is planned at the beginning of October, before the lectures start.",
        "request_id": "56158121939a2f6570906b7f32e4990d"
    },
    {
        "id": "e75dfd8b-55a1-481e-94ff-7f841159a0aa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_164.txt",
        "created": 1737369137,
        "question": "Could I attend my course online until my visa is ready?",
        "answer": "It will be no problem if you attend the courses online until end of October.",
        "request_id": "3f3c5003eca50285f671404080d429b0"
    },
    {
        "id": "db51a127-7fe5-4528-ba90-f20bd291df80",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_164.txt",
        "created": 1737369137,
        "question": "Could you please advise if it would be possible to defer my start date to the next summer semester?",
        "answer": "You cannot officially start in a summer semester. You could only defer it to next winter semester (if you have not yet accepted the offer online).",
        "request_id": "3f3c5003eca50285f671404080d429b0"
    },
    {
        "id": "a38ed6f9-dbeb-4a93-a8ac-c928ccaab2e2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_164.txt",
        "created": 1737369137,
        "question": "Can I participate in the courses online while I am not yet in Munich?",
        "answer": "For the time being (while you are not yet in Munich), you can participate in the courses online. We will make sure they will all be streamed in parallel for people who could not make it here physically in time.",
        "request_id": "3f3c5003eca50285f671404080d429b0"
    },
    {
        "id": "7939751b-b79c-4900-9438-0cfdeb768657",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_165.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "Is there a deadline for applying for the waiver for the winter semester?",
        "answer": "The email implies that there was a deadline for applying for the waiver for the winter semester, but it has already passed.",
        "request_id": "29b26332e29b719a871fc4fd9762ae23"
    },
    {
        "id": "2b75bbf4-4080-4380-a80a-23aea95182f0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_165.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "Can I officially start my studies in a summer semester?",
        "answer": "No, you cannot officially start your studies in a summer semester, only in winter.",
        "request_id": "29b26332e29b719a871fc4fd9762ae23"
    },
    {
        "id": "3feddd96-5476-4ceb-8e3b-b04d1de2be57",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_165.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "Can the TUM's scholarship office reimburse me for this winter semester if I officially apply for the waiver for the summer semester?",
        "answer": "The email suggests reaching out to TUM's scholarship office to see if they can reimburse you for this winter semester, even if you officially apply for the waiver for the summer semester.",
        "request_id": "29b26332e29b719a871fc4fd9762ae23"
    },
    {
        "id": "4e9aea16-65d4-445b-a2fe-872aa403b406",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_165.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "Can I look for a student side job to support my studies?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can look for a student side job. Specifically, these kinds of positions are called 'Werkstudent', you can look online for such positions.",
        "request_id": "29b26332e29b719a871fc4fd9762ae23"
    },
    {
        "id": "466e13ca-19a8-4723-ba75-3ae76c22ef19",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_165.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "Can I apply for DAAD scholarships?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can apply for DAAD scholarships, assuming their deadline has not passed yet.",
        "request_id": "29b26332e29b719a871fc4fd9762ae23"
    },
    {
        "id": "561efff4-ab8b-4e4d-bcf7-8fc9aa045157",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_166.txt",
        "created": 1737369157,
        "question": "Does a digitally verifiable document require additional notarization for enrollment at TUM?",
        "answer": "A digitally verifiable document does not require additional notarization.",
        "request_id": "93de8b06a4ab121ad10d4c271845e8fc"
    },
    {
        "id": "ac2affb0-ae13-442e-9adb-7c835454be8c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_166.txt",
        "created": 1737369157,
        "question": "How should the documents for enrollment be submitted to TUM?",
        "answer": "The documents should be submitted along with the signed application for enrollment by mail.",
        "request_id": "93de8b06a4ab121ad10d4c271845e8fc"
    },
    {
        "id": "2bff08e4-3dd6-4821-a219-b8e678f2f4fd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_167.txt",
        "created": 1737369162,
        "question": "Can I upload my new passport document later in case of admission?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can upload your new document later in case of admission.",
        "request_id": "a30e3b1682a8aed00c51e3e789e8304e"
    },
    {
        "id": "6b100ed9-6a5a-4714-9b85-9b3645954006",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_167.txt",
        "created": 1737369162,
        "question": "Can I be invited to the aptitude test if there's an issue with my passport upload?",
        "answer": "Yes, you will be invited to the aptitude test at the beginning of September, should all documents be okay.",
        "request_id": "a30e3b1682a8aed00c51e3e789e8304e"
    },
    {
        "id": "71591528-e401-4c25-9d68-bd8463b09a30",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_167.txt",
        "created": 1737369162,
        "question": "When is the aptitude test scheduled?",
        "answer": "The aptitude test is scheduled for September 3rd.",
        "request_id": "a30e3b1682a8aed00c51e3e789e8304e"
    },
    {
        "id": "fbeaf02a-cc95-48c6-b9ea-a5059d4da093",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_168.txt",
        "created": 1737369168,
        "question": "Can the AI in Society program provide a letter verifying my English language proficiency?",
        "answer": "No, the AI in Society program cannot issue a verification of English language proficiency, as you have not studied with them.",
        "request_id": "039d9d979bc41ac971718d8348a5b7be"
    },
    {
        "id": "933f9cb7-4b7b-44b4-a166-39f55a7b6cc6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_168.txt",
        "created": 1737369168,
        "question": "What should the letter verifying my English language proficiency contain?",
        "answer": "The letter should confirm that the M.Sc AI in Society department has looked at your application and confirmed that you as an applicant have enough English skills to enroll for the master program.",
        "request_id": "039d9d979bc41ac971718d8348a5b7be"
    },
    {
        "id": "6cb1ffda-72f2-415e-bae6-91289ee4d03f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_168.txt",
        "created": 1737369168,
        "question": "Who suggested that the AI in Society program can help me with the verification of my English language proficiency?",
        "answer": "The School of social sciences and technology suggested that the AI in Society program can help you with the verification of your English language proficiency.",
        "request_id": "039d9d979bc41ac971718d8348a5b7be"
    },
    {
        "id": "67aae57e-407e-4978-9f4b-daea77d3a84a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_168.txt",
        "created": 1737369168,
        "question": "Why do I need a letter verifying my English language proficiency?",
        "answer": "You need a letter verifying your English language proficiency for your visa application, as your IELTS score is 1 year old.",
        "request_id": "039d9d979bc41ac971718d8348a5b7be"
    },
    {
        "id": "06ec9e21-831e-4479-8b24-00ebe1d248bf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_168.txt",
        "created": 1737369168,
        "question": "Who should issue the letter verifying my English language proficiency?",
        "answer": "The department you actually received your degree from should issue the letter verifying your English language proficiency.",
        "request_id": "039d9d979bc41ac971718d8348a5b7be"
    },
    {
        "id": "bf8de96e-4350-4b1b-8826-c56b040ec214",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_169.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "Can the department issue a verification of English language proficiency?",
        "answer": "The department cannot issue a verification of English language proficiency if you have not studied with them.",
        "request_id": "b1b710dbaafbe6077557703100e6d79c"
    },
    {
        "id": "254f46e4-c558-4154-9f50-ef58717af5cc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_169.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "What does the letter verifying English language proficiency need to state?",
        "answer": "The letter should state that the M.Sc AI in Society department has looked at the application and confirmed that the applicant has enough English skills to enroll for the master program.",
        "request_id": "b1b710dbaafbe6077557703100e6d79c"
    },
    {
        "id": "beddae90-7d8c-4ab6-90eb-1155f92d0c10",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_169.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "Who should issue the verification of English language proficiency?",
        "answer": "The verification of English language proficiency should be issued by the department where the degree was received.",
        "request_id": "b1b710dbaafbe6077557703100e6d79c"
    },
    {
        "id": "8f37e7b2-b2aa-4d5d-b318-bfdaf5abad24",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_169.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "Why is a letter verifying English language proficiency needed?",
        "answer": "The letter verifying English language proficiency is required for a visa application in India, as the IELTS score is 1 year old, even though the validity for IELTS is 2 years.",
        "request_id": "b1b710dbaafbe6077557703100e6d79c"
    },
    {
        "id": "9c1aa7bd-838c-4411-8c82-35c079fb15cb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_170.txt",
        "created": 1737369187,
        "question": "Can the candidate upload his passport again?",
        "answer": "Please upload the correct document if you have it.",
        "request_id": "6d7951ffffcf5c94530c209e31a65399"
    },
    {
        "id": "13693d6c-d41a-4cf5-a594-c120d5db6ad7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_170.txt",
        "created": 1737369187,
        "question": "Can the candidate receive a link to the test?",
        "answer": "We are offering another test right at the beginning of September, to which we will of course invite you, should all documents be okay.",
        "request_id": "6d7951ffffcf5c94530c209e31a65399"
    },
    {
        "id": "911e8669-bfa2-4b7a-8756-c3b6f23de215",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_170.txt",
        "created": 1737369187,
        "question": "Can the candidate upload a new passport if there is an issue with the passport upload on the application portal?",
        "answer": "Please upload the correct document if you have it.",
        "request_id": "6d7951ffffcf5c94530c209e31a65399"
    },
    {
        "id": "3eb03d3c-2cb1-4db0-abd8-897e2939b108",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_171.txt",
        "created": 1737369195,
        "question": "Is the AI in Society program at TUM also taught in the summer semester 2025, or is the start always only possible in the winter semester?",
        "answer": "Enrollment for AI in Society is generally only possible in the winter semester. The next possible start of studies would be in October 2025.",
        "request_id": "ab940cfe0d32d2ec15260e966fea1e56"
    },
    {
        "id": "a38d909a-c138-479b-9a69-4282a41778e2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_172.txt",
        "created": 1737369198,
        "question": "Could you please confirm whether the classes for the first semester will be conducted online or in person?",
        "answer": "We are planning to conduct the classes of the first semester both in-person and stream in parallel online.",
        "request_id": "283bb41dfa9c6f4d0e6368f5bf031f64"
    },
    {
        "id": "09ef97e1-41cd-4a51-8820-0d8431190b13",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_172.txt",
        "created": 1737369198,
        "question": "Could you advise me on the appropriate time to arrive in the city? Is there a recommended date for students to be present before the semester begins?",
        "answer": "There is no exact recommended time you should be arriving in Munich physically. However, I would highly recommend you take care of accommodation as soon as possible. You can either familiarize yourself with the dorms of the Studentenwerk (main dorms for all universities in Munich) or look independently for e.g. shared flats on other websites, such as wg-gesucht. It is not so easy to find an accommodation \u2013 the sooner you take care of it, the better.",
        "request_id": "283bb41dfa9c6f4d0e6368f5bf031f64"
    },
    {
        "id": "af60ea6e-cc7b-4b28-b714-4c9e9c17ae81",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_172.txt",
        "created": 1737369198,
        "question": "When are the classes scheduled to start, and is there a specific timetable available that I can review?",
        "answer": "Classes at TUM will officially start on October 14th. Regarding a specific timetable for the first semester, please check back soon on our website.",
        "request_id": "283bb41dfa9c6f4d0e6368f5bf031f64"
    },
    {
        "id": "570b7568-f760-4e36-bb62-34b6736d6e91",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_173.txt",
        "created": 1737369209,
        "question": "Can the M.Sc AI in Society department issue a letter confirming that an applicant has enough English skills to enroll for the master program?",
        "answer": "The department cannot issue a verification of English language proficiency if the applicant has not studied with them.",
        "request_id": "c3f7bc81f9d51c7887aef51f6f7d95ec"
    },
    {
        "id": "e3594657-5307-408f-bd10-c9ea2158a215",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_173.txt",
        "created": 1737369209,
        "question": "What is the requirement for English language proficiency for the Master's program?",
        "answer": "The proficiency requirement for the Master's program is 6.5 bands (B2 CEFR).",
        "request_id": "c3f7bc81f9d51c7887aef51f6f7d95ec"
    },
    {
        "id": "a6a79216-f643-4f25-97d9-ecd0d7dd98c7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_174.txt",
        "created": 1737369214,
        "question": "Can the university provide a letter verifying my English language proficiency for my visa application?",
        "answer": "The department you received your degree from should issue you a verification of English language proficiency. The university cannot provide this verification if you have not studied with them.",
        "request_id": "d2ed75e6949df65b6e2ac71a47f4f7f0"
    },
    {
        "id": "9062981b-bd5f-4f43-9ddc-c8d9619120aa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_175.txt",
        "created": 1737369217,
        "question": "Can the selection committee reconsider my application after it has been rejected?",
        "answer": "No, the selection committee cannot re-evaluate people again after they have already gone through the interview and were rejected.",
        "request_id": "0ce6c81ab23e929d208e7d3e37ecb18d"
    },
    {
        "id": "68f3ebde-e773-483a-907d-ea3cc54fcc3c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_175.txt",
        "created": 1737369217,
        "question": "Can I request a new interview after my application has been rejected?",
        "answer": "No, a new interview cannot be offered once the decision has already been made.",
        "request_id": "0ce6c81ab23e929d208e7d3e37ecb18d"
    },
    {
        "id": "1676b821-a7af-451c-a991-00c55986b64a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_176.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "Can an applicant rescind their application withdrawal for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes, an applicant can rescind their application withdrawal. In this case, the applicant was invited to participate in the third and last aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "763efb92a7a88b5594072d64ef785220"
    },
    {
        "id": "fb71eca2-d673-4ae5-a0e2-6f2f94942c4f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_176.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "What is the process for admission to the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "Admission to the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society at TUM is conditioned on the successful completion of an aptitude assessment. Approved applicants are invited to take an aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "763efb92a7a88b5594072d64ef785220"
    },
    {
        "id": "810ee914-157f-4165-bafa-d8dd11cdaf92",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_176.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society at TUM is primarily held online, with an option to take it in person at TUM, Munich city center. The test is conducted in English and spans 90 minutes. It consists of multiple-choice questions on topics including Politics, Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, and Engineering. During the test, applicants are allowed to use a calculator.",
        "request_id": "763efb92a7a88b5594072d64ef785220"
    },
    {
        "id": "740928e9-0761-4064-9cbd-9b9a64a671ff",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_176.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "What are the requirements for taking the aptitude test online for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "If an applicant chooses to take the aptitude test online, they will be monitored via an automated proctoring software. Participation using the proctoring program will demand a fee of 25$. If an applicant does not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure, the only other option is to take the test in person.",
        "request_id": "763efb92a7a88b5594072d64ef785220"
    },
    {
        "id": "210068d1-b661-4e1c-b9c1-1c03371786ba",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_178.txt",
        "created": 1737369238,
        "question": "What should I do about the requirement to submit an original APS certificate for my enrollment in the AI in Society course, given that I have a diploma from a Russian secondary school in Vietnam?",
        "answer": "The APS requirement will be deleted from your required documents as soon as the degree certificates from UK are received.",
        "request_id": "4db3b0ef1f1d379f5217c699a3001b37"
    },
    {
        "id": "cb6694e9-667a-4d11-861e-2f57a95fe5e5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_178.txt",
        "created": 1737369238,
        "question": "I have been living in Germany for more than 5 years and according to TUM terms & conditions, I should not pay the \u20ac4000 tuition fee for foreign countries. However, my fee status indicates that I have to pay this amount. How should I proceed?",
        "answer": "For issues regarding study fees, please reach out to the office for fees and scholarships at the provided email address.",
        "request_id": "4db3b0ef1f1d379f5217c699a3001b37"
    },
    {
        "id": "7f2c3d37-c030-4a8e-8ec4-89986071e972",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_179.txt",
        "created": 1737369245,
        "question": "Can I defer my start date to the next summer semester due to visa processing delays?",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, you cannot officially start in a summer semester. You could only defer it to next winter semester.",
        "request_id": "2146691dd9b7bc5a0b687c261c1c309b"
    },
    {
        "id": "ff10e0a7-f652-4b45-a619-9b15279f9264",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_179.txt",
        "created": 1737369245,
        "question": "Can I participate in the courses online if I am not able to be in Munich physically in time?",
        "answer": "Yes, for the time being (while you are not yet in Munich), you can participate in the courses online. They will all be streamed in parallel for people who could not make it here physically in time.",
        "request_id": "2146691dd9b7bc5a0b687c261c1c309b"
    },
    {
        "id": "d0ab334e-9707-4a57-aa8b-958d39721884",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_181.txt",
        "created": 1737369252,
        "question": "Where can Ukrainian students who have fled Ukraine due to the war apply for a waiver for the master's degree program 'AI in Society'?",
        "answer": "For this, please reach out to the contact given at the bottom of this page: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/fees-and-financial-aid/scholarships/tum-scholarships/scholarship/urgent-fonds-students-ukraine-war",
        "request_id": "da23a573d902a043990f36b6c2092b8b"
    },
    {
        "id": "07d21d55-b9f1-4b3d-951d-d32ef44b8344",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_182.txt",
        "created": 1737369256,
        "question": "Where will the classes for the AI in Society program at TUM be held?",
        "answer": "The classes will be held in the center of the city, mainly. The buildings will be: Richard-Wagner-Str. 1, Marsstr. 20-22, and Arcisstr. 21.",
        "request_id": "9a1464c849173ac859599e323b2206ee"
    },
    {
        "id": "59df56d1-5907-42e4-bfac-2b3801eceef5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_182.txt",
        "created": 1737369256,
        "question": "Will I need to attend lectures on different campuses for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes, the lectures will be held in different buildings in the city center.",
        "request_id": "9a1464c849173ac859599e323b2206ee"
    },
    {
        "id": "6435ef6a-ff27-4fd4-8f88-fa9bfb5d9c9e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_182.txt",
        "created": 1737369256,
        "question": "Are there any specific networking options, groups, or events organised for students of the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "There is currently no specific networking events for the AI in Society program. However, students will have plenty of opportunities to connect with their classmates as they will have the same study plan and attend the same courses.",
        "request_id": "9a1464c849173ac859599e323b2206ee"
    },
    {
        "id": "9803ff65-45a0-4c50-8de7-0944d0e08a90",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_183.txt",
        "created": 1737369264,
        "question": "Is it possible to get the curriculum for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The exact times and locations of the modules and their descriptions are currently still in planning, since the semester starts only in around 2 months. A plan for the first semester will be uploaded on the website soon.",
        "request_id": "662eca9ab2b7a39e1d1dbdb06db4edfe"
    },
    {
        "id": "9f47c2ad-a17e-463c-a189-007d701724cd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_184.txt",
        "created": 1737369267,
        "question": "When will the exact schedules for the lectures and other mandatory events for the \u201cAI in Society\u201d program be available?",
        "answer": "The exact schedules are not yet available as the lecture planning is not yet complete. A timetable for the first semester will be posted on the website in due course.",
        "request_id": "18b684e33d62bbb120dfc57c2f1f7e58"
    },
    {
        "id": "738f7d26-3a20-4c25-98bd-f94f9353ab94",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_184.txt",
        "created": 1737369267,
        "question": "Why can't I find any of the modules for the first semester of the \u201cAI in Society\u201d program in the LV-Portal?",
        "answer": "The lecture planning for the semester is not yet complete, which is why the modules are not yet available in the LV-Portal.",
        "request_id": "18b684e33d62bbb120dfc57c2f1f7e58"
    },
    {
        "id": "8a651202-495e-4187-af1b-cc6a11de51be",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_184.txt",
        "created": 1737369267,
        "question": "Can you provide me with information regarding the exact lecture times (and possibly locations) for the \u201cAI in Society\u201d program?",
        "answer": "The exact lecture times and locations are not yet available. They will be posted on the website in due course.",
        "request_id": "18b684e33d62bbb120dfc57c2f1f7e58"
    },
    {
        "id": "7748f054-b6e4-4e1b-8c31-2729cc7378bd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_185.txt",
        "created": 1737369274,
        "question": "I don't seem to have received a link to the test, can you send me a link?",
        "answer": "Please upload the correct document if you have it. We are offering another test right at the beginning of September, to which we will of course invite you, should all documents be okay.",
        "request_id": "1ec0e0fbd93cd0e6a51606f8792df7d1"
    },
    {
        "id": "0d17e0e7-8448-4f00-aaba-14dbcda8092a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_185.txt",
        "created": 1737369274,
        "question": "I reviewed my application on the portal and saw an issue with the passport upload. I have a new passport and can upload it to you if needed. Can we resolve this issue?",
        "answer": "Please upload the correct document if you have it. We are offering another test right at the beginning of September, to which we will of course invite you, should all documents be okay.",
        "request_id": "1ec0e0fbd93cd0e6a51606f8792df7d1"
    },
    {
        "id": "0d4a691f-3b96-4d56-a9e0-384b6f12e2e4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_186.txt",
        "created": 1737369284,
        "question": "Is it possible to start the program in the summer semester and catch up on the winter semester content individually?",
        "answer": "No, you can officially only start the program in a winter semester. A start in the summer semester is not planned.",
        "request_id": "c866750f247fccef0f649348e7752fbe"
    },
    {
        "id": "26df4dde-3a85-4f95-bd2f-6d4d5dc7178f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_186.txt",
        "created": 1737369284,
        "question": "Can the acceptance be postponed for a year to the winter semester 2024/2025?",
        "answer": "Yes, your acceptance will still apply for the next year. However, you will have to reapply and upload all documents again (especially an up-to-date CV). With the already pronounced admission, you will be admitted directly. You do not have to go through the aptitude procedure again.",
        "request_id": "c866750f247fccef0f649348e7752fbe"
    },
    {
        "id": "0e3efe16-51d0-4aca-8519-28e356bf9656",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_186.txt",
        "created": 1737369284,
        "question": "If the acceptance can be postponed, can I still participate in lectures/practical work etc. in the meantime from January and possibly contribute my experiences (possibly as a 'guest') - and then officially start in the winter semester 2024/2025?",
        "answer": "You would have to be properly enrolled to participate in events and receive ECTS for it. So, this would not be possible.",
        "request_id": "c866750f247fccef0f649348e7752fbe"
    },
    {
        "id": "b0370909-865a-4720-9960-0caf6ff1ec0b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_186.txt",
        "created": 1737369284,
        "question": "How should I respond to the current invitation for the winter semester 24? Should I formally decline this online and then reapply next year as you described, or should I just leave it open?",
        "answer": "You can simply decline the admission online without giving a reason.",
        "request_id": "c866750f247fccef0f649348e7752fbe"
    },
    {
        "id": "6fc1cabe-31db-4999-84ac-8e2d57759701",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_187.txt",
        "created": 1737369294,
        "question": "Is there a possibility to get more detailed information about the lecture plan and possible elective modules for the AI in Society WS 24/25 program?",
        "answer": "The team is currently working on posting a timetable for the first semester on their website, where you will also be able to view the module descriptions.",
        "request_id": "21d6a62a867f3b6bee2fb606f931110b"
    },
    {
        "id": "36d5569b-a7df-4d13-89f3-aa1d5cbed0b6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_187.txt",
        "created": 1737369294,
        "question": "When would a consultation be possible?",
        "answer": "A consultation is currently not possible as the respondent will not be available throughout August. It is suggested to send specific questions and concerns via email.",
        "request_id": "21d6a62a867f3b6bee2fb606f931110b"
    },
    {
        "id": "9c140429-af97-4b12-a35f-40714c26fc7a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_188.txt",
        "created": 1737369300,
        "question": "Is it possible to move the aptitude test for the MSc in AI in Society to August?",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, the test cannot be moved to August as most people will be on vacation. The test is planned for the 2nd or 3rd of September.",
        "request_id": "f74311fcccad780de351de84297ac58e"
    },
    {
        "id": "7b0717cb-2dca-421d-87dd-17eda245e57d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_188.txt",
        "created": 1737369300,
        "question": "When is the third aptitude test for the MSc in AI in Society planned?",
        "answer": "The third aptitude test is currently being planned for September, but an exact date is not yet available.",
        "request_id": "f74311fcccad780de351de84297ac58e"
    },
    {
        "id": "fc33a319-04c9-412b-b13c-4f389b1b24a1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_188.txt",
        "created": 1737369300,
        "question": "What is the status of my application for the MSc in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "Your application seems to be all good now. You will be invited to the third aptitude test, which is currently being planned for September.",
        "request_id": "f74311fcccad780de351de84297ac58e"
    },
    {
        "id": "21bdcd9e-965d-440b-aabe-009e61b85c79",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_190.txt",
        "created": 1737369308,
        "question": "Is it possible to start the 'AI in Society' program in the summer semester and catch up with the winter semester content individually?",
        "answer": "No, you can officially only start the program in a winter semester. Starting in the summer semester is not planned.",
        "request_id": "02eb621feeddee6bbcd4020f47799b11"
    },
    {
        "id": "3c23e3bc-b1a0-436c-abbe-f4173256476b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_190.txt",
        "created": 1737369308,
        "question": "If starting in the summer semester is not possible, can the admission be deferred for a year to the winter semester 2024/2025?",
        "answer": "Yes, your admission will still be valid for the next year. However, you will have to reapply and upload all documents again, especially an up-to-date CV. With the already granted admission, you will be directly admitted. You do not have to go through the aptitude assessment again.",
        "request_id": "02eb621feeddee6bbcd4020f47799b11"
    },
    {
        "id": "49f8555c-e34e-4af6-a101-38c8af532006",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_190.txt",
        "created": 1737369308,
        "question": "If the admission can be deferred, can I still participate in lectures/practical work etc. in the meantime from January and possibly contribute my experiences (possibly as a 'guest') - and then officially start in the winter semester 2024/2025?",
        "answer": "You would have to be properly enrolled to participate in events and receive ECTS for them. So, this would not be possible.",
        "request_id": "02eb621feeddee6bbcd4020f47799b11"
    },
    {
        "id": "80230fac-cc0d-4e8b-b585-b7ec7f2bf2aa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_191.txt",
        "created": 1737369320,
        "question": "Is there already a module handbook for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The module descriptions are currently being taken care of, so they will be available on the website soon.",
        "request_id": "2f75722b584ffc9cf48c0c111bf474ee"
    },
    {
        "id": "35c95609-0454-4df7-90b2-4a0510fec7a5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_195.txt",
        "created": 1737369333,
        "question": "Where should documents for enrollment be sent?",
        "answer": "Documents for enrollment should be sent to the Enrollment Office, not to me.",
        "request_id": "1adfc46bf46e625026b87b132200e280"
    },
    {
        "id": "70f707b0-a321-4dbe-a49a-7662ea737c47",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_201.txt",
        "created": 1737369055,
        "question": "Can you please tell me at which campus the lectures for AI in Society will take place?",
        "answer": "The lectures for AI in Society take place at various locations in the city center. The exact locations for each lecture are not yet precisely determined, but you can prepare for these buildings.",
        "request_id": "3802aac7c98c6056e26a9e3b796b1bdd"
    },
    {
        "id": "0235faed-af8e-4ad9-8c5e-2e5c69c5289c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_206.txt",
        "created": 1737369063,
        "question": "When is the third aptitude test for the MSc in AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The third aptitude test is currently being planned for September, but an exact date has not been provided.",
        "request_id": "7571bba3ff932ba7f2a17effa02c9302"
    },
    {
        "id": "40e98fda-70c5-455d-acad-39a1b4546812",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_206.txt",
        "created": 1737369063,
        "question": "What is the status of my application for the MSc in AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Your application seems to be all good now and you will be invited to the third aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "7571bba3ff932ba7f2a17effa02c9302"
    },
    {
        "id": "bc409191-24d5-455a-a877-e1d7e3f37f74",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_207.txt",
        "created": 1737369072,
        "question": "Due to reduced visa slot availability, how much extension can TUM give me to join the winter semester?",
        "answer": "There is no official date/extension when you need to be here. The courses of the first semester will be streamed online, allowing you to participate while you\u2019re not yet in Munich.",
        "request_id": "fe2903d38074e48e7b7a9799fa63590b"
    },
    {
        "id": "e2647e2e-70f5-421e-81a8-231f73eb074c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_207.txt",
        "created": 1737369072,
        "question": "Will the one-week block course on programming before the semester starts be streamed online?",
        "answer": "It is not yet known if the one-week block course on programming will be streamed online. However, the possibility of making all first-semester courses streamable online will be explored.",
        "request_id": "fe2903d38074e48e7b7a9799fa63590b"
    },
    {
        "id": "2cb53577-3780-48e1-bdd4-655b95596677",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_208.txt",
        "created": 1737369078,
        "question": "What is the Zoom link for the AI in [REDACTED] on July 26th, 10:00 \u2013 10:30 AM CEST?",
        "answer": "[MANUALLY REDACTED]",
        "request_id": "5823dd77cbe4e6591122f37800c58be7"
    },
    {
        "id": "43e4a557-a9c8-4888-9c4c-bba524e06c3c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_209.txt",
        "created": 1737369082,
        "question": "What is the Zoom link for the AI in [REDACTED] on July 26th, 10:00 \u2013 10:30 AM CEST?",
        "answer": "[MANUALLY REDACTED]",
        "request_id": "7042108e60cd3705abf5607327269db9"
    },
    {
        "id": "40179d0e-7aec-4c54-8aa8-107cbc9d65e0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_230.txt",
        "created": 1737369112,
        "question": "Can the interview time slot be changed?",
        "answer": "Yes, the interview time slot can be changed. This can be done by the individual themselves through an email received from kulibri.",
        "request_id": "abd45ed4345309ce032b38be235d33a5"
    },
    {
        "id": "472d0cb4-be2b-47d8-aa79-bfb58fc8a20e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_230.txt",
        "created": 1737369112,
        "question": "What are the available dates for rescheduling the interview?",
        "answer": "There is only one last slot left for rescheduling the interview, which is on the 30th.",
        "request_id": "abd45ed4345309ce032b38be235d33a5"
    },
    {
        "id": "932e9e04-9f2f-4da1-ae9b-413686858bfd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_230.txt",
        "created": 1737369112,
        "question": "What is the current selected slot for the interview?",
        "answer": "The current selected slot for the interview is on the 25th.",
        "request_id": "abd45ed4345309ce032b38be235d33a5"
    },
    {
        "id": "4ff08c22-d92e-4c46-bd34-a3bc29e63ab3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_231.txt",
        "created": 1737369117,
        "question": "Why didn't I receive an invitation to the aptitude test on the 16th of July?",
        "answer": "You did not receive an invitation since your documents were still formally incomplete in the system.",
        "request_id": "6233b065dd2df6c36792b3b84e8e6284"
    },
    {
        "id": "9f9ada41-7c1a-4982-9598-11243afb0d77",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_231.txt",
        "created": 1737369117,
        "question": "Can I upload a new document to my application?",
        "answer": "Yes, you are able to upload the new document to your application.",
        "request_id": "6233b065dd2df6c36792b3b84e8e6284"
    },
    {
        "id": "cb156482-7e0b-4b7b-aa89-84708425f66d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_231.txt",
        "created": 1737369117,
        "question": "Will I receive an invitation to the third test if my application is correct?",
        "answer": "If your application is correct, you will receive an invitation to the third test which is currently planned for September.",
        "request_id": "6233b065dd2df6c36792b3b84e8e6284"
    },
    {
        "id": "e23df954-fb28-4254-8860-d17fa7a96bf7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_232.txt",
        "created": 1737369125,
        "question": "What was my exact result on the aptitude exam?",
        "answer": "You have reached 22 points in the aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "079899056513fa16df80ce698de84204"
    },
    {
        "id": "079116eb-bee7-4b70-a2bf-30b396f9d132",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_232.txt",
        "created": 1737369125,
        "question": "Does that mean I got 3 points from my subjects and credits?",
        "answer": "Exactly, this in total lands you at 25 points.",
        "request_id": "079899056513fa16df80ce698de84204"
    },
    {
        "id": "12bf2f92-702e-4809-a10b-43d0882e7db2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_232.txt",
        "created": 1737369125,
        "question": "Was my total score of 25 points enough to pass to the interview stage?",
        "answer": "No, 25 points was unfortunately not enough to pass to the interview stage.",
        "request_id": "079899056513fa16df80ce698de84204"
    },
    {
        "id": "daaed285-916e-4d2e-a412-ee3222f5bd62",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_233.txt",
        "created": 1737369130,
        "question": "Is it possible to check whether the Master 'AI in Society' meets the requirements for Baf\u00f6g?",
        "answer": "The university will automatically register the program for Baf\u00f6g at some point, but it seems this has not happened yet.",
        "request_id": "657f073bf43ca1e92288ee79a679aae7"
    },
    {
        "id": "77f31b44-ea09-451e-8745-1a653350cd74",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_234.txt",
        "created": 1737369136,
        "question": "How can I find out my exact result on the aptitude exam?",
        "answer": "You have reached 22 points in the aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "690f9e33201e55af40b7baa5ee468d9b"
    },
    {
        "id": "52203df1-ed45-44b2-aa1a-3829346233aa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_245.txt",
        "created": 1737369158,
        "question": "Can I reject the offer now and then apply again next year with a guaranteed seat?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can reject the offer now and instead accept the study place next year. We will still have it in the system that you had passed all requirements and will be admitted.",
        "request_id": "1032527f5cf2cdb6ff9419b7149c7200"
    },
    {
        "id": "1e17f786-ccec-4dce-acc0-c66481430306",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_247.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "Could you please confirm if the booked meeting is at 11:30 AM Munich time to avoid any misunderstanding?",
        "answer": "Yes, the slot you selected is 11:30 \u2013 12:00 AM Munich time.",
        "request_id": "3efd04c13a4f85a7d506accfeb3f8044"
    },
    {
        "id": "3da0b917-c8c7-4873-aacf-2880dbbc272a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_247.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "Could you let me know my final score for Level 1 of this process?",
        "answer": "You received 12 points for your previous grades, and 31 points in the test. In total, you landed at 43 points.",
        "request_id": "3efd04c13a4f85a7d506accfeb3f8044"
    },
    {
        "id": "09b590aa-a9c2-42a9-a34b-134e800d47b0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_248.txt",
        "created": 1737369169,
        "question": "What is the second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second stage of the aptitude assessment is an interview. During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss the applicant's motivation for choosing this degree program, willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, professional interests, any previous specializations, and professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and the applicant's career aspirations.",
        "request_id": "e296d91ec2fe2402b02b9a3208acf6de"
    },
    {
        "id": "1ed27b52-12c9-4978-8917-c078eba39a5a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_248.txt",
        "created": 1737369169,
        "question": "What is the focus of the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The focus of the aptitude interview is on understanding the applicant's motivation for the study program, not testing their knowledge on specific subjects.",
        "request_id": "e296d91ec2fe2402b02b9a3208acf6de"
    },
    {
        "id": "2dbbee5d-3546-4f29-ae1a-f4c02a59b6db",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_248.txt",
        "created": 1737369169,
        "question": "When and how will the aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place from July 22nd to July 30th and will be conducted online over Zoom.",
        "request_id": "e296d91ec2fe2402b02b9a3208acf6de"
    },
    {
        "id": "7b09a22a-a020-45dd-a4fd-1b21428027ed",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_248.txt",
        "created": 1737369169,
        "question": "How can I select a timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "To select a timeslot, you need to use the provided link, enter your email address and full name, and then choose one timeslot that works best for you. Each timeslot can only be selected by one person, therefore the distribution of slots works by the principle \u201cfirst come, first serve\u201d. After selecting, you need to submit your answer.",
        "request_id": "e296d91ec2fe2402b02b9a3208acf6de"
    },
    {
        "id": "7d46dc97-35c6-432c-b725-8eb31d1bcdd4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_248.txt",
        "created": 1737369169,
        "question": "What should I do if I need to change my selected timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "If you want to change your selection later, you will be able to do so yourself. However, you should let the team know in case you had to change your slot, especially if it's last minute.",
        "request_id": "e296d91ec2fe2402b02b9a3208acf6de"
    },
    {
        "id": "1bc94296-fcd3-4408-89f0-e2c98ebdf815",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_249.txt",
        "created": 1737369186,
        "question": "What is the second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM is an interview.",
        "request_id": "0686c48671aa63b33eb720092e38446e"
    },
    {
        "id": "12a10cb9-c89a-445d-b43c-34c2a9084eb1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_249.txt",
        "created": 1737369186,
        "question": "What will be discussed during the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program, your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations.",
        "request_id": "0686c48671aa63b33eb720092e38446e"
    },
    {
        "id": "0d5d0ecc-d4f5-4113-bb37-3a23c10e9be6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_249.txt",
        "created": 1737369186,
        "question": "When will the aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place from July 22nd to July 30th.",
        "request_id": "0686c48671aa63b33eb720092e38446e"
    },
    {
        "id": "d9bd2ab9-9a13-475f-a6ff-6b68d962b5a5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_249.txt",
        "created": 1737369186,
        "question": "How can I select a timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "You can select a timeslot for the aptitude interview by using the provided link, entering your email address and full name, and choosing one timeslot that works best for you.",
        "request_id": "0686c48671aa63b33eb720092e38446e"
    },
    {
        "id": "e83d8232-de05-4c2b-aac5-09e54be6b1bb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_249.txt",
        "created": 1737369186,
        "question": "When will I receive the Zoom link for my aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "You will receive your personal Zoom link at least 12 hours in advance to your interview.",
        "request_id": "0686c48671aa63b33eb720092e38446e"
    },
    {
        "id": "c97355d8-1be9-421d-81d7-0f79124dc810",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_250.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "Can you tell me whether I can still apply for any scholarship program to finance my studies?",
        "answer": "For questions regarding scholarships, please contact TUM\u2019s scholarship office directly: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/fees-and-financial-aid/scholarships",
        "request_id": "e67e454c77d61fe2138ad80c2241f561"
    },
    {
        "id": "c0cfb8bb-6314-4454-94b5-14b3200ee5a4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_251.txt",
        "created": 1737369062,
        "question": "What is the score that decides between admission, interview, and rejection for the MSc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The score that decides between admission, interview, and rejection is the one that is entered in the system. It is comprised of 1) the scores you receive from your previous grades, and 2) the score you got in the aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "1a5b276281bb0a6ec8406bba9f7f1b18"
    },
    {
        "id": "53e23dd6-fdd3-4ac2-a226-36d9ffe97eed",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_251.txt",
        "created": 1737369062,
        "question": "Can I get a detailed review of how many points I scored on each question in the aptitude test for the MSc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, detailed reviews of how many points you scored on each question cannot be provided, as this could lead to the test questions being leaked.",
        "request_id": "1a5b276281bb0a6ec8406bba9f7f1b18"
    },
    {
        "id": "7d5c3964-979f-40ba-89a2-ca0f564576a7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_251.txt",
        "created": 1737369062,
        "question": "Are my answers saved if I get logged out in the middle of the aptitude test for the MSc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Yes, your submitted answers get saved regardless of you getting logged out in the middle of the test.",
        "request_id": "1a5b276281bb0a6ec8406bba9f7f1b18"
    },
    {
        "id": "1abfd6e0-856e-451c-9aac-87860d9658b1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_251.txt",
        "created": 1737369062,
        "question": "How is the score for the MSc. AI in Society program calculated?",
        "answer": "The score is comprised of the scores you receive from your previous grades, transformed into the German system, and the score you got in the aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "1a5b276281bb0a6ec8406bba9f7f1b18"
    },
    {
        "id": "1ac99239-46d9-47f2-93f6-cc7890c48cdf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_251.txt",
        "created": 1737369062,
        "question": "What happens if I encounter a technical error during the aptitude test for the MSc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "In case of a technical error, you will be added to the moodle exam and sent a link to participate on another date. If anything goes wrong, there will be a third test date, to which you will be invited.",
        "request_id": "1a5b276281bb0a6ec8406bba9f7f1b18"
    },
    {
        "id": "a7e2f0c6-e3ee-4c08-b952-792cd0ca759e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_252.txt",
        "created": 1737369075,
        "question": "At which TUM location do the events for the M.Sc. AI in Society program take place, or do they take place at several locations?",
        "answer": "The events are somewhat distributed throughout the city center. They will mainly take place in the following buildings: Richard-Wagner-Str. 1, Marsstr. 20-22, Arcisstr. 21 (possibly).",
        "request_id": "7a8f7f86b24e402b43f6e98feaaf9564"
    },
    {
        "id": "de9ffa81-cfcc-4a31-9433-f815505ad629",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_253.txt",
        "created": 1737369081,
        "question": "Do you have any relevant data on actual graduate outcomes of the MSc AI in Society program, such as hiring firms, average/median starting salary, and countries graduates are hired in?",
        "answer": "Since the coming semester is the very first semester we are offering this program, we do not have data on graduate outcomes yet.",
        "request_id": "add7eadb800bf6e2ca38460314c2291c"
    },
    {
        "id": "24322cd2-7cf3-4289-a3bb-700937c12d6d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_254.txt",
        "created": 1737369085,
        "question": "What are the usual office hours of the \u201cAI in Society\u201d master?",
        "answer": "The coordinator does not have specific office hours, but is available for visits if notified in advance.",
        "request_id": "52ed576f7284442283d82cde750512cc"
    },
    {
        "id": "268c7744-aba3-445b-be58-95d61fc94582",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_254.txt",
        "created": 1737369085,
        "question": "What are the nearest libraries that the TUM offers for their students and the program 'AI in Society'?",
        "answer": "The University library has different topic branches, please see here: https://www.ub.tum.de/en/accessibility",
        "request_id": "52ed576f7284442283d82cde750512cc"
    },
    {
        "id": "e701005c-a9ce-4f07-b47a-3059074b9a4c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_254.txt",
        "created": 1737369085,
        "question": "If I would like to drop the immatriculation documents in person, where and how should this happen?",
        "answer": "You can drop off your documents in person at the student center service desk.",
        "request_id": "52ed576f7284442283d82cde750512cc"
    },
    {
        "id": "24b7867d-e21f-477a-a65e-a2ba63e56c72",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_254.txt",
        "created": 1737369085,
        "question": "When is the deadline to accept the admission offer and enroll to the AI in Society master program?",
        "answer": "You can accept the study place until September 30th.",
        "request_id": "52ed576f7284442283d82cde750512cc"
    },
    {
        "id": "386b30cc-15e2-46db-8094-f73ea1c0d796",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_254.txt",
        "created": 1737369085,
        "question": "Where are the AI in Society lectures taking place?",
        "answer": "The lectures are planned to be organized in the city center, either at Richard-Wagner-Str. 1, Marsstr. 20-22, or Arcisstr. 21. Some courses from other departments might be offered in Garching, but the majority will take place in the city center.",
        "request_id": "52ed576f7284442283d82cde750512cc"
    },
    {
        "id": "2fd898ef-be97-41b2-bcfe-932f259d0cd1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_255.txt",
        "created": 1737369096,
        "question": "What happens if I can't access the assessment due to inability to make foreign currency transactions with Egyptian cards?",
        "answer": "You are invited to the third test date that is currently being planned. If you still can't find a solution by then, you should reach out for another solution to be found.",
        "request_id": "66e72443163ec17e4d4a3f0e3b96aa99"
    },
    {
        "id": "94f46c06-ad63-4e0c-8697-578fa2f0aef6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_255.txt",
        "created": 1737369096,
        "question": "What should I do if my local bank card doesn't work for the assessment?",
        "answer": "You should try using an internationally valid credit card. If that fails, you should come into the zoom support room right before the exam begins for a solution to be found.",
        "request_id": "66e72443163ec17e4d4a3f0e3b96aa99"
    },
    {
        "id": "122d8800-fe0b-47e1-a4f2-85678a10bc29",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_255.txt",
        "created": 1737369096,
        "question": "What are the requirements for the off-campus (online) variant of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The off-campus (online) variant will require you to pay a fee of 25$ for the proctoring software Proctorio. This will require a working webcam and microphone.",
        "request_id": "66e72443163ec17e4d4a3f0e3b96aa99"
    },
    {
        "id": "85d91a0b-4fa9-492a-baa5-ebecfb65fdec",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_255.txt",
        "created": 1737369096,
        "question": "What are the requirements for the on-campus variant of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The on-campus variant will not require any fee, as you will be monitored by staff in person. It will take place in Marsstr. 20-22, 80335 Munich, room 605, 6th floor. You will need to bring your laptop to take the test. If you can't bring a laptop, you should let the staff know in advance and a laptop will be provided for you.",
        "request_id": "66e72443163ec17e4d4a3f0e3b96aa99"
    },
    {
        "id": "158565dd-074d-4df7-a8b3-4f92c8abe757",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_255.txt",
        "created": 1737369096,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The test will consist of 35 multiple choice questions spanned over 90 minutes, and will be held over TUM's internal moodle platform. You will be allowed to use a calculator, as well as a piece of paper and pen to help you.",
        "request_id": "66e72443163ec17e4d4a3f0e3b96aa99"
    },
    {
        "id": "691c81c5-9502-4bc2-ada7-f99b340efd30",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_256.txt",
        "created": 1737369109,
        "question": "Why haven't I received a link to the AI in Society program aptitude test?",
        "answer": "Your application was marked as insufficient regarding one of your documents, which is why you have not been invited.",
        "request_id": "adad1871cc8ff5baed140e5fc05cf506"
    },
    {
        "id": "7fe4677d-7159-41b2-8050-804dfa82f86a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_256.txt",
        "created": 1737369109,
        "question": "Can I apply with an expired passport?",
        "answer": "Yes, you were allowed to apply with an expired passport due to some circumstances that prohibited you from renewing it.",
        "request_id": "adad1871cc8ff5baed140e5fc05cf506"
    },
    {
        "id": "b8ec6f8c-1f98-4138-ba4f-2232022feac6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_256.txt",
        "created": 1737369109,
        "question": "What will happen since I missed the aptitude test for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "You will be invited to the third test date that is currently being planned.",
        "request_id": "adad1871cc8ff5baed140e5fc05cf506"
    },
    {
        "id": "a1e99ef8-7d92-47e4-946d-fa4f8fbb739c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_257.txt",
        "created": 1737369115,
        "question": "Why haven't I received a link to the AI in Society program aptitude test?",
        "answer": "Your application has been marked as insufficient regarding one of your documents, which is why you have not been invited. Please check the comment regarding your application.",
        "request_id": "77df0d561eadf418960c15827aedde86"
    },
    {
        "id": "c0aa6fb1-3d64-4ee2-b69d-69d63596fd9c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_258.txt",
        "created": 1737369118,
        "question": "What should I do if I can't make any foreign currency transactions with my card to access the assessment?",
        "answer": "Try it with an internationally valid credit card. Local bank cards will not work. If everything fails, come into the zoom support room right before the exam begins, and a solution will be found.",
        "request_id": "93a3450cc517e04e831d0a86e054098b"
    },
    {
        "id": "d2d8dd75-48fb-457a-a167-9c05f2776e44",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_258.txt",
        "created": 1737369118,
        "question": "What are the requirements for the off-campus (online) variant of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The off-campus (online) variant will require you to pay a fee of 25$ for the proctoring software Proctorio. This will require a working webcam and microphone.",
        "request_id": "93a3450cc517e04e831d0a86e054098b"
    },
    {
        "id": "bdfad508-67ce-462c-abd6-41ee4de39289",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_258.txt",
        "created": 1737369118,
        "question": "What are the requirements for the on-campus variant of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The on-campus variant will not require any fee, as you will be monitored by staff in person. It will take place in Marsstr. 20-22, 80335 Munich, room 605, 6th floor. You will need to bring your laptop to take the test in the on-campus variant, as the test will not be written on paper. If you are unable to bring a laptop for the test, let the staff know in advance and a laptop will be provided for you.",
        "request_id": "93a3450cc517e04e831d0a86e054098b"
    },
    {
        "id": "87270221-c9e1-4885-b548-f8c295747e1f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_258.txt",
        "created": 1737369118,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The test will consist of 35 multiple choice questions spanned over 90 minutes, and will be held over TUM's internal moodle platform. You will be allowed to use a calculator, as well as a piece of paper and pen to help you.",
        "request_id": "93a3450cc517e04e831d0a86e054098b"
    },
    {
        "id": "e49c9a4b-5cae-4e64-89ee-3a6d13483675",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_258.txt",
        "created": 1737369118,
        "question": "What should I do after receiving the link to the moodle test?",
        "answer": "After receiving the link to the moodle test, you should 1) choose your preferred exam modality (on-/off-campus) and 2) take the demo test to make yourself familiar with the test environment. If you choose the off-campus version, you will also be guided through the Proctorio installation and payment there.",
        "request_id": "93a3450cc517e04e831d0a86e054098b"
    },
    {
        "id": "ad588ed8-df67-4b07-97d0-7f641e63d131",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_259.txt",
        "created": 1737369135,
        "question": "If I use a blank paper on my desk and do not look at the camera constantly, will that be counted as an attempt to cheat?",
        "answer": "Looking at your desk at your paper will not be counted as cheating.",
        "request_id": "865bb2d6779e1183375c8618f20b7e5a"
    },
    {
        "id": "b2008e22-c729-4585-972f-b09d388590b3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_259.txt",
        "created": 1737369135,
        "question": "If there are some technical issues during the test tomorrow, is there a contact person or an email which I can use for help?",
        "answer": "If there are any technical problems, there is a zoom call hotline as well as a phone number given on the moodle exam page.",
        "request_id": "865bb2d6779e1183375c8618f20b7e5a"
    },
    {
        "id": "138798f4-dae4-487f-8973-1b5741f64b2a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_260.txt",
        "created": 1737369140,
        "question": "What is the date and time of the aptitude test for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The aptitude test will take place on July 16th, 2024, from 10:45 to 12:15 CEST.",
        "request_id": "db34966ed01526b7f25073f01015e237"
    },
    {
        "id": "4bcfe5fb-5b51-48b0-b257-f45d11b8e438",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_260.txt",
        "created": 1737369140,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The test will consist of 35 multiple choice questions spanned over 90 minutes, and will be held over TUM's internal moodle platform.",
        "request_id": "db34966ed01526b7f25073f01015e237"
    },
    {
        "id": "c99ce050-fe29-4cd0-b628-7cb151b42ef9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_260.txt",
        "created": 1737369140,
        "question": "What materials are allowed during the aptitude test for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "You will be allowed to use a calculator, as well as a piece of paper and pen to help you.",
        "request_id": "db34966ed01526b7f25073f01015e237"
    },
    {
        "id": "3e940984-0231-4a02-bbc4-1768a1521792",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_260.txt",
        "created": 1737369140,
        "question": "What are the options for taking the aptitude test for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "You can choose between an on-campus and an off-campus (online) variant. The off-campus (online) variant will require you to pay a fee of 25$ for the proctoring software Proctorio, and will require a working webcam and microphone. The on-campus variant will not require any fee, as you will be monitored by staff in person.",
        "request_id": "db34966ed01526b7f25073f01015e237"
    },
    {
        "id": "1b08ae95-ea5d-4b40-bbd8-acd4a61d4449",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_261.txt",
        "created": 1737369150,
        "question": "Can I still be added to the moodle exam for the upcoming test?",
        "answer": "We will try our best to still add you to the moodle exam today and send you the link to participate in tomorrow's test.",
        "request_id": "29969745d7a60d5b39e90225a5433a9b"
    },
    {
        "id": "22acddc4-1049-498c-a4be-2dea6e77c35e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_261.txt",
        "created": 1737369150,
        "question": "What happens if I can't participate in the upcoming test?",
        "answer": "Should anything go wrong, there will be a third test date, to which we will invite you.",
        "request_id": "29969745d7a60d5b39e90225a5433a9b"
    },
    {
        "id": "abcceac4-70c2-4d6a-82e7-abd0016e2572",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_261.txt",
        "created": 1737369150,
        "question": "When is the third aptitude test planned?",
        "answer": "The third test is planned for September currently.",
        "request_id": "29969745d7a60d5b39e90225a5433a9b"
    },
    {
        "id": "58867b73-680f-4783-9d99-be5e87413b33",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_262.txt",
        "created": 1737369155,
        "question": "What happens if I have not received any additional information pertaining to the aptitude test the day before the scheduled test?",
        "answer": "There seems to have been a technical mistake. The team will try to add you to the moodle exam today and send you the link to participate tomorrow. Should anything go wrong, there will be a third test date, to which you will be invited.",
        "request_id": "09d5b80c242e51718a6be7deee71e03e"
    },
    {
        "id": "dd303d9a-7b82-49ef-8223-f6b62a9026a5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_263.txt",
        "created": 1737369159,
        "question": "Why haven't I received the link for the Aptitude test and the payment link for the TUM AI program?",
        "answer": "There seems to have been a technical mistake. The team will try to add you to the moodle exam and send you the link to participate. If anything goes wrong, there will be a third test date to which you will be invited.",
        "request_id": "8e0e8aa31c34d8cc6c1de57ad1c5d9b2"
    },
    {
        "id": "c857d45f-bbf4-45b1-9c1a-f9545ed3d63d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_265.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "Are we allowed to have something written before hand on our piece of paper for the exam?",
        "answer": "No, you are not allowed to have information written already. You are only allowed a calculator and a blank piece of paper.",
        "request_id": "65af5aeee03b7017d88eaaff8120a9d9"
    },
    {
        "id": "1dd8c379-fd1c-4715-811f-3808e75a52a1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_267.txt",
        "created": 1737369168,
        "question": "Why haven't I received the test link for the test on July 16th for the MSc in AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Some of your documents are still not marked as 'OK'. The matriculation office needs to assess these documents, which won't be completed in time for the test on July 16th. However, there will be a third test date, to which you will be invited if all your documents are found to be sufficient.",
        "request_id": "515b3871e3be8b296c84068715fa985a"
    },
    {
        "id": "57968d10-86bd-482c-b1c0-c132e5ffb4ff",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_267.txt",
        "created": 1737369168,
        "question": "I uploaded my VPD before the deadline (July 15th), why is it not marked as 'OK'?",
        "answer": "The matriculation office needs to assess the VPD, and it has not been marked as 'OK' yet. The process will be discussed with the matriculation office and you will be informed about what you need to do.",
        "request_id": "515b3871e3be8b296c84068715fa985a"
    },
    {
        "id": "a82b82d3-5d05-4ef9-aa98-a43903b5d551",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_268.txt",
        "created": 1737369320,
        "question": "Why did I receive an invitation to the test when my projects have not been checked yet?",
        "answer": "It could be because you have been waiting for your VPD until recently, which would explain why your documents hadn't been checked yet.",
        "request_id": "d0b5387ac83d3a3ad84adf2ebb10633f"
    },
    {
        "id": "eff17a5c-95fd-4e91-957c-15b937a93cf6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_268.txt",
        "created": 1737369320,
        "question": "Can I be invited to the test tomorrow last-minute?",
        "answer": "No, you cannot be invited to the test tomorrow last-minute as your projects do not reach 18 ECTS.",
        "request_id": "d0b5387ac83d3a3ad84adf2ebb10633f"
    },
    {
        "id": "9aa42ab8-e6f5-4182-9ddc-40ffbe88d1bd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_268.txt",
        "created": 1737369320,
        "question": "Who will make the final decision about the ECTS of my projects?",
        "answer": "The aptitude committee will make the final decision about the ECTS of your projects.",
        "request_id": "d0b5387ac83d3a3ad84adf2ebb10633f"
    },
    {
        "id": "b12f7a8f-29ab-4404-b8b0-336d20e47559",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_268.txt",
        "created": 1737369320,
        "question": "Will there be another aptitude test date?",
        "answer": "Yes, there will be a third aptitude test date, to which you will be invited if your documents pass.",
        "request_id": "d0b5387ac83d3a3ad84adf2ebb10633f"
    },
    {
        "id": "cfa7a5d2-dd17-4bcd-a668-f13aec84cf17",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_269.txt",
        "created": 1737369330,
        "question": "When is the aptitude test scheduled for?",
        "answer": "The aptitude test is scheduled for July 16th, 2024, from 10:45 to 12:15 CEST.",
        "request_id": "332f56a84ac1bac7f538a0a620479443"
    },
    {
        "id": "a199ae40-5186-4578-bd61-a081760efc20",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_269.txt",
        "created": 1737369330,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The aptitude test will consist of 35 multiple choice questions spanned over 90 minutes, and will be held over TUM's internal Moodle platform.",
        "request_id": "332f56a84ac1bac7f538a0a620479443"
    },
    {
        "id": "dde8bb78-b5d5-41a5-9a0f-fee6a4e8a067",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_269.txt",
        "created": 1737369330,
        "question": "What materials are allowed during the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude test, you will be allowed to use a calculator, as well as a piece of paper and pen.",
        "request_id": "332f56a84ac1bac7f538a0a620479443"
    },
    {
        "id": "e745d818-68b2-4d3d-a511-fa9a3764ef30",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_269.txt",
        "created": 1737369330,
        "question": "What are the two variants of taking the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The two variants of taking the aptitude test are an on-campus and an off-campus (online) variant. The off-campus variant requires a fee of 25$ for the proctoring software and a working webcam and microphone. The on-campus variant does not require any fee, as you will be monitored by staff in person.",
        "request_id": "332f56a84ac1bac7f538a0a620479443"
    },
    {
        "id": "897ad944-5758-43d6-a0e4-19581ba1f330",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_269.txt",
        "created": 1737369330,
        "question": "What is the location for the on-campus variant of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The on-campus variant of the aptitude test will take place in Marsstr. 20-22, 80335 Munich, room 605, 6th floor.",
        "request_id": "332f56a84ac1bac7f538a0a620479443"
    },
    {
        "id": "0fa9e00a-2eab-466c-b455-91871ea0241c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_270.txt",
        "created": 1737369342,
        "question": "Why have I not received the detailed guidance link regarding the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Your application was still marked as incomplete in the system, which is why you were not invited to the test right away.",
        "request_id": "ec56feaed7b63afae11e4696d4c4181b"
    },
    {
        "id": "750750a5-f3d9-4084-8597-26168a31ce80",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_270.txt",
        "created": 1737369342,
        "question": "When can I expect to receive the link to the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "You should receive a link to the test today.",
        "request_id": "ec56feaed7b63afae11e4696d4c4181b"
    },
    {
        "id": "99727cb9-ab6f-40fd-a86c-9eec10f83f2e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_270.txt",
        "created": 1737369342,
        "question": "Is the issue of the place of birth not being indicated in the passport related to the aptitude assessment for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The document indicating the place of birth is not related to the aptitude assessment and can be submitted after the admission is confirmed.",
        "request_id": "ec56feaed7b63afae11e4696d4c4181b"
    },
    {
        "id": "8f96474a-8178-4673-912e-13bec0fb2da8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_270.txt",
        "created": 1737369342,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The test will be conducted in English language and span 90 minutes. You will be asked to answer multiple-choice questions (out of multiple different answers, only one is correct).",
        "request_id": "ec56feaed7b63afae11e4696d4c4181b"
    },
    {
        "id": "396b9dab-8456-4c7c-ad37-64d44cbbaaf4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_270.txt",
        "created": 1737369342,
        "question": "What are the options for taking the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The test for the winter semester 2024/25 will be primarily held online. Should you want to take the test in person (TUM, Munich city center) instead, this possibility will also be provided. If you choose to write the test online, you will be monitored via an automated proctoring software, which will demand a fee of 25$. If you do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure, the only other option is to take the test in person.",
        "request_id": "ec56feaed7b63afae11e4696d4c4181b"
    },
    {
        "id": "6204fa54-3a5a-46bc-863e-0cdbf59a0bc7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_271.txt",
        "created": 1737369357,
        "question": "When can I expect to receive the formal offer for the AI in Society master's program?",
        "answer": "The formal offer has been issued now.",
        "request_id": "aa6ecebb7ea3db8f8b503694c91e6d90"
    },
    {
        "id": "51293377-ff2b-4516-90e2-e977bf26f0e0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_274.txt",
        "created": 1737369362,
        "question": "When can the link for the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM be expected?",
        "answer": "The link to the aptitude test will be sent a few days in advance of the test.",
        "request_id": "1d94c682deccb54a9e90b312ebe8fc24"
    },
    {
        "id": "08c278cd-7d60-4e97-8c5d-13ff5695e14b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_274.txt",
        "created": 1737369362,
        "question": "What are the options for taking the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The test can be taken online or in person at TUM, Munich city center.",
        "request_id": "1d94c682deccb54a9e90b312ebe8fc24"
    },
    {
        "id": "971b5048-0973-400d-a531-ef5b5453f59d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_274.txt",
        "created": 1737369362,
        "question": "What are the requirements for taking the online aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the online test, you will be monitored via an automated proctoring software, which will require a fee of $25.",
        "request_id": "1d94c682deccb54a9e90b312ebe8fc24"
    },
    {
        "id": "2f8897a4-173e-4a19-a304-531685a2c3be",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_274.txt",
        "created": 1737369362,
        "question": "What is the format and duration of the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The test will be conducted in English language and span 90 minutes. You will be asked to answer multiple-choice questions.",
        "request_id": "1d94c682deccb54a9e90b312ebe8fc24"
    },
    {
        "id": "8ab5d4ff-a738-4e9e-8309-96dc204f6e09",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_275.txt",
        "created": 1737369373,
        "question": "When can I expect to receive the detailed guidance link for the aptitude test scheduled for July 16th for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "There seems to be an issue with your submitted documents, which is why you have not received an invitation. Please see the TUM application portal for further information.",
        "request_id": "87f0895fa9faa1ef9cd4b02d31a76189"
    },
    {
        "id": "96bb9046-0e08-438b-b3ba-565b41ebf856",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_275.txt",
        "created": 1737369373,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "The test will be conducted in English language and span 90 minutes. You will be asked to answer multiple-choice questions (out of multiple different answers, only one is correct). The topics will span Politics and [REDACTED], Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, Engineering and [REDACTED].",
        "request_id": "87f0895fa9faa1ef9cd4b02d31a76189"
    },
    {
        "id": "7779e208-59b9-40fb-82e3-2d29995eb230",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_275.txt",
        "created": 1737369373,
        "question": "What are the options for taking the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "The test for the winter semester 2024/25 will be primarily held online. Should you want to take the test in person (TUM, Munich city center) instead, we will also provide you with this possibility. If you do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure, the only other option we can offer you is to take the test in person.",
        "request_id": "87f0895fa9faa1ef9cd4b02d31a76189"
    },
    {
        "id": "512f6f19-8022-4cc3-a7e9-26812cb59b9d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_275.txt",
        "created": 1737369373,
        "question": "What is required for the online version of the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "During the online test, you will be monitored via an automated proctoring software. Participation using the proctoring program will demand a fee of 25$.",
        "request_id": "87f0895fa9faa1ef9cd4b02d31a76189"
    },
    {
        "id": "7367787b-d0fb-4ed8-839a-81fc269569ce",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_275.txt",
        "created": 1737369373,
        "question": "Can I use a calculator during the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "During the test, you are allowed to use a calculator.",
        "request_id": "87f0895fa9faa1ef9cd4b02d31a76189"
    },
    {
        "id": "d6152d57-247c-4bb9-ab62-b5457ed5647d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_276.txt",
        "created": 1737369387,
        "question": "Is there a resource for topics for the AI in Society aptitude test?",
        "answer": "Please check our website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/",
        "request_id": "535585db90f03dc76e320776753fd4ce"
    },
    {
        "id": "da6cba27-75b8-4686-a646-43c7a768b0e9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_276.txt",
        "created": 1737369387,
        "question": "When and where will the AI in Society aptitude test take place?",
        "answer": "The test will take place on July 16th, 10:45-12:15 CEST, and will be held over TUM's internal moodle platform. The on-campus variant will take place in Marsstr. 20-22, 80335 Munich, room 605, 6th floor.",
        "request_id": "535585db90f03dc76e320776753fd4ce"
    },
    {
        "id": "e9bad798-d355-4dbe-9325-b4acf71d7fe5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_276.txt",
        "created": 1737369387,
        "question": "What is the format of the AI in Society aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The test will consist of 35 multiple choice questions spanned over 90 minutes. You will be allowed to use a calculator, as well as a piece of paper and pen to help you.",
        "request_id": "535585db90f03dc76e320776753fd4ce"
    },
    {
        "id": "ca04382e-0f1a-4399-97f5-9a8f4ea079e7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_276.txt",
        "created": 1737369387,
        "question": "What are the requirements for the off-campus (online) variant of the AI in Society aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The off-campus (online) variant will require you to pay a fee of 25$ for the proctoring software. This will require a working webcam and microphone.",
        "request_id": "535585db90f03dc76e320776753fd4ce"
    },
    {
        "id": "89c6a1ea-71b1-4198-8194-ab37c3774fee",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_276.txt",
        "created": 1737369387,
        "question": "What are the requirements for the on-campus variant of the AI in Society aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The on-campus variant will not require any fee, as you will be monitored by staff in person. You will need to bring your laptop to take the test. The test will not be written on paper. Should you not be able to bring a laptop for the test, please let us know in advance. We will provide you with a laptop in this case.",
        "request_id": "535585db90f03dc76e320776753fd4ce"
    },
    {
        "id": "7d593d4a-a269-454b-b23e-41a3287a59aa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_277.txt",
        "created": 1737369400,
        "question": "Due to a time difference mix-up, would it be possible for us to reschedule for a different time today?",
        "answer": "In that case, we will offer you a second interview date at the end of July. Please await further information regarding timeslots.",
        "request_id": "cddbcfb030e251ef3e1a8bdf914f1fd1"
    },
    {
        "id": "45bacc69-70fa-4882-b3a8-1f88ec73d820",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_278.txt",
        "created": 1737369403,
        "question": "When will the link for the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society be sent?",
        "answer": "The link for the aptitude test will be sent a few days in advance of the test.",
        "request_id": "2d0182bb236df2672a71ef1a1fe8107c"
    },
    {
        "id": "baa90062-9270-4285-9075-2eec9a5dab51",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_278.txt",
        "created": 1737369403,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "The test will be conducted in English language and span 90 minutes. You will be asked to answer multiple-choice questions (out of multiple different answers, only one is correct). The topics will span Politics and [REDACTED], Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, Engineering and [REDACTED].",
        "request_id": "2d0182bb236df2672a71ef1a1fe8107c"
    },
    {
        "id": "50a48ad7-42cf-4fa1-a3c5-cc43adc44be0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_278.txt",
        "created": 1737369403,
        "question": "What are the options for taking the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "The test for the winter semester 2024/25 will be primarily held online. Should you want to take the test in person (TUM, Munich city center) instead, this possibility will also be provided.",
        "request_id": "2d0182bb236df2672a71ef1a1fe8107c"
    },
    {
        "id": "bd103794-71df-4a52-b858-2d1f81d75754",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_278.txt",
        "created": 1737369403,
        "question": "What are the requirements for taking the online aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "During the online test, you will be monitored via an automated proctoring software. Participation using the proctoring program will demand a fee of 25$. If you do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure, the only other option is to take the test in person.",
        "request_id": "2d0182bb236df2672a71ef1a1fe8107c"
    },
    {
        "id": "f1654f04-a03d-44e2-9406-58f467425480",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_278.txt",
        "created": 1737369403,
        "question": "What materials are allowed during the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "During the test, you are allowed to use a calculator.",
        "request_id": "2d0182bb236df2672a71ef1a1fe8107c"
    },
    {
        "id": "1b499f24-dbcb-4495-94b4-8b4f24fbe6b0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_282.txt",
        "created": 1737369421,
        "question": "What is the status of my application for M.Sc AI?",
        "answer": "Your application documents are still marked as incomplete as your VPD has still not been processed yet. For detailed information, please refer to the comments inserted in your TUM application portal regarding missing/incomplete documents.",
        "request_id": "591ea34188dab30517a5ab19865c7558"
    },
    {
        "id": "b8469d2c-c616-4f9a-9ec0-856a28ffdb9f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_282.txt",
        "created": 1737369421,
        "question": "Why haven't I received an invitation for the interview and aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You have not been invited to the test as your application documents are still marked as incomplete due to your unprocessed VPD.",
        "request_id": "591ea34188dab30517a5ab19865c7558"
    },
    {
        "id": "7cc01cd1-b6e0-4c2d-a51b-ef8b5ddf0ff4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_282.txt",
        "created": 1737369421,
        "question": "Is my interview scheduled for July 16th 2024?",
        "answer": "No, you cannot be invited to the test as of now because your application documents are incomplete. For applicants where we are still waiting on the VPD, there will be another test date in September.",
        "request_id": "591ea34188dab30517a5ab19865c7558"
    },
    {
        "id": "b70c705e-8675-409b-8e4d-fc56971a1fba",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_282.txt",
        "created": 1737369421,
        "question": "Why have some applicants not received an invitation to the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "Due to the large number of applications, some were not checked in time for the initial test date. These applicants will be invited to a second test date, provided all their documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "591ea34188dab30517a5ab19865c7558"
    },
    {
        "id": "f3242dbb-b753-4a6d-b875-211701ab1850",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_282.txt",
        "created": 1737369421,
        "question": "When is the second test date for those who did not receive an invitation for the first one?",
        "answer": "The second test date is on July 16th, from 10:45 - 12:15 CEST. However, for applicants where we are still waiting on the VPD, there will be another test date in September.",
        "request_id": "591ea34188dab30517a5ab19865c7558"
    },
    {
        "id": "a69070f1-0174-48e1-99ee-c9a07bc703f3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_284.txt",
        "created": 1737369442,
        "question": "Are there any additional steps I need to take or applications I should submit for financial aid consideration at TUM or the AIS master program?",
        "answer": "The student is referred to TUM\u2019s scholarship office (https://www.tum.de/en/studies/fees-and-financial-aid/scholarships) for all questions regarding funding possibilities.",
        "request_id": "a07fb0298db6c7f53b42bdc0caab098b"
    },
    {
        "id": "63b324b5-669f-46dd-841f-bc6c16620eb2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_285.txt",
        "created": 1737369449,
        "question": "Is it possible that in the acceptance letter the semester fees could be mentioned?",
        "answer": "For this question, I would kindly refer you to the center of fees and scholarships: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/fees",
        "request_id": "cdacbc078c14d0111480fdbc56ca4600"
    },
    {
        "id": "8dc7a995-e1f1-4540-9173-73de0d1f4549",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_286.txt",
        "created": 1737369452,
        "question": "How many questions are in the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The test consists of 35 questions.",
        "request_id": "c78d259ffa07d2adaaf63b1595f6db79"
    },
    {
        "id": "2d637e54-e293-4c4f-9b40-a065d181007f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_286.txt",
        "created": 1737369452,
        "question": "What does 'Level 2' mean in terms of the total score for the entry process to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The score for level 2 refers to the score you receive in the interview. The interview, however, is an optional step and not everyone will need to go through one.",
        "request_id": "c78d259ffa07d2adaaf63b1595f6db79"
    },
    {
        "id": "1f69d37d-5331-4ebd-916f-b1be2a9ea2d0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_298.txt",
        "created": 1737369474,
        "question": "Do we need to offer a third test date?",
        "answer": "Yes, we are still waiting for people who are waiting for their VPD. They have a long deadline for submission. We might have to move it to August or so, otherwise it really won't work with the programming course.",
        "request_id": "9961ede79e736dd296e466be6b115110"
    },
    {
        "id": "8cea1cb0-f786-4b0e-9dc1-765489abd487",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_298.txt",
        "created": 1737369474,
        "question": "Should we give people the opportunity to move the test date (from the second to the third test date in September), or should we just say this is the only opportunity?",
        "answer": "No, we don't have to offer a third date. If we can do without it, that would be great, as we are already starting the programming course in the week before the start of the semester.",
        "request_id": "9961ede79e736dd296e466be6b115110"
    },
    {
        "id": "9e07ff9c-0b89-480b-8533-a390e74747f5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_300.txt",
        "created": 1737369481,
        "question": "Could you confirm that I am enrolling as a German national and thus will not be charged for tuition?",
        "answer": "You will not be charged a tuition fee due to your dual citizenship. However, for an official confirmation, you should refer to the center of fees and scholarships (https://www.tum.de/en/studies/fees).",
        "request_id": "56d314307fccde2e1a6020a10bcbc4b9"
    },
    {
        "id": "d7d46d1c-0912-4f76-a8bc-e94b51e97485",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_302.txt",
        "created": 1737369071,
        "question": "Why is the admission process for the AI in Society program at TUM taking longer than expected?",
        "answer": "There is a shortage in administration staff, causing the processes to take more time than usual.",
        "request_id": "960e301186ef096efbf56429ba9f3ec6"
    },
    {
        "id": "cdd0addb-6525-4bd7-900b-6106a42ee21f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_302.txt",
        "created": 1737369071,
        "question": "Why is my score for Level 1 of the admission step not available on the platform?",
        "answer": "The score for Level 1 is made up of points calculated based on your grades, as well as the points you receive in the aptitude test. It will be updated after the aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "960e301186ef096efbf56429ba9f3ec6"
    },
    {
        "id": "821fc9b3-1482-43a9-bf80-9540649f8931",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_302.txt",
        "created": 1737369071,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The test will be conducted in English language and span 90 minutes. You will be asked to answer multiple-choice questions. The topics will span Politics and [REDACTED], Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, Engineering and [REDACTED].",
        "request_id": "960e301186ef096efbf56429ba9f3ec6"
    },
    {
        "id": "0f9979e9-3415-4c22-8251-5a6a040e8d3f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_302.txt",
        "created": 1737369071,
        "question": "What are the options for taking the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The test for the winter semester 2024/25 will be primarily held online. Should you want to take the test in person (TUM, Munich city center) instead, that option is also available. If you choose to write the test online, you will be monitored via an automated proctoring software, which will demand a fee of 25$. If you do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure, the only other option is to take the test in person.",
        "request_id": "960e301186ef096efbf56429ba9f3ec6"
    },
    {
        "id": "f3839f81-9473-42a0-bf9d-c5b5ca099ba6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_303.txt",
        "created": 1737369087,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The test will be conducted in English language and span 90 minutes. You will be asked to answer multiple-choice questions (out of multiple different answers, only one is correct). The topics will span Politics and [REDACTED], Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, and Engineering and [REDACTED].",
        "request_id": "72d056acfe6d35b0e8de0a77eb61ecfd"
    },
    {
        "id": "1d6187c2-9eda-4b65-9a89-ec81f94c0981",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_303.txt",
        "created": 1737369087,
        "question": "Can the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society at TUM be taken online?",
        "answer": "Yes, the test can be taken online. However, during the test, you will be monitored via an automated proctoring software. Participation using the proctoring program will demand a fee of 25$. If you do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure, the only other option is to take the test in person.",
        "request_id": "72d056acfe6d35b0e8de0a77eb61ecfd"
    },
    {
        "id": "39e6867b-ce17-4a72-89cc-7c28f56f452d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_303.txt",
        "created": 1737369087,
        "question": "Why was the date of the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society at TUM changed?",
        "answer": "Problems with the test date occurred due to capacity shortcuts in the administration.",
        "request_id": "72d056acfe6d35b0e8de0a77eb61ecfd"
    },
    {
        "id": "360888f2-52b4-44d4-b991-75fca962df55",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_303.txt",
        "created": 1737369087,
        "question": "Can I take the online aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society at TUM without being monitored?",
        "answer": "The monitoring form of the test is aligned according to TUM ProLehre standards and is a standard procedure. If you choose to take the test without being monitored, your test results may be disregarded.",
        "request_id": "72d056acfe6d35b0e8de0a77eb61ecfd"
    },
    {
        "id": "e149e42b-3275-4f78-82c3-e0b436c89742",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_305.txt",
        "created": 1737369102,
        "question": "When is the interview scheduled for?",
        "answer": "The interview is scheduled for July 10th, 09:30 \u2013 10:00.",
        "request_id": "ba02c8f769600f94f7242e89c24d3dad"
    },
    {
        "id": "ae92a1da-0bb4-4a96-81a1-12fd7dd4bba7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_305.txt",
        "created": 1737369102,
        "question": "When will the Zoom meeting link for the interview be sent?",
        "answer": "The Zoom meeting link will be sent at some point during the day before the interview.",
        "request_id": "ba02c8f769600f94f7242e89c24d3dad"
    },
    {
        "id": "e2da9090-fe47-4bce-8895-ef51d81a9cbf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_305.txt",
        "created": 1737369102,
        "question": "Does the website automatically convert the interview times to the applicant's timezone?",
        "answer": "Yes, the website automatically converts the interview times to the applicant's timezone.",
        "request_id": "ba02c8f769600f94f7242e89c24d3dad"
    },
    {
        "id": "48915949-a60a-4af6-a796-e39c68cc77e6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_305.txt",
        "created": 1737369102,
        "question": "What will be discussed during the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss the applicant's motivation for choosing this degree program, willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, professional interests, any previous specializations, and professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and career aspirations.",
        "request_id": "ba02c8f769600f94f7242e89c24d3dad"
    },
    {
        "id": "dbd81536-ff9c-4036-be44-81b9a09f601e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_305.txt",
        "created": 1737369102,
        "question": "How can an applicant select a timeslot for the interview?",
        "answer": "Applicants can select a timeslot for the interview using the provided link. They will need to enter their email address and full name, then choose one timeslot that works best for them. Each timeslot can only be selected by one person, therefore the distribution of slots works by the principle \u201cfirst come, first serve\u201d. After selecting, they need to submit their answer.",
        "request_id": "ba02c8f769600f94f7242e89c24d3dad"
    },
    {
        "id": "6a7a70d0-9945-44df-91a9-66b1ff164da1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_313.txt",
        "created": 1737369122,
        "question": "What is the process for admission into the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society at the Technical University of Munich?",
        "answer": "The admission is conditioned on the successful completion of an aptitude assessment. The applicant's documents must be approved by the aptitude committee, after which they are invited to take the aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "bd41d36001502a44c14eb9c173e701a4"
    },
    {
        "id": "b04b43b3-f570-449b-80af-34c15032b4e9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_313.txt",
        "created": 1737369122,
        "question": "When and where will the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society for the winter semester 2024/25 take place?",
        "answer": "The aptitude test will take place on July 16th, from 10:45 to 12:15 CEST. The test will be primarily held online, but there is also an option to take the test in person at TUM, Munich city center.",
        "request_id": "bd41d36001502a44c14eb9c173e701a4"
    },
    {
        "id": "4fbc9b68-12df-43a0-a041-55d3b5b75ec2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_313.txt",
        "created": 1737369122,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "The test will be conducted in English language and span 90 minutes. It will consist of multiple-choice questions (out of multiple different answers, only one is correct). The topics will cover Politics, Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, and Engineering.",
        "request_id": "bd41d36001502a44c14eb9c173e701a4"
    },
    {
        "id": "14524ca1-9fd4-4802-9f51-65cf1f9a9d74",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_313.txt",
        "created": 1737369122,
        "question": "What are the requirements for taking the online aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "During the online test, applicants will be monitored via an automated proctoring software. Participation using the proctoring program will demand a fee of 25$. If an applicant does not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure, the only other option is to take the test in person.",
        "request_id": "bd41d36001502a44c14eb9c173e701a4"
    },
    {
        "id": "82e23970-4c5a-49a5-9c9f-0516da6d1a10",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_313.txt",
        "created": 1737369122,
        "question": "What resources are allowed during the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "During the test, applicants are allowed to use a calculator.",
        "request_id": "bd41d36001502a44c14eb9c173e701a4"
    },
    {
        "id": "6cad0605-39d4-48b5-9ade-f84361427094",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_316.txt",
        "created": 1737369140,
        "question": "What is the requirement for ECTS in the context of the project?",
        "answer": "The requirement is 5 ECTS.",
        "request_id": "94925f236ef93796ebea8d8ffce4025f"
    },
    {
        "id": "b9851a60-1e17-4a95-bcf3-1f95d846a8b5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_316.txt",
        "created": 1737369140,
        "question": "What are the reasons for a project not being okay?",
        "answer": "A project may not be okay if it has less than the required ECTS, if the technical aspect is not given sufficiently, if the interdisciplinary aspect is not given sufficiently, or if it is unclear which module the project refers to, making it impossible to match ECTS.",
        "request_id": "94925f236ef93796ebea8d8ffce4025f"
    },
    {
        "id": "1848946e-05d2-44e6-8d05-02ec380e037b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_321.txt",
        "created": 1737369160,
        "question": "What is the status of my application for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "You have passed the document check and will be invited to take the test. The invitation will be sent out in the coming days. Your status has just not been updated in the system yet.",
        "request_id": "fd3acc6563d00415fd7873aaf9f6643f"
    },
    {
        "id": "86393867-e0f3-4947-993e-04c4e6cadcfc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_321.txt",
        "created": 1737369160,
        "question": "How can I appear in the test on the 16th of July 2024 for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM if my application review status is still in progress?",
        "answer": "You have passed the document check and will be invited to take the test. The invitation will be sent out in the coming days. Your status has just not been updated in the system yet.",
        "request_id": "fd3acc6563d00415fd7873aaf9f6643f"
    },
    {
        "id": "f0d6aa0b-bb4f-42b6-b684-c5a15eefdc67",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_321.txt",
        "created": 1737369160,
        "question": "What is the procedure for applicants who have not yet received an invitation to the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "There will be a second test date on July 16th, from 10:45 - 12:15 CEST. Applicants who did not yet hear back from the university (and were not declined either), should await further feedback regarding their application in the coming weeks. The university will finish checking the remaining applicants and invite them to the second test, should all their documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "fd3acc6563d00415fd7873aaf9f6643f"
    },
    {
        "id": "2ce51032-4585-4ead-9c1a-c362c4c8f9da",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_323.txt",
        "created": 1737369171,
        "question": "What time is my interview scheduled for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Your interview is scheduled for 09:00 \u2013 09:30 CEST.",
        "request_id": "3ed385b3c3c2da11593f83ad7d8d883c"
    },
    {
        "id": "57f61ebb-2195-42ed-be9d-f389a0ec091f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_323.txt",
        "created": 1737369171,
        "question": "Does the kulibri website adjust the interview times to the user\u2019s timezone?",
        "answer": "Yes, the website seems to adjust the times to the user\u2019s timezone.",
        "request_id": "3ed385b3c3c2da11593f83ad7d8d883c"
    },
    {
        "id": "b16fb3a7-1abc-48b2-9032-a87f5bf79c5a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_340.txt",
        "created": 1737369201,
        "question": "When is the deadline to accept the admission offer and enroll for the AI in Society master program?",
        "answer": "You can accept the study place until September 30th.",
        "request_id": "8a1e88e1276d37710d97c6c3356b2298"
    },
    {
        "id": "179aaf27-3eb9-4875-89c3-9039da143b36",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_340.txt",
        "created": 1737369201,
        "question": "Where are the AI in Society lectures taking place?",
        "answer": "The lectures are planned to be organized in the city center, either at Richard-Wagner-Str. 1, Marsstr. 20-22, or Arcisstr. 21. Some courses from other departments might be offered in Garching, but the majority will take place in the city center.",
        "request_id": "8a1e88e1276d37710d97c6c3356b2298"
    },
    {
        "id": "0462f6da-0b3c-4019-b95c-cfc851c6bd9f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_340.txt",
        "created": 1737369201,
        "question": "What is the intake rate for 'AI in Society' for the academic year 2024/25, i.e. how many students have applied and are expected to be admitted to the master program for this upcoming semester?",
        "answer": "The amount of students who will start their studies with us is relatively hard to tell at the moment, since the selection progress is still ongoing.",
        "request_id": "8a1e88e1276d37710d97c6c3356b2298"
    },
    {
        "id": "afe4b4d7-ef0d-4493-aea5-2213747ba095",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_341.txt",
        "created": 1737369208,
        "question": "What is the status of my application for the Master of Science in AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Your application is being reviewed in the coming days. Should you pass the formal requirements, you will receive an invitation email to the aptitude test in advance to the test.",
        "request_id": "14850d9a1e0f480f03fe4ed1cefdbc8b"
    },
    {
        "id": "bbd26208-1927-4f87-88d7-623789d0055f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_341.txt",
        "created": 1737369208,
        "question": "What is the procedure for applicants who have not yet received an invitation to the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "There will be a second test date. Should you be one of the applicants who did not yet hear back from us (and were not declined either), please await further feedback regarding your application in the coming weeks from us. We will finish checking the remaining applicants and invite you to the second test, should all your documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "14850d9a1e0f480f03fe4ed1cefdbc8b"
    },
    {
        "id": "8db3edb0-c45c-4598-941c-b63c18a0a0a9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_347.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "Can I submit a missing document via email after the application deadline?",
        "answer": "No, documents cannot be accepted via email and must be uploaded to the application portal by the deadline.",
        "request_id": "1ed3ed768232b7dc9ec605646d18adff"
    },
    {
        "id": "d29e3f45-6667-4342-9c8e-eea27bbcfcb9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_347.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "Can the application deadline be extended to allow for late submission of a document?",
        "answer": "No, the application deadline cannot be extended for late submissions.",
        "request_id": "1ed3ed768232b7dc9ec605646d18adff"
    },
    {
        "id": "017d0179-bf34-42ab-b2a5-860dcc5e3d17",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_347.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "Can my application be considered for the next admission cycle if I missed the current deadline?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can apply again for the next year if you missed the current deadline.",
        "request_id": "1ed3ed768232b7dc9ec605646d18adff"
    },
    {
        "id": "38a33c3d-9dd6-4c1a-bf3a-672af7ffc1a0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_347.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "What happens if I have not received an invitation to the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "If you have not received an invitation to the aptitude test, there will be a second test date. You should await further feedback regarding your application in the coming weeks.",
        "request_id": "1ed3ed768232b7dc9ec605646d18adff"
    },
    {
        "id": "63fc7e25-f6a7-42aa-9922-33ee0ba6e1fe",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_348.txt",
        "created": 1737369228,
        "question": "Can documents be sent via email for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, documents cannot be accepted via email. They need to be uploaded in time to the application portal.",
        "request_id": "73532c143657a6e57e334c52ba9c13b8"
    },
    {
        "id": "c2aa3fcf-c343-4764-8440-06267bed83c8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_348.txt",
        "created": 1737369228,
        "question": "What happens if an applicant hasn't received an invitation to the aptitude test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "If an applicant hasn't received an invitation to the aptitude test, they should await further feedback regarding their application in the coming weeks. There will be a second test date and they will be invited to this test if all their documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "73532c143657a6e57e334c52ba9c13b8"
    },
    {
        "id": "44c977e2-2efe-4264-a93e-aaee10066956",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_348.txt",
        "created": 1737369228,
        "question": "What is the plan for applicants who have not yet received feedback for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The plan for applicants who have not yet received feedback is to finish checking the remaining applicants and invite them to a second test, should all their documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "73532c143657a6e57e334c52ba9c13b8"
    },
    {
        "id": "39655553-4f0c-44d9-ad6e-dd09cc692bca",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_353.txt",
        "created": 1737369079,
        "question": "Do I have a slot for 1200 today?",
        "answer": "No, you are not registered for any slot. Someone else is scheduled for 12 o'clock.",
        "request_id": "8c091a0ab541e5295e97f71b1d1e1b63"
    },
    {
        "id": "fd0f26de-eae2-4e7c-bcdd-7edac94e06da",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_353.txt",
        "created": 1737369079,
        "question": "Why didn't my slot reservation go through?",
        "answer": "You might have indicated your slot but did not click save or something similar. There should be a red button next to the slot for saving.",
        "request_id": "8c091a0ab541e5295e97f71b1d1e1b63"
    },
    {
        "id": "fb4cc40e-e0e4-434a-916b-a1628a0f137f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_353.txt",
        "created": 1737369079,
        "question": "How can I reserve a slot?",
        "answer": "Please use the following link to reserve an available slot from the remaining ones: https://app.kulibri.com/pr/GY6mLGdlpEg0/1BWn1BWnmarZw9zE",
        "request_id": "8c091a0ab541e5295e97f71b1d1e1b63"
    },
    {
        "id": "1589054a-7eee-4dc1-89f5-5e83d5786399",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_354.txt",
        "created": 1737369087,
        "question": "What is the purpose of the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program. They will also explore your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations. The focus is on understanding your motivation for the study program, not testing your knowledge on specific subjects.",
        "request_id": "321ca6a57dbae3738c54b4b8adc86b3c"
    },
    {
        "id": "1f3575da-04c1-4252-ba16-997e06f79392",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_354.txt",
        "created": 1737369087,
        "question": "When and how will the aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place from July 3rd to July 10th and will be conducted online over Zoom.",
        "request_id": "321ca6a57dbae3738c54b4b8adc86b3c"
    },
    {
        "id": "52b9d54d-d148-432a-971c-7866db2fce4b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_354.txt",
        "created": 1737369087,
        "question": "How can I select a timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "You can select a timeslot by using the provided link. You will need to enter your email address as well as your full name. Then choose one timeslot that works best for you. Each timeslot can only be selected by one person, therefore the distribution of slots works by the principle \u201cfirst come, first serve\u201d. Don\u2019t forget to submit your answer after selecting.",
        "request_id": "321ca6a57dbae3738c54b4b8adc86b3c"
    },
    {
        "id": "25503baf-8e39-411c-ad2d-d4d17e6317ba",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_354.txt",
        "created": 1737369087,
        "question": "Can I change my selected timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can change your selection later yourself. However, you should let the committee know if you had to change your slot, especially last minute.",
        "request_id": "321ca6a57dbae3738c54b4b8adc86b3c"
    },
    {
        "id": "6b4d3cd6-ead5-4715-aa7e-3687e1e9c732",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_354.txt",
        "created": 1737369087,
        "question": "Will I receive a confirmation email after selecting a timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, as soon as you have selected a time slot, you can think of it as confirmed \u2013 there will be no additional email confirming your timeslot. You will receive your personal Zoom link at least 12 hours in advance to your interview.",
        "request_id": "321ca6a57dbae3738c54b4b8adc86b3c"
    },
    {
        "id": "9a75420d-bc69-4eeb-b4d7-3ad20bc13b61",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_355.txt",
        "created": 1737369105,
        "question": "Is there any date that we should expect the result of the acceptance to the Master AI in Society?",
        "answer": "The result of the acceptance to the Master AI in Society can only be provided after the aptitude test on July 16th.",
        "request_id": "ef4c8bf66f18cf453f56d0801bb8c0ad"
    },
    {
        "id": "ebb22c7b-58e5-482e-9432-b4288cf82e53",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_355.txt",
        "created": 1737369105,
        "question": "Would it be possible to get an answer for the acceptance to the Master AI in Society before the 15th of July?",
        "answer": "No, it is not possible to provide an answer for the acceptance to the Master AI in Society before the 15th of July as the aptitude test is scheduled for July 16th.",
        "request_id": "ef4c8bf66f18cf453f56d0801bb8c0ad"
    },
    {
        "id": "f4555b15-9c51-499a-b9ba-143be9b5aa2d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_356.txt",
        "created": 1737369111,
        "question": "When scheduling the interview for the AI in Society program, the prompt states that 'Times are given in CEST,' but in the Antwort section, the time zone is listed as Asia/Shanghai. Which time zone should I follow when arranging the interview time?",
        "answer": "The website automatically converts the times to your timezone. So, what you are seeing is just according to your timezone, not CEST.",
        "request_id": "1dd9dd4bec0df7eacedd2a6fea7f5a6e"
    },
    {
        "id": "5c3ad655-34fe-4b15-9eed-b643aed2c482",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_357.txt",
        "created": 1737369116,
        "question": "Is it theoretically possible to reverse a rejection in the system?",
        "answer": "Yes, it is possible. You would need to write us an email or call us as soon as possible. Within an hour of booking, we can withdraw the rejection without an email going out to the applicant. If the rejection has been a little longer, it's also no problem.",
        "request_id": "66d63165a3ce10b498b43f13b5d1ca6b"
    },
    {
        "id": "3eeaa09a-26b8-4eb8-acd6-349a7574fb81",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_358.txt",
        "created": 1737369119,
        "question": "What is the issue with the previously chosen interview timeslot (9.7. 12:30-13:00)?",
        "answer": "One of the interviewers has a time conflict and won\u2019t be able to make it.",
        "request_id": "e7f11dde3d6d6e644c2f00f390b9b34a"
    },
    {
        "id": "9821aa33-7cf1-4518-9682-a03ae0b096e6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_358.txt",
        "created": 1737369119,
        "question": "What is the proposed solution for the issue with the previously chosen interview timeslot?",
        "answer": "The solution is to choose a different timeslot from the ones that are still available.",
        "request_id": "e7f11dde3d6d6e644c2f00f390b9b34a"
    },
    {
        "id": "427fb074-3dc7-494d-a40b-4ceb9ff362a6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_378.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "What time zone are the meetings?",
        "answer": "The meetings are in the CEST timezone.",
        "request_id": "6347dfe37403fba0c1d87c50391f206a"
    },
    {
        "id": "ffc94b61-e72b-42f6-bf57-2ce9514dcc81",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_378.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "When choosing slots, it says Asia/ Karachi, does this mean that the timings have been converted to our timezones or it's just additional information?",
        "answer": "The selected time is in CEST for your interview.",
        "request_id": "6347dfe37403fba0c1d87c50391f206a"
    },
    {
        "id": "822583cd-9fae-4ab2-9ae6-75cc30120ada",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_378.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "How to select a timeslot for the interview?",
        "answer": "You need to use the provided link, enter your email address and full name, and then choose one timeslot that works best for you. Each timeslot can only be selected by one person, therefore the distribution of slots works by the principle \u201cfirst come, first serve\u201d. After selecting, don't forget to submit your answer.",
        "request_id": "6347dfe37403fba0c1d87c50391f206a"
    },
    {
        "id": "4c49745f-071e-481c-b0ba-c96733e56e1e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_378.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "What if I want to change my selection later?",
        "answer": "You will be able to change your selection yourself. However, you should let the team know in case you had to change your slot, especially last minute.",
        "request_id": "6347dfe37403fba0c1d87c50391f206a"
    },
    {
        "id": "a93910c5-191f-4e06-b3da-bfc20eec8476",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_378.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "Will there be an additional email confirming my timeslot?",
        "answer": "As soon as you have selected a time slot, you can think of it as confirmed \u2013 there will be no additional email confirming your timeslot.",
        "request_id": "6347dfe37403fba0c1d87c50391f206a"
    },
    {
        "id": "5524d55e-0049-463c-a564-492f3f60c60d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_379.txt",
        "created": 1737369161,
        "question": "What is the second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second stage of the aptitude assessment is an interview. During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program, your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations.",
        "request_id": "f119bdaf19c3986d98b9246135fada89"
    },
    {
        "id": "9abaec23-8a15-4e54-802a-3cb846fdd63d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_379.txt",
        "created": 1737369161,
        "question": "When and where will the interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place from July 3rd to July 10th and will be conducted online over Zoom.",
        "request_id": "f119bdaf19c3986d98b9246135fada89"
    },
    {
        "id": "6d6458fe-a5ce-44f3-af99-c7a737d4bbfd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_379.txt",
        "created": 1737369161,
        "question": "How can I select a timeslot for the interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "You can select a timeslot by using the provided link. You will need to enter your email address as well as your full name, and then choose one timeslot that works best for you. Each timeslot can only be selected by one person, therefore the distribution of slots works by the principle \u201cfirst come, first serve\u201d. After selecting, don't forget to submit your answer.",
        "request_id": "f119bdaf19c3986d98b9246135fada89"
    },
    {
        "id": "8bb9c499-197c-4ed9-8587-21b19e0c9929",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_379.txt",
        "created": 1737369161,
        "question": "Can I change my selected timeslot for the interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can change your selection later by yourself. However, you should let the committee know if you had to change your slot, especially if it was last minute.",
        "request_id": "f119bdaf19c3986d98b9246135fada89"
    },
    {
        "id": "c7042d74-d7ff-434f-8190-59c640c6bf45",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_379.txt",
        "created": 1737369161,
        "question": "Will I receive a confirmation email after selecting a timeslot for the interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, there will be no additional email confirming your timeslot. As soon as you have selected a time slot, you can think of it as confirmed. You will receive your personal Zoom link at least 12 hours in advance to your interview.",
        "request_id": "f119bdaf19c3986d98b9246135fada89"
    },
    {
        "id": "b5952480-dc4c-47bb-bd4b-b3ebabbaf9f4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_382.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "What is the second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second stage of the aptitude assessment is an interview. During the interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program, your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations.",
        "request_id": "a479bbcc63f6e7c90c78831aa4d69a78"
    },
    {
        "id": "80104d85-8b48-4b88-9696-5889b74bac4c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_382.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "When and how will the aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place from July 3rd to July 10th and will be conducted online over Zoom.",
        "request_id": "a479bbcc63f6e7c90c78831aa4d69a78"
    },
    {
        "id": "e7ee3934-7542-4c04-bc2b-004e2ff66d71",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_382.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "How can I select a timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "You can select a timeslot by using the provided link. You will need to enter your email address and your full name, then choose one timeslot that works best for you. Each timeslot can only be selected by one person, and the distribution of slots works by the principle \u201cfirst come, first serve\u201d. After selecting, don't forget to submit your answer.",
        "request_id": "a479bbcc63f6e7c90c78831aa4d69a78"
    },
    {
        "id": "6b26c1ad-f39b-4f8b-8115-409912a9475d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_382.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "Can I change my selected timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can change your selection later by yourself. However, you should let the committee know if you had to change your slot, especially if it was a last-minute change.",
        "request_id": "a479bbcc63f6e7c90c78831aa4d69a78"
    },
    {
        "id": "4e90457c-84ff-4013-9ba0-141368c443ea",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_382.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "Will I receive a confirmation email after selecting a timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, there will be no additional email confirming your timeslot. As soon as you have selected a time slot, you can think of it as confirmed. You will receive your personal Zoom link at least 12 hours in advance to your interview.",
        "request_id": "a479bbcc63f6e7c90c78831aa4d69a78"
    },
    {
        "id": "56997851-3588-4682-9bcb-53e86b4c8aaa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_383.txt",
        "created": 1737369194,
        "question": "What is the second stage of the aptitude assessment for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second stage of the aptitude assessment is an interview. During the interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss the applicant's motivation for choosing this degree program, willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, professional interests, any previous specializations, and professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and the applicant's career aspirations.",
        "request_id": "f71c3d426000e5eb2005de97aafde8e6"
    },
    {
        "id": "5ecebae5-f1ed-41e9-8237-f4c6dbe9a2ac",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_383.txt",
        "created": 1737369194,
        "question": "What is the focus of the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The focus of the aptitude interview is understanding the applicant's motivation for the study program, not testing their knowledge on specific subjects.",
        "request_id": "f71c3d426000e5eb2005de97aafde8e6"
    },
    {
        "id": "fd856a7b-8752-421a-aa8a-ca898b2175a1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_383.txt",
        "created": 1737369194,
        "question": "When and how will the interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place from July 3rd to July 10th and will be conducted online over Zoom.",
        "request_id": "f71c3d426000e5eb2005de97aafde8e6"
    },
    {
        "id": "bc8f2d2c-a58b-468d-91d4-5be18803e4d0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_383.txt",
        "created": 1737369194,
        "question": "How can an applicant select a timeslot for the interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "Applicants can select a timeslot by using a provided link. They will need to enter their email address and full name, and then choose one timeslot that works best for them. Each timeslot can only be selected by one person, therefore the distribution of slots works by the principle \u201cfirst come, first serve\u201d. After selecting, they must submit their answer.",
        "request_id": "f71c3d426000e5eb2005de97aafde8e6"
    },
    {
        "id": "ba449190-f5b1-4123-a5fb-862ac1ea8b84",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_383.txt",
        "created": 1737369194,
        "question": "What should an applicant do if they want to change their selected timeslot for the interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "If an applicant wants to change their selection later, they will be able to do so themselves. However, they should let the committee know if they had to change their slot, especially at the last minute.",
        "request_id": "f71c3d426000e5eb2005de97aafde8e6"
    },
    {
        "id": "b8aab7ac-0008-4344-a27f-0dd367b8e418",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_384.txt",
        "created": 1737369209,
        "question": "What is the purpose of the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "During the aptitude interview, two members of the selection committee will discuss your motivation for choosing this degree program. They will also explore your willingness to engage in interdisciplinary learning and work, your professional interests, any previous specializations, and your professional background to assess how well these align with the goals of the program and your career aspirations. The focus is on understanding your motivation for the study program, not testing your knowledge on specific subjects.",
        "request_id": "ead46cedc1eac2e3ee7d0ce753be1331"
    },
    {
        "id": "c46318e9-ac39-4689-af7b-0334de490945",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_384.txt",
        "created": 1737369209,
        "question": "When and how will the aptitude interviews for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM take place?",
        "answer": "The interviews will take place from July 3rd to July 10th and will be conducted online over Zoom.",
        "request_id": "ead46cedc1eac2e3ee7d0ce753be1331"
    },
    {
        "id": "831897c5-3af9-4fba-a50a-bb8e0fb7accc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_384.txt",
        "created": 1737369209,
        "question": "How can I select a timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "You will need to enter your email address as well as your full name in the provided link. Please then choose one timeslot that works best for you. Each timeslot can only be selected by one person, therefore the distribution of slots works by the principle \u201cfirst come, first serve\u201d. Don\u2019t forget to submit your answer after selecting.",
        "request_id": "ead46cedc1eac2e3ee7d0ce753be1331"
    },
    {
        "id": "0b961ad7-6e02-4f12-a30b-6572dbe7aa4e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_384.txt",
        "created": 1737369209,
        "question": "Can I change my selected timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can change your selection later by yourself. However, you should let the committee know if you had to change your slot, especially at the last minute.",
        "request_id": "ead46cedc1eac2e3ee7d0ce753be1331"
    },
    {
        "id": "6005ade9-8f7e-4c17-bf8d-2e04e708ad77",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_384.txt",
        "created": 1737369209,
        "question": "Will I receive a confirmation email after selecting a timeslot for the aptitude interview for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, as soon as you have selected a time slot, you can think of it as confirmed \u2013 there will be no additional email confirming your timeslot. You will receive your personal Zoom link at least 12 hours in advance to your interview.",
        "request_id": "ead46cedc1eac2e3ee7d0ce753be1331"
    },
    {
        "id": "94157a07-36f2-433a-8ec3-d1f78b1f7e13",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_387.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "Can students use a sheet of paper and a pen during the exam?",
        "answer": "Yes, students will be allowed to use a paper and pen during the exam.",
        "request_id": "573c793b4f7df4ba3aa452509cf93dfb"
    },
    {
        "id": "7e641981-2fa5-41c9-a519-937f63a2023d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_387.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "How many questions will there be in the exam?",
        "answer": "There will be 35 questions in the exam.",
        "request_id": "573c793b4f7df4ba3aa452509cf93dfb"
    },
    {
        "id": "e8fa513d-e6d4-42ba-8929-f5e6371382a5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_387.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "How long will the exam last?",
        "answer": "The exam will last for 90 minutes.",
        "request_id": "573c793b4f7df4ba3aa452509cf93dfb"
    },
    {
        "id": "e4d087d8-aaab-4ff6-b7ca-877a8dffc685",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_387.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "How should students choose the option about off-site or on-site for the exam?",
        "answer": "Students should choose the option about off-site or on-site on the moodle exam page, not via an email.",
        "request_id": "573c793b4f7df4ba3aa452509cf93dfb"
    },
    {
        "id": "f6b514b7-a161-4dcd-8986-7727155a7f59",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_388.txt",
        "created": 1737369231,
        "question": "What should I do if I am having difficulty processing my aptitude test fee for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "For completing the payment, you need to go through the off campus DEMO exam. In there, you will find instructions on downloading proctorio and payment.",
        "request_id": "be57c3d65f184acc01d855cf18dac65d"
    },
    {
        "id": "603207c2-f0de-4ac0-85a4-27568ebd8c6b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_388.txt",
        "created": 1737369231,
        "question": "What happens if I am unable to process the payment for the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You will be moved to the second exam date.",
        "request_id": "be57c3d65f184acc01d855cf18dac65d"
    },
    {
        "id": "ac56cb1a-548a-42d4-ac46-2751e9b4f227",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_388.txt",
        "created": 1737369231,
        "question": "When is the second exam date for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second exam date is on July 16th.",
        "request_id": "be57c3d65f184acc01d855cf18dac65d"
    },
    {
        "id": "84fcdc46-b418-4fe7-bb2f-c8563e35b688",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_388.txt",
        "created": 1737369231,
        "question": "What should I do if I have not yet received an invitation to the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "If you did not yet hear back from the university and were not declined either, you should await further feedback regarding your application in the coming weeks. The university will finish checking the remaining applicants and invite you to the second test, should all your documents suffice. You do not need to worry about the exam tomorrow.",
        "request_id": "be57c3d65f184acc01d855cf18dac65d"
    },
    {
        "id": "af762162-7d04-4b72-8e7d-d794f5ba2ef9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_388.txt",
        "created": 1737369231,
        "question": "What happens if I have already received an invitation to the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "If you already received an invitation to the test, the test is still being held as scheduled. You should ignore the email about the second test date.",
        "request_id": "be57c3d65f184acc01d855cf18dac65d"
    },
    {
        "id": "3d77904f-ea91-4027-b64c-170652b623c3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_389.txt",
        "created": 1737369242,
        "question": "What happens if an applicant cannot attend the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM due to illness?",
        "answer": "The applicant will be moved to the second test date.",
        "request_id": "b83a7236d2dab2d27e8c3e1387672981"
    },
    {
        "id": "701475dd-8ea4-4c4c-aff7-f597081e487a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_389.txt",
        "created": 1737369242,
        "question": "When is the second test date for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The second test date is on July 16th.",
        "request_id": "b83a7236d2dab2d27e8c3e1387672981"
    },
    {
        "id": "9f55a794-5021-4f69-87e9-7d1650b9ea67",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_389.txt",
        "created": 1737369242,
        "question": "What is the procedure for applicants who have not yet received an invitation to the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "There will be a second test date on July 16th for those who have not yet received feedback. The remaining applicants will be checked and invited to the second test if all their documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "b83a7236d2dab2d27e8c3e1387672981"
    },
    {
        "id": "542df7da-e10c-4fa6-aaa8-6c0191b4aa0e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_389.txt",
        "created": 1737369242,
        "question": "What should applicants do if they have not yet received feedback regarding their application for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "Applicants should await further feedback regarding their application in the coming weeks. They do not need to worry about the exam.",
        "request_id": "b83a7236d2dab2d27e8c3e1387672981"
    },
    {
        "id": "388d1b40-8be6-41df-998c-8a9b60354185",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_389.txt",
        "created": 1737369242,
        "question": "What should applicants do if they have already received an invitation to the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "If applicants have already received an invitation to the test, they should ignore the email about the second test date. For them, the test is still being held on the original date.",
        "request_id": "b83a7236d2dab2d27e8c3e1387672981"
    },
    {
        "id": "8fefc9cb-890d-4d97-b90d-50caa1b0c2b9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_390.txt",
        "created": 1737369283,
        "question": "How can I complete the payment for the aptitude test fee?",
        "answer": "You need to go through the off campus DEMO exam. In there, you will find instructions on downloading proctorio and payment.",
        "request_id": "17b93f348f8aa64b875929993549a0b0"
    },
    {
        "id": "01f72ddb-f638-4b1f-9bcb-c6dfd94d2aaa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_390.txt",
        "created": 1737369283,
        "question": "What should I do if I have not yet received an invitation to the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "There will be a second test date on July 16th, from 10:45 - 12:15 CEST. If you have not yet heard back from us and were not declined either, please await further feedback regarding your application in the coming weeks from us. We will finish checking the remaining applicants and invite you to the second test, should all your documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "17b93f348f8aa64b875929993549a0b0"
    },
    {
        "id": "bc3ccb52-8f2e-4f82-986c-223b8957889f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_390.txt",
        "created": 1737369283,
        "question": "What should I do if I have already received an invitation to the test?",
        "answer": "If you already received an invitation to the test, the test is still being held as scheduled. Please ignore the email about the second test date.",
        "request_id": "17b93f348f8aa64b875929993549a0b0"
    },
    {
        "id": "3b350e01-8c66-48ce-8067-6a3e3d6275e4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_391.txt",
        "created": 1737369291,
        "question": "Can I take the aptitude test on the second test date on July 16th, instead of the initial date on June 26th?",
        "answer": "If this is the case, we will move you to the second test date. You will receive an invitation email again.",
        "request_id": "8b395aefb972bf1a63eff972e84d1936"
    },
    {
        "id": "acf6b5d3-e79a-4c26-8a89-2e10c8ca164e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_391.txt",
        "created": 1737369291,
        "question": "What happens if I have not yet received an invitation to the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "There will be a second test date on July 16th, from 10:45 - 12:15 CEST. If you did not yet hear back from us (and were not declined either), please await further feedback regarding your application in the coming weeks from us. We will finish checking the remaining applicants and invite you to the second test, should all your documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "8b395aefb972bf1a63eff972e84d1936"
    },
    {
        "id": "e929ac80-c742-4c38-8b6c-eaf1f9c13696",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_391.txt",
        "created": 1737369291,
        "question": "What if I already received an invitation to the test on June 26th?",
        "answer": "If you already received an invitation to the test tomorrow, please ignore this email. For you, the test is still being held tomorrow.",
        "request_id": "8b395aefb972bf1a63eff972e84d1936"
    },
    {
        "id": "b1e568bd-d4d4-45c7-bdf0-b9f3ca0e5d1a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_392.txt",
        "created": 1737369300,
        "question": "How many questions will there be in the exam?",
        "answer": "There will be 35 questions.",
        "request_id": "f4b753574e28129fd1dbf52233e306c6"
    },
    {
        "id": "b034a855-eb38-4f34-a66c-47865716cc58",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_392.txt",
        "created": 1737369300,
        "question": "How long will the exam last?",
        "answer": "The exam will last 90 minutes.",
        "request_id": "f4b753574e28129fd1dbf52233e306c6"
    },
    {
        "id": "d276df11-f783-4542-836c-fa4ba44f1b36",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_392.txt",
        "created": 1737369300,
        "question": "How should I select my exam option?",
        "answer": "Please choose the option about off-site or on-site on the moodle exam page, not via an email.",
        "request_id": "f4b753574e28129fd1dbf52233e306c6"
    },
    {
        "id": "6faab963-e045-42a7-8107-db8350788304",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_393.txt",
        "created": 1737369305,
        "question": "Why can't I see the exam option on my Moodle page?",
        "answer": "You need to log in with the login sent to you by Moodle for this test. If you can\u2019t find the credentials, they can be sent to you again.",
        "request_id": "9175af411657b4d02bb722aacbf138cd"
    },
    {
        "id": "544ed46b-0eb0-4832-b7bc-026e318ee720",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_393.txt",
        "created": 1737369305,
        "question": "What should I do if I can't find my Moodle login credentials?",
        "answer": "You should contact the support team, who can resend the credentials to you.",
        "request_id": "9175af411657b4d02bb722aacbf138cd"
    },
    {
        "id": "ea138bd1-9b51-4e0a-9ca2-5eb3bb7fea9a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_393.txt",
        "created": 1737369305,
        "question": "How do I select my exam option for the TUM AIS course?",
        "answer": "You should choose the option about off-site or on-site on the Moodle exam page, not via an email.",
        "request_id": "9175af411657b4d02bb722aacbf138cd"
    },
    {
        "id": "e03a3965-b68d-4b8b-93cd-455aa1ed42a1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_393.txt",
        "created": 1737369305,
        "question": "What should I do if I still can't access the exam after trying different sign-in options?",
        "answer": "You should contact the support team for further assistance.",
        "request_id": "9175af411657b4d02bb722aacbf138cd"
    },
    {
        "id": "cf8b0074-5b28-44fa-96eb-aa924adff213",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_394.txt",
        "created": 1737369312,
        "question": "What happens if an applicant for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM has not yet received an invitation to the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "There will be a second test date on July 16th, from 10:45 - 12:15 CEST. Applicants who did not yet hear back from the university (and were not declined either), should await further feedback regarding their application in the coming weeks. The university will finish checking the remaining applicants and invite them to the second test, should all their documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "3b371b0812d949ca68b6204a82ddc04b"
    },
    {
        "id": "eadfcc2d-2991-425e-bda0-1609678e51cd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_394.txt",
        "created": 1737369312,
        "question": "What should an applicant do if they have not received feedback from the university about their application for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "Applicants should await further feedback regarding their application in the coming weeks from the university. The university will finish checking the remaining applicants and invite them to the second test, should all their documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "3b371b0812d949ca68b6204a82ddc04b"
    },
    {
        "id": "9339c07d-fd67-44e0-af60-8f68fab5df6f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_394.txt",
        "created": 1737369312,
        "question": "What should an applicant do if they have already received an invitation to the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "If the applicant has already received an invitation to the test, they should ignore the email about the second test date. For them, the test is still being held on the originally scheduled date.",
        "request_id": "3b371b0812d949ca68b6204a82ddc04b"
    },
    {
        "id": "e83418de-76e7-40f5-8778-7b317ee6ddd3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_395.txt",
        "created": 1737369326,
        "question": "What is the new date for the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The new date for the aptitude test is July 16th.",
        "request_id": "66f82749b6ae4f365499dc004df6a0a9"
    },
    {
        "id": "6462771c-6f34-4aee-af34-a2c7988b7640",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_395.txt",
        "created": 1737369326,
        "question": "What should applicants do if they have not yet received an invitation to the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Applicants who have not yet received an invitation should await further feedback regarding their application in the coming weeks. They will be invited to the second test, should all their documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "66f82749b6ae4f365499dc004df6a0a9"
    },
    {
        "id": "95e34464-db4e-4a27-bd43-078512ee1a43",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_395.txt",
        "created": 1737369326,
        "question": "What should applicants do if they have already received an invitation to the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Applicants who have already received an invitation should ignore the email about the rescheduled test. For them, the test is still being held on the original date.",
        "request_id": "66f82749b6ae4f365499dc004df6a0a9"
    },
    {
        "id": "1580355b-80f2-40b3-9e85-808ef183e96e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_395.txt",
        "created": 1737369326,
        "question": "Can an applicant request to be considered for the rescheduled test date if they have a scheduling conflict with the original date?",
        "answer": "Yes, an applicant can request to be considered for the rescheduled test date if they have a scheduling conflict with the original date.",
        "request_id": "66f82749b6ae4f365499dc004df6a0a9"
    },
    {
        "id": "ac231c81-d67c-4303-b6e1-859f7c8ba99c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_396.txt",
        "created": 1737369336,
        "question": "Is it possible to reschedule the aptitude test for July 17th?",
        "answer": "The next available date is July 16. If the originally scheduled date is not feasible, the test can be rescheduled for July 16.",
        "request_id": "35f299448ef532fd852cba7d8faa762d"
    },
    {
        "id": "9ecb34a3-6d5c-467e-9b0c-fd88377c1aee",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_396.txt",
        "created": 1737369336,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "The test will be conducted in English language and span 90 minutes. You will be asked to answer multiple-choice questions (out of multiple different answers, only one is correct). The topics will span: Politics and [REDACTED], Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, Engineering and [REDACTED]. During the test, you are allowed to use a calculator.",
        "request_id": "35f299448ef532fd852cba7d8faa762d"
    },
    {
        "id": "0bb7ee73-5d4b-41b8-9aa2-7d04898939d5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_396.txt",
        "created": 1737369336,
        "question": "How will the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society be conducted?",
        "answer": "The test for the winter semester 2024/25 will be held online. You will receive the link to the test a few days in advance to make yourself familiar with the setup. During the test, you will be monitored via an automated proctoring software. Participation using the proctoring program will demand a fee of 25$.",
        "request_id": "35f299448ef532fd852cba7d8faa762d"
    },
    {
        "id": "82d10f43-f874-4bb6-b411-761b73177678",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_396.txt",
        "created": 1737369336,
        "question": "What should I do if I do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure?",
        "answer": "If you do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure, please reach out to [REDACTED]@sot.tum.de by Friday, June 21st, 23:59 PM.",
        "request_id": "35f299448ef532fd852cba7d8faa762d"
    },
    {
        "id": "e21f3b3c-eadf-495c-b5f1-1fb5b8f45080",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_397.txt",
        "created": 1737369349,
        "question": "Why can't I access the moodle exam for the TUM Master AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "You need to log in with the login sent to you by moodle for this test. If you can\u2019t find the credentials, they can be sent to you again.",
        "request_id": "9d5b472d94044601a8b51459a6e6eae5"
    },
    {
        "id": "0803f93e-6420-46dc-9d9f-770b1fd47e0f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_397.txt",
        "created": 1737369349,
        "question": "What could be the reason for not seeing the exam option on my moodle page?",
        "answer": "You might be logging in with your normal TUM credentials instead of the specific login sent to you by moodle for this test.",
        "request_id": "9d5b472d94044601a8b51459a6e6eae5"
    },
    {
        "id": "1a806a0c-5b91-4e8c-a4a1-4bbba8643547",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_398.txt",
        "created": 1737369356,
        "question": "Where should I choose the option about off-site or on-site for the exam?",
        "answer": "Please choose the option about off-site or on-site on the moodle exam page, not via an email to me. Please look for 'Select your exam option here'.",
        "request_id": "8e6ae08ab8276d50b3be1b604cd39399"
    },
    {
        "id": "9f208160-ecfb-402c-916b-c5f8ba5f416c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_401.txt",
        "created": 1737369085,
        "question": "Why was my application for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM rejected even though I am a student at TUM and all my transcripts are from the TUM?",
        "answer": "Your application was rejected because you uploaded your transcripts instead of filling and uploading the specific form provided by the university.",
        "request_id": "3bd825eba3e53f0c47b6f249296938e6"
    },
    {
        "id": "ee62a524-ae95-47b8-8bb5-f9d6fb5427f7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_401.txt",
        "created": 1737369085,
        "question": "Why have some applicants not yet received an invitation to the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "Some applicants have not received an invitation due to the large number of applications, which the university didn't manage to check in time for the test date.",
        "request_id": "3bd825eba3e53f0c47b6f249296938e6"
    },
    {
        "id": "82a30e81-cf0e-4d46-86d6-60ca4bb3baae",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_401.txt",
        "created": 1737369085,
        "question": "What is the plan for applicants who have not yet received feedback for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "There will be a second test date on July 16th. The university will finish checking the remaining applicants and invite them to the second test, should all their documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "3bd825eba3e53f0c47b6f249296938e6"
    },
    {
        "id": "0762b9f0-1ad9-4fef-8c4c-c91bc8707405",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_401.txt",
        "created": 1737369085,
        "question": "Should applicants who have not yet heard back from the university worry about the exam on June 26th for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, applicants who have not yet heard back from the university do not need to worry about the exam on June 26th.",
        "request_id": "3bd825eba3e53f0c47b6f249296938e6"
    },
    {
        "id": "8ef42168-77b1-4ec7-980a-f53d03b435ae",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_403.txt",
        "created": 1737369098,
        "question": "Will the exams for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM be digital or in person?",
        "answer": "Both an online and an offline (on campus) version of the test will be offered. The online version will require the use of an automated proctoring software (Proctorio), which monitors if somebody is cheating. The software also demands a fee of 25$.",
        "request_id": "c1124bb355dac1a72809610fbc9e1d79"
    },
    {
        "id": "1bf646e2-9620-45ca-af0c-a7388649fa6d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_403.txt",
        "created": 1737369098,
        "question": "What is the plan for applicants who have not yet received an invitation to the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "There will be a second test date on July 16th, from 10:45 - 12:15 CEST. The remaining applicants will be checked and invited to the second test, should all their documents suffice.",
        "request_id": "c1124bb355dac1a72809610fbc9e1d79"
    },
    {
        "id": "0a225421-5139-41de-bc54-624c3de2dc37",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_404.txt",
        "created": 1737369105,
        "question": "Where should I choose the option about off-site or on-site for the exam?",
        "answer": "You should choose the option about off-site or on-site on the moodle exam page, not via an email.",
        "request_id": "abebabdfe95451112d43ea048215b76c"
    },
    {
        "id": "30b5cd0a-c085-48a6-a3eb-00b4f5250536",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_405.txt",
        "created": 1737369109,
        "question": "Why can't I see the exam option on my Moodle page for the TUM AIS course?",
        "answer": "You should have been enrolled in the Moodle exam and should be able to access it through the provided link. If you are still having issues, it might be due to the way you are logging in. Try using a different sign-in option.",
        "request_id": "c2d3a4d4c990190d05f71fc9d89ae29c"
    },
    {
        "id": "f2afec76-5d8a-4886-898f-75f7c838793c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_405.txt",
        "created": 1737369109,
        "question": "How should I select my exam option for the TUM AIS course?",
        "answer": "You should select your exam option on the Moodle exam page, not via an email.",
        "request_id": "c2d3a4d4c990190d05f71fc9d89ae29c"
    },
    {
        "id": "274cbfe9-d84c-49b3-b8b2-5d4e59f1a22b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_407.txt",
        "created": 1737369116,
        "question": "Do I need to bring my own laptop for the TUM AI in Society - aptitude test and also need to download Proctorio?",
        "answer": "The test will be in paper form, so you do not need to bring a laptop or download/pay for Proctorio.",
        "request_id": "4bccea70ec7ff8ae24cf8e1195af5b23"
    },
    {
        "id": "f4e5a8e6-49c1-4555-b2c1-8622820a2ff4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_409.txt",
        "created": 1737369121,
        "question": "What happens to the applicants who have not received an invitation to the test for the Master AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The program received many applications and have not finished checking all of them. They plan to have a second date for the test and will invite these applicants once their documents have been checked. No one will be disadvantaged.",
        "request_id": "4bc189dd91842751fd5ae8cc6bc26eda"
    },
    {
        "id": "3047a1c7-d9db-4d9d-a8f1-b9c5c649395b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_413.txt",
        "created": 1737369130,
        "question": "Does the aptitude test for the TUM Master AI in Society take place online?",
        "answer": "Yes, there is an online version of the aptitude test, as well as an in-person version for applicants who are in Munich.",
        "request_id": "c60d4158295fada862e90a98e1f34ac5"
    },
    {
        "id": "9201af80-f924-48f3-b326-4663cfd1d9e4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_413.txt",
        "created": 1737369130,
        "question": "When will I receive the invitation email with all the details for the second date of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You will receive the invitation email with all the details for the second date of the aptitude test soon. Patience is requested.",
        "request_id": "c60d4158295fada862e90a98e1f34ac5"
    },
    {
        "id": "73886a7a-8e2d-4a56-9ff1-9dc989a5b195",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_416.txt",
        "created": 1737369138,
        "question": "Why is the exam not showing up on my moodle page?",
        "answer": "You have been enrolled in the moodle exam, so it should work. You should try accessing it through the link: https://exam.moodle.tum.de. When you open the link, you should see two options. Try the different sign-in option from the one you used up until now.",
        "request_id": "4c37d5b36ad0a6ac885469aea63c2f33"
    },
    {
        "id": "bd5b58dd-bf5b-41d1-9174-4bb58e7152d8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_416.txt",
        "created": 1737369138,
        "question": "How should I choose the option about off-site or on-site for the exam?",
        "answer": "You should choose the option about off-site or on-site on the moodle exam page, not via an email. Look for 'Select your exam option here'.",
        "request_id": "4c37d5b36ad0a6ac885469aea63c2f33"
    },
    {
        "id": "2a339bfe-dfc8-498f-89de-a9c8ba3c35bb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_417.txt",
        "created": 1737369145,
        "question": "Why don't I have an option for an exam on my moodle page?",
        "answer": "You have been enrolled in the moodle exam, so everything should work. You should access it through the following link: https://exam.moodle.tum.de.",
        "request_id": "20f9f77c52a66623ca1a22fc97f865ea"
    },
    {
        "id": "fed422f1-9925-4e6a-aad7-4e99b0057532",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_417.txt",
        "created": 1737369145,
        "question": "How should I choose the option about off-site or on-site for the exam?",
        "answer": "You should choose the option about off-site or on-site on the moodle exam page, not via an email.",
        "request_id": "20f9f77c52a66623ca1a22fc97f865ea"
    },
    {
        "id": "b9f6a597-0c87-4ac2-8c73-2e87ee3f643c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_418.txt",
        "created": 1737369150,
        "question": "Can I request another appointment for the aptitude test since I have my last exam for my bachelor program on the same day?",
        "answer": "In case you are not able to make it to this exam date, you can take the exam on the second test date, July 16th, from 10:45 \u2013 12:15 CEST.",
        "request_id": "fef49ec98be829b8a40ff2edf5ba94f1"
    },
    {
        "id": "bfdbffdb-4e65-4bef-b615-74016c7b8c0b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_418.txt",
        "created": 1737369150,
        "question": "Will I get another email for the log in data or should I use the same one?",
        "answer": "You will receive another email.",
        "request_id": "fef49ec98be829b8a40ff2edf5ba94f1"
    },
    {
        "id": "c1bb71fd-c011-4c19-93e3-d84af7c061db",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_419.txt",
        "created": 1737369158,
        "question": "May I be offered the opportunity to join in the aptitude test for the MSc AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Due to the large number of applications, not every single applicant has been checked yet. If you are admitted to the test after your documents have been fully checked, you will receive an invitation to the test in July. A second test date is being set up on July 16th from 10:45 \u2013 12:15 CEST for those applicants whose documents haven't been checked yet.",
        "request_id": "481df45fe5dcf46ec5397c49584d8df5"
    },
    {
        "id": "2550fef8-54f5-4a99-953c-46d40129701b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_420.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "Would it be possible for me to change from OFF campus to ON Campus testing?",
        "answer": "I have just taken out your group selection \u2013 you can select the correct group now.",
        "request_id": "656f4cbce0c1a3090edf7b3b0f04f5e4"
    },
    {
        "id": "79121f43-6a58-4362-9c9c-3a27a6065814",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_420.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "What are the options for taking the aptitude test for the Master's program 'AI in Society'?",
        "answer": "You might have noticed two options: on-site and off-site. Please choose one of these options. If you are present in Munich and would like to take the exam on-site instead of online, please come to the room specified for the test at the given time.",
        "request_id": "656f4cbce0c1a3090edf7b3b0f04f5e4"
    },
    {
        "id": "224b763b-dabc-4752-b5c0-57db30697ac6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_420.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "What will I be allowed to use during the aptitude test for the Master's program 'AI in Society'?",
        "answer": "For both options, you will be allowed to use a calculator, a blank piece of paper and a pen. Please also don't forget to bring your ID card.",
        "request_id": "656f4cbce0c1a3090edf7b3b0f04f5e4"
    },
    {
        "id": "947acddd-1b05-405f-8733-e34dda8abb52",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_420.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "What should I do if I have already been in contact with you about not attending the exam on June 26th?",
        "answer": "If you have already been in contact with me about not attending the exam on June 26th, please just ignore this email. There is nothing you need to do now.",
        "request_id": "656f4cbce0c1a3090edf7b3b0f04f5e4"
    },
    {
        "id": "00cba4ee-9631-4cb4-aaa7-fe8e6c611657",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_421.txt",
        "created": 1737369175,
        "question": "Can I request another appointment for the aptitude test since I have my last exam for my bachelor program on the same day?",
        "answer": "You can take the exam on the second test date, July 16th, from 10:45 \u2013 12:15 CEST.",
        "request_id": "20d51fa3acd6623a72d12a62f78e01a2"
    },
    {
        "id": "ffcaa79c-733e-47f2-a1e5-d198cc666ece",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_422.txt",
        "created": 1737369179,
        "question": "Could you give me some tips on what I should focus on and the depth of the knowledge that is expected for the AI in Society master's program aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You can find a section \u201cDetails about the test\u201d on our website. Also, if you received an invitation to the exam and a link to moodle, you can have a look at the demo exam to get a rough idea about the questions.",
        "request_id": "3b96ba9249dd56a9604aa3bdd9ffb5f7"
    },
    {
        "id": "61e5f2dd-cf9e-4aad-b230-65be693825ab",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_422.txt",
        "created": 1737369179,
        "question": "Could you please clarify the location of the on-site exam for the AI in Society master's program?",
        "answer": "The on-site location can now be found on moodle.",
        "request_id": "3b96ba9249dd56a9604aa3bdd9ffb5f7"
    },
    {
        "id": "d713e386-9750-41ff-bc0d-6d20498c9529",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_422.txt",
        "created": 1737369179,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the AI in Society master's program?",
        "answer": "The test will be conducted in English language and span 90 minutes. You will be asked to answer multiple-choice questions (out of multiple different answers, only one is correct). The topics will span Politics and [REDACTED], Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, Engineering and [REDACTED]. During the test, you are allowed to use a calculator.",
        "request_id": "3b96ba9249dd56a9604aa3bdd9ffb5f7"
    },
    {
        "id": "94f8ecb8-1f30-42d4-8f13-a81eea769738",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_422.txt",
        "created": 1737369179,
        "question": "What is the procedure for the online aptitude test for the AI in Society master's program?",
        "answer": "The test will be held online. You will receive the link to the test a few days in advance to make yourself familiar with the setup. During the test, you will be monitored via an automated proctoring software. Participation using the proctoring program will demand a fee of 25$.",
        "request_id": "3b96ba9249dd56a9604aa3bdd9ffb5f7"
    },
    {
        "id": "da079640-efb9-45c6-822c-98ead9776844",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_422.txt",
        "created": 1737369179,
        "question": "What should I do if I do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure for the AI in Society master's program?",
        "answer": "If you do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure, please reach out to us by this Friday, June 21st, 23:59 PM.",
        "request_id": "3b96ba9249dd56a9604aa3bdd9ffb5f7"
    },
    {
        "id": "72cc0595-0752-4b91-ba4f-da04678bf6a1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_424.txt",
        "created": 1737369198,
        "question": "If I have completed the on-site demo exam, do I still need to complete the online demo exam for the AI in Society aptitude test at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, you do not need to do anything else, besides showing up for the exam.",
        "request_id": "41d5888f645d74e390362bb8d6cf3ea4"
    },
    {
        "id": "0fdcbad3-e3bc-4d46-ae0c-f51a5eb40d16",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_425.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "What happens if an applicant is unable to make the $25 payment for the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The applicant can take the aptitude test in-person at TUM free of charge.",
        "request_id": "b60332bc8c3609d3bf7a56eac0b2dd13"
    },
    {
        "id": "22f32858-2dbc-48a4-8c65-bf5a92427cf0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_425.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "What happens if an applicant receives an invitation email to take the aptitude test but was actually declined by the system?",
        "answer": "The applicant will not be able to participate in the exam.",
        "request_id": "b60332bc8c3609d3bf7a56eac0b2dd13"
    },
    {
        "id": "c22a5866-1822-4631-8312-d39bea7acba5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_426.txt",
        "created": 1737369204,
        "question": "What happens if an applicant is unable to make the $25 payment for the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "If an applicant is unable to take the aptitude test online due to financial constraints, they can take the test in-person free of charge. However, this would require the applicant to be physically present on the test date at TUM.",
        "request_id": "96f772653abd976f043bcebb32d3d107"
    },
    {
        "id": "0698eedb-72b2-4e17-a311-7250f6006307",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_426.txt",
        "created": 1737369204,
        "question": "What are the details for the in-person aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The in-person aptitude test is scheduled on the 26th of June from 11:00 \u2013 12:30 at Marsstr. 20-22, 80335 M\u00fcnchen, Room 607 (6th floor). Applicants are allowed to use a calculator.",
        "request_id": "96f772653abd976f043bcebb32d3d107"
    },
    {
        "id": "dfc67dc7-cd21-4fb4-8d03-6a9e9323cef9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_426.txt",
        "created": 1737369204,
        "question": "Can an applicant participate in the aptitude test if they received an invitation email?",
        "answer": "Not necessarily. There can be cases of misunderstanding where an applicant is declined by the system and is not admitted to take the aptitude test, despite receiving an invitation email.",
        "request_id": "96f772653abd976f043bcebb32d3d107"
    },
    {
        "id": "8d4a0717-2328-4c52-a537-895557c54dfc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_428.txt",
        "created": 1737369216,
        "question": "I have applied to the Master 3 months ago, but I still didn't get the confirmation for the test tomorrow. Should I expect it at any time today?",
        "answer": "If you didn\u2019t get an invitation to the test until now, then no. Please await an invitation for the second test date.",
        "request_id": "d999ca8325ac71349cda2939847ea477"
    },
    {
        "id": "235d9130-b2e8-413a-b1dc-afa931fb98bd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_428.txt",
        "created": 1737369216,
        "question": "So, does it mean that I don't have the test tomorrow?",
        "answer": "If you didn\u2019t get an invitation to the test until now, then no. Please await an invitation for the second test date.",
        "request_id": "d999ca8325ac71349cda2939847ea477"
    },
    {
        "id": "2f68c93a-7092-41c2-97a6-de8df8515c2f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_429.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "I have applied to the Master 3 months ago, but I still didn't get the confirmation for the test tomorrow. Should I expect it at any time today?",
        "answer": "Due to the large number of applications, there are still applicants which we didn\u2019t fully check yet. Your application is unfortunately not fully checked yet. For these cases, we are planning a second test date on July 16th, to which you will be invited, should your documents pass.",
        "request_id": "4bad1ab6534a8bc28cea4fb96a05ed72"
    },
    {
        "id": "55227d39-8d0b-4a09-a03b-8f893b4c39de",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_430.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "What materials are allowed on the desk during the online aptitude test for the master program 'AI in Society'?",
        "answer": "A calculator, a pen, a blank piece of paper, and a glass of water are all permitted during the examination.",
        "request_id": "af930e4a8e8f1660454577dd7893f457"
    },
    {
        "id": "a487d903-d44a-468d-8d7e-c83ca9532df2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_431.txt",
        "created": 1737369228,
        "question": "Could you share where the in-person exam for the AI in Society program will take place at the TUM?",
        "answer": "The information about where the test will be held on-site can be found on the moodle exam page.",
        "request_id": "831cf5db93d48033834b2aca0ace1289"
    },
    {
        "id": "27dd9151-abeb-4522-aff6-3e5a3247b947",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_432.txt",
        "created": 1737369231,
        "question": "Am I able to use any calculator? I have a texas instrument TI-Nspire CX CAS.",
        "answer": "Yes, you are welcome to use your calculator during the test.",
        "request_id": "5f5abc76dd272854fe4d462095c13ab3"
    },
    {
        "id": "e3e0a348-7399-411d-aa93-1ff4b32c816a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_433.txt",
        "created": 1737369234,
        "question": "Could you please provide an update on the status of my resubmitted proof of successful participation in a practical project relevant to my course of study, including the module description worth at least 18 credits?",
        "answer": "We received your resubmissions, but still need to check them again.",
        "request_id": "7fe5439a92cb1f9ee3ac0e21fc0f5a50"
    },
    {
        "id": "2d5a5e6a-719e-433d-9239-a16c1936de5d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_433.txt",
        "created": 1737369234,
        "question": "Could you please confirm when I can expect to receive the aptitude assessment invitation email for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "For applicants we did not check until last week, we are offering a second test date option on July 16th from 10:45 \u2013 12:15 (CEST). Should your resubmitted documents be accepted, you will receive an invitation for this test date.",
        "request_id": "7fe5439a92cb1f9ee3ac0e21fc0f5a50"
    },
    {
        "id": "64d14df2-81dc-4264-b004-415b8f35094c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_434.txt",
        "created": 1737369240,
        "question": "Where will the in-person aptitude test take place?",
        "answer": "The in-person variant will take place at Marsstr. 20-22, 80335 M\u00fcnchen, Room 607 (6th floor).",
        "request_id": "521f11d2072402f99f8dd4d230c389cb"
    },
    {
        "id": "d590b25f-455b-4d5a-806b-8da17be52ffc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_434.txt",
        "created": 1737369240,
        "question": "What am I allowed to bring to the in-person aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You are allowed to use a calculator during the exam. Otherwise, please just bring a pen, as well as your ID card.",
        "request_id": "521f11d2072402f99f8dd4d230c389cb"
    },
    {
        "id": "97fd6f16-19ab-442c-ba85-5e12510fb89e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_434.txt",
        "created": 1737369240,
        "question": "Are there other possible ways to take the aptitude test apart from the automated monitoring procedure?",
        "answer": "Alternatively to the online test, there is an option to take it in-person. This will require you to be physically present at TUM on the specified date and time. In this case, you will write the same exam on paper and be monitored by people instead of a software.",
        "request_id": "521f11d2072402f99f8dd4d230c389cb"
    },
    {
        "id": "2efe0862-43c1-46fd-8d71-6580a595fc05",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_434.txt",
        "created": 1737369240,
        "question": "What does the online monitoring procedure for the aptitude test entail?",
        "answer": "The online monitoring includes the participant being blocked from opening other browser windows during the test, as well as being recorded through your webcam over the duration of the test. After the test, the recordings will be evaluated to check for possible cheating, after which the videos will be deleted.",
        "request_id": "521f11d2072402f99f8dd4d230c389cb"
    },
    {
        "id": "be86c79f-cba1-4968-847b-1dfbca537af0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_435.txt",
        "created": 1737369249,
        "question": "Why haven't I received an invitation to the aptitude test on 26.06.24?",
        "answer": "Your application seems to have been overlooked in the system \u2013 you were actually already admitted to the exam, but your status was mistakenly not set to \u201cok\u201d.",
        "request_id": "feb6ec1e63e8494266293ef51f550dd7"
    },
    {
        "id": "105de0d7-ccf7-4922-8126-4fd07444a2b8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_435.txt",
        "created": 1737369249,
        "question": "When will I know if I can take the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You have already been admitted to the exam. You can choose to take the test on the original date, 26.06, or on the alternative date offered, 16.07 from 10:45 \u2013 12:15.",
        "request_id": "feb6ec1e63e8494266293ef51f550dd7"
    },
    {
        "id": "63c8e8bc-c58a-434b-a032-36fdd35152a7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_437.txt",
        "created": 1737369256,
        "question": "Where can I find more specific topics for the TUM entrance aptitude test for AI in Society?",
        "answer": "You can find more specific topics on the website under \u201cdetails about the test\u201d: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/",
        "request_id": "989062df57256f743f68fe2f07465fda"
    },
    {
        "id": "9beb786f-89f3-4968-88be-9c4aa6f159bb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_437.txt",
        "created": 1737369256,
        "question": "Is there a way to get an idea of the final test for the TUM entrance aptitude test for AI in Society?",
        "answer": "If you received a link for the moodle exam, you will also find a few test questions to get an idea of the final test.",
        "request_id": "989062df57256f743f68fe2f07465fda"
    },
    {
        "id": "bbbbc912-f42d-48b5-875e-0471291fa662",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_438.txt",
        "created": 1737369263,
        "question": "Can a blank paper and a pen be used for the mathematics part of the moodle test?",
        "answer": "Yes, a blank piece of paper can be used to do calculations on.",
        "request_id": "55174941b308abbf0b313e268cbda51c"
    },
    {
        "id": "ec9f86ff-4009-4c1a-a22a-2e2241d3c7f8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_438.txt",
        "created": 1737369263,
        "question": "Does receiving an invitation to the exam mean that all other documents have been assessed as okay?",
        "answer": "Yes, if you have been invited to take the aptitude test, this means that all your other documents have been assessed as okay by the aptitude commission.",
        "request_id": "55174941b308abbf0b313e268cbda51c"
    },
    {
        "id": "f5378d9d-ade7-4551-81dc-0209f9281632",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_438.txt",
        "created": 1737369263,
        "question": "What materials are allowed during the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You will be allowed to use a calculator for this test. Other things will not be allowed.",
        "request_id": "55174941b308abbf0b313e268cbda51c"
    },
    {
        "id": "6a8151cd-2fec-433d-b32d-be3046f10590",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_438.txt",
        "created": 1737369263,
        "question": "What should be written in the 'grade' section for pass/fail modules when filling in grades for the application?",
        "answer": "For pass/fail modules, you should write 'pass' in the grade section.",
        "request_id": "55174941b308abbf0b313e268cbda51c"
    },
    {
        "id": "8f4a7e25-22c2-4949-a397-cd6fc5fefe52",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_438.txt",
        "created": 1737369263,
        "question": "Can individual projects or volunteer experience contribute to the practical project requirement for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Technically, individual projects that were not part of a university module can be counted. However, you would then need to provide an official documentation that those practical projects in total spanned at least 540 hours for completion (540h correspond to 18 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "55174941b308abbf0b313e268cbda51c"
    },
    {
        "id": "cd1a1d6d-9598-4637-8add-fccf0310bf06",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_441.txt",
        "created": 1737369281,
        "question": "When is the second test date for the online assessment?",
        "answer": "The second test date for the online assessment is on the 16th of July from 10:45 - 12:15 AM.",
        "request_id": "c804ec17b462533297a719ca3954f8d2"
    },
    {
        "id": "a6521c09-cd3b-4f71-a45e-d4be7deaa52e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_441.txt",
        "created": 1737369281,
        "question": "What should I do if I want to attend the second test date for the online assessment?",
        "answer": "Please let the sender know shortly if you would like to instead attend the second date.",
        "request_id": "c804ec17b462533297a719ca3954f8d2"
    },
    {
        "id": "332e4e76-0cb1-40ce-8e0e-a11a78ced6b1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_441.txt",
        "created": 1737369281,
        "question": "What should I do if I am unable to participate in the online assessment at the scheduled time?",
        "answer": "You should inform the sender about your inability to participate in the assessment at the scheduled time.",
        "request_id": "c804ec17b462533297a719ca3954f8d2"
    },
    {
        "id": "8f006d0a-594d-421c-ab72-3cbbe30ac8e6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_442.txt",
        "created": 1737369287,
        "question": "What should I do if I received an invitation for the online test for the Master's program in AI in Society at TUM, but I don't want to take it?",
        "answer": "In this case, you should just ignore the invitation.",
        "request_id": "08350f37dc391a5da18340323f5b4afc"
    },
    {
        "id": "4e252ace-67ed-426e-81c7-4b39f765adc0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_442.txt",
        "created": 1737369287,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the Master's program in AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The test will be conducted in English language and span 90 minutes. You will be asked to answer multiple-choice questions (out of multiple different answers, only one is correct). The topics will span Politics and [REDACTED], Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, Engineering and [REDACTED]. During the test, you are allowed to use a calculator.",
        "request_id": "08350f37dc391a5da18340323f5b4afc"
    },
    {
        "id": "69233868-07b7-42aa-9724-a4a95cde2d11",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_442.txt",
        "created": 1737369287,
        "question": "How will the aptitude test for the Master's program in AI in Society at TUM be conducted?",
        "answer": "The test for the winter semester 2024/25 will be held online. You will receive the link to the test a few days in advance to make yourself familiar with the setup. During the test, you will be monitored via an automated proctoring software. Participation using the proctoring program will demand a fee of 25$.",
        "request_id": "08350f37dc391a5da18340323f5b4afc"
    },
    {
        "id": "fdba3301-529f-46cb-aad7-29949b9e4b37",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_442.txt",
        "created": 1737369287,
        "question": "What should I do if I do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure for the Master's program in AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "If you do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure, you should reach out to the admission committee by the specified date.",
        "request_id": "08350f37dc391a5da18340323f5b4afc"
    },
    {
        "id": "f7c5a345-4e8f-4f82-a7dd-0f2bfadf8b06",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_443.txt",
        "created": 1737369298,
        "question": "What happens if an applicant is unable to make the $25 payment for the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "If an applicant is unable to take the aptitude test online due to financial circumstances, they can take the test in-person free of charge.",
        "request_id": "a066164af95afba51f74c20a187df0e8"
    },
    {
        "id": "eaa43155-6cc6-47f3-91ef-0574d86dd1fd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_443.txt",
        "created": 1737369298,
        "question": "When and where can the in-person aptitude test be taken?",
        "answer": "The in-person aptitude test can be taken on the 26th of June from 11:00 \u2013 12:30 at Marsstr. 20-22, 80335 M\u00fcnchen, Room 607 (6th floor).",
        "request_id": "a066164af95afba51f74c20a187df0e8"
    },
    {
        "id": "03ecf173-b29d-4ece-8932-96c82def9ebd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_443.txt",
        "created": 1737369298,
        "question": "What materials are allowed during the in-person aptitude test?",
        "answer": "During the in-person aptitude test, applicants are allowed to use a calculator.",
        "request_id": "a066164af95afba51f74c20a187df0e8"
    },
    {
        "id": "0d85772e-f716-4263-87e8-122d47060f7b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_444.txt",
        "created": 1737369305,
        "question": "Where at TUM would the test take place?",
        "answer": "The test will take place at Marsstr. 20-22, 80335 M\u00fcnchen, Room 607 (6th floor).",
        "request_id": "b5747177379c5bb8ee3be0a910f2750d"
    },
    {
        "id": "8bef4c10-a4e0-4309-b392-c00b879f036a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_444.txt",
        "created": 1737369305,
        "question": "Would the test take place at the same time?",
        "answer": "Yes, the test will take place at the same time, from 11:00 to 12:30.",
        "request_id": "b5747177379c5bb8ee3be0a910f2750d"
    },
    {
        "id": "bee6f1f4-bd8d-4d33-a6e3-c48e9cbfc0e6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_444.txt",
        "created": 1737369305,
        "question": "What is the format of the in-person test?",
        "answer": "The in-person test will be the same as the online test, but in paper form. You are allowed to use a calculator.",
        "request_id": "b5747177379c5bb8ee3be0a910f2750d"
    },
    {
        "id": "e38643c1-0149-4bee-a72f-1d7ad0459281",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_445.txt",
        "created": 1737369313,
        "question": "Could you please share more information on the types of questions for the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "The test will include questions on facts, thought questions (description of an economic situation, question about the consequences of this situation), and mathematical thinking where you will have to calculate. However, keep in mind that there are always answer options to choose from for each question. The level of the questions will be oriented towards the high school graduation level.",
        "request_id": "dd3bf877a0f499c0679365df45169256"
    },
    {
        "id": "83fbf881-e940-447a-8b81-95899e497b7c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_445.txt",
        "created": 1737369313,
        "question": "What are the alternatives to the automated monitoring procedure for the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "If you do not want to participate in the automated online procedure, you can alternatively take the test in person at TUM. You would have to be present in person on the test date. The test will then be written in paper form, and you will be supervised by invigilators as usual.",
        "request_id": "dd3bf877a0f499c0679365df45169256"
    },
    {
        "id": "6c159d10-6c66-46b1-ad01-baafaa349f79",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_446.txt",
        "created": 1737369322,
        "question": "Is it mandatory for every applicant to take the aptitude test for the TUM Master AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Yes, every applicant needs to take the aptitude test to successfully pass the selection procedure.",
        "request_id": "4faf7862ccdf23cc1a25db61bb8c432c"
    },
    {
        "id": "8c15a965-8038-4be7-b088-9b0d80b887ba",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_446.txt",
        "created": 1737369322,
        "question": "What are the alternatives if an applicant is unable to take the aptitude test online for the TUM Master AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "If an applicant is unable to take the aptitude test online, the only other alternative is to take the test in-person at TUM.",
        "request_id": "4faf7862ccdf23cc1a25db61bb8c432c"
    },
    {
        "id": "44a47b26-3d24-4e4e-9403-25bc7c1b25c5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_446.txt",
        "created": 1737369322,
        "question": "Does it cost anything to take the aptitude test in-person for the TUM Master AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "No, taking the aptitude test in-person at TUM is free of charge.",
        "request_id": "4faf7862ccdf23cc1a25db61bb8c432c"
    },
    {
        "id": "e4268b04-81e0-44dc-87cb-8f7cc8472ecd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_447.txt",
        "created": 1737369331,
        "question": "Can I take the online test on a tablet, more specifically, can I install the monitoring software on it?",
        "answer": "The monitoring software, Proctorio, does not work on tablets.",
        "request_id": "4c296f99536e1e9211b7845182ec4ad7"
    },
    {
        "id": "a27d08ab-16bd-4323-92c0-b3fdc7257a93",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_450.txt",
        "created": 1737369337,
        "question": "Does the aptitude test for the TUM Master AI in Society program offer alternatives to the online format?",
        "answer": "Yes, an alternative to the online test is to take it in-person. This requires the participant to be physically present at TUM on the specified date and time. In this case, the participant will write the same exam on paper and be monitored by people instead of a software. There is no fee involved in this case.",
        "request_id": "87fee7ad873b7ecaa275cbdd291bf16f"
    },
    {
        "id": "9a21e9b7-af7e-4ded-8241-0ed2c2e1601a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_450.txt",
        "created": 1737369337,
        "question": "What does the online monitoring for the aptitude test involve?",
        "answer": "The online monitoring includes the participant being blocked from opening other browser windows during the test, as well as being recorded through the webcam over the duration of the test. After the test, the recordings are evaluated to check for possible cheating, after which the videos are deleted.",
        "request_id": "87fee7ad873b7ecaa275cbdd291bf16f"
    },
    {
        "id": "e153ba25-f0a5-4ce6-8422-f68854251478",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_451.txt",
        "created": 1737369091,
        "question": "Is there a chance to take the exam on a different day and time than the specified one?",
        "answer": "Yes, an alternative test date is being offered for those who can't make it on the 26th of June. The second test date will be on the 16th of July between 10:45 and 12:15 AM, CEST.",
        "request_id": "c0ecaba60cb7014dcd5e0fefa0bdf97a"
    },
    {
        "id": "9560ed57-8c06-4209-9f39-6136f02bdf8e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_451.txt",
        "created": 1737369091,
        "question": "Is it possible to take the exam on a different date?",
        "answer": "Yes, an alternative test date is being offered for those who can't make it on the 26th of June. The second test date will be on the 16th of July between 10:45 and 12:15 AM, CEST.",
        "request_id": "c0ecaba60cb7014dcd5e0fefa0bdf97a"
    },
    {
        "id": "78064994-7325-44ef-83a3-ba76b31fc99f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_451.txt",
        "created": 1737369091,
        "question": "Do we have to pay 25 dollars for this exam?",
        "answer": "If you choose to take the test in-person by coming to TUM, there is no fee to pay.",
        "request_id": "c0ecaba60cb7014dcd5e0fefa0bdf97a"
    },
    {
        "id": "9c679d7b-6776-4d0b-95b8-4480e26e26d8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_451.txt",
        "created": 1737369091,
        "question": "Is it possible to take the exam without paying this fee?",
        "answer": "Yes, if you choose to take the test in-person by coming to TUM, there is no fee to pay.",
        "request_id": "c0ecaba60cb7014dcd5e0fefa0bdf97a"
    },
    {
        "id": "081ede60-4641-4baf-8fc9-f1e8b9b62a48",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_454.txt",
        "created": 1737369103,
        "question": "When can applicants know if they will get the link to participate in the aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Due to the large volume of applications, a second test date is being set up in the week from 15.7. \u2013 19.7., to which the remaining candidates will be invited. If an applicant has not received an invitation yet, this possibly means they fall into this category. The remaining invitations will be sent out in the coming week.",
        "request_id": "e9d5ee7245fa8c2b706831e422b4e97c"
    },
    {
        "id": "ad144e39-862b-413a-b8cb-71caaf1fe37b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_455.txt",
        "created": 1737369109,
        "question": "Is the aptitude assessment the last step which decides whether I am eligible to join the master's program or not?",
        "answer": "After the aptitude test, you will either be directly accepted, directly rejected, or invited to an additional interview if you fall within a certain point range.",
        "request_id": "f134a218af86614db844aa87c8f062a7"
    },
    {
        "id": "ed8f4807-07e6-4556-85b3-3076b4ad3fc8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_455.txt",
        "created": 1737369109,
        "question": "What is the format of the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "The test will be conducted in English language and span 90 minutes. You will be asked to answer multiple-choice questions (out of multiple different answers, only one is correct). The topics will span Politics and [REDACTED], Economics and Law, Statistics and Mathematics, Engineering and [REDACTED]. During the test, you are allowed to use a calculator.",
        "request_id": "f134a218af86614db844aa87c8f062a7"
    },
    {
        "id": "b7aac0ec-26ca-4272-898c-bfa55028039a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_455.txt",
        "created": 1737369109,
        "question": "How will the aptitude test for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society be conducted?",
        "answer": "The test for the winter semester 2024/25 will be held online. You will be monitored via an automated proctoring software. Participation using the proctoring program will demand a fee of 25$.",
        "request_id": "f134a218af86614db844aa87c8f062a7"
    },
    {
        "id": "9e3a23ed-fdd4-4a37-9cb9-fa88d35432e3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_455.txt",
        "created": 1737369109,
        "question": "What happens if I do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure?",
        "answer": "If you do not agree to partake in the online test with the automated monitoring procedure, you should reach out to the program by Friday, June 21st, 23:59 PM.",
        "request_id": "f134a218af86614db844aa87c8f062a7"
    },
    {
        "id": "575cc3c1-ea4b-459a-90a8-81a1242738a6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_455.txt",
        "created": 1737369109,
        "question": "What is the next step after my documents have been approved by the aptitude committee for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "After your documents have been approved, you will be invited to take the aptitude test for the study program.",
        "request_id": "f134a218af86614db844aa87c8f062a7"
    },
    {
        "id": "b7b51129-83d5-43d6-ba51-d4a611d02a7d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_456.txt",
        "created": 1737369122,
        "question": "Does the invitation to the exam mean that my other documents are okay and the projects criterium have been fulfilled in my case?",
        "answer": "Yes, if you have been invited to take the aptitude test, this means that all your other documents have been assessed as \u201cok\u201d by our aptitude commission.",
        "request_id": "d9912b7a773fddd0b970f7b4af879cac"
    },
    {
        "id": "d66b382a-d8b4-4cbe-8fb7-5c856cd20622",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_456.txt",
        "created": 1737369122,
        "question": "What is allowed during the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You will be allowed to use a calculator for this test. Other things will not be allowed.",
        "request_id": "d9912b7a773fddd0b970f7b4af879cac"
    },
    {
        "id": "5445fee9-2df8-4bc5-9341-1bea36396df9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_456.txt",
        "created": 1737369122,
        "question": "What is the specific time for the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The time for the test will be from 11:00 \u2013 12:30 German time (GMT+2) on June 26th.",
        "request_id": "d9912b7a773fddd0b970f7b4af879cac"
    },
    {
        "id": "71e7428d-1d7c-4577-9969-f7fcbb6aa02a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_456.txt",
        "created": 1737369122,
        "question": "If I have reuploaded a correction in TUM Online, will this suffice and the applicants will be reviewed again, or do I need to actually start another application?",
        "answer": "You do not need to start a new application \u2013 if you uploaded new documents, this application will be checked again.",
        "request_id": "d9912b7a773fddd0b970f7b4af879cac"
    },
    {
        "id": "22058ddb-0a46-40a7-9f08-b4ac0bed5278",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_456.txt",
        "created": 1737369122,
        "question": "Does the project document have to be translated by an official translator?",
        "answer": "No, your own translation + university signature would suffice for us.",
        "request_id": "d9912b7a773fddd0b970f7b4af879cac"
    },
    {
        "id": "ca8cb132-1c87-48bc-930e-ce229bfab4e4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_457.txt",
        "created": 1737369132,
        "question": "Could you please provide more details about the resources or references that would be useful for each section of the syllabus for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "Please refer to the section \u201cDetails about the test\u201d on our website for further information: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/",
        "request_id": "94d6cce6aeadd1edbabaa8b127efa2dd"
    },
    {
        "id": "6f65d102-0178-4aa7-b484-83700f7157b9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_457.txt",
        "created": 1737369132,
        "question": "Are there any recommended materials for the topics Politics and [REDACTED], and Economics and Law for the Master\u2019s program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "Please refer to the section \u201cDetails about the test\u201d on our website for further information: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/",
        "request_id": "94d6cce6aeadd1edbabaa8b127efa2dd"
    },
    {
        "id": "f10e3374-411a-4a67-b904-f9b770a7c3a8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_461.txt",
        "created": 1737369143,
        "question": "Is the letter of motivation considered in the application for the TUM Master AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Yes, the letter of motivation is considered in the application. If you are invited for an interview after the test, your letter of motivation will be the basis of discussion.",
        "request_id": "da376907b6d56dd90c76cf702643626b"
    },
    {
        "id": "576df89f-2f5d-4955-be17-c3fa8ab70c00",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_461.txt",
        "created": 1737369143,
        "question": "What is the selection process for the TUM Master AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The students are first checked for formal requirements by the admissions committee, i.e. whether all necessary documents have been submitted, as well as whether the submitted practical projects are sufficient. Those students who pass this stage will receive an email with an invitation to the test.",
        "request_id": "da376907b6d56dd90c76cf702643626b"
    },
    {
        "id": "6dff23fe-983e-4a7b-aa8b-e5fc03faf8a0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_461.txt",
        "created": 1737369143,
        "question": "Will all prospective students who have applied for the TUM Master AI in Society program receive the test link, or is there an additional selection process before that?",
        "answer": "Not all prospective students will receive the test link. There is a selection process where students are checked for formal requirements by the admissions committee. Only those who pass this stage will receive an email with an invitation to the test.",
        "request_id": "da376907b6d56dd90c76cf702643626b"
    },
    {
        "id": "3e01437a-0db5-4aa7-871b-a84b55636f44",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_461.txt",
        "created": 1737369143,
        "question": "What is the time zone for the test timing for the TUM Master AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The test timing is in Central European Summer Time (CEST). If there are any unclarities, you should orient yourself for Berlin time.",
        "request_id": "da376907b6d56dd90c76cf702643626b"
    },
    {
        "id": "668c1e63-546f-4323-8f7b-25ed6322a09e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_467.txt",
        "created": 1737369167,
        "question": "What is the minimum notice period for sending the invitation to the AIS aptitude test?",
        "answer": "The invitation to the AIS aptitude test should be sent to the applicants at least one week before the test date.",
        "request_id": "6c670fb3a4ad3f00a47cb1a7d4d915e2"
    },
    {
        "id": "40fec3e2-8859-496e-a8c1-98cca82e53b1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_467.txt",
        "created": 1737369167,
        "question": "What is the plan if the Moodle test is not ready in time?",
        "answer": "If the Moodle test is not ready in time, the decision is to send only the notifications that the applicants are admitted to the test, and then send the test links in the following days.",
        "request_id": "6c670fb3a4ad3f00a47cb1a7d4d915e2"
    },
    {
        "id": "8aada8ef-11a2-4719-984b-de1497254671",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_468.txt",
        "created": 1737369174,
        "question": "Will all prospective students who have applied for the program receive the test link, or is there an additional selection process before that?",
        "answer": "The students are first checked for formal requirements by the admissions committee, i.e. whether they have submitted all necessary documents, as well as whether their submitted practical projects are sufficient. Those students who have passed this stage will receive an email with an invitation to the test.",
        "request_id": "4a6a1b4936dfa75fb3a80385604970b1"
    },
    {
        "id": "05c39588-11ac-40cc-a124-64b1c2c612cf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_468.txt",
        "created": 1737369174,
        "question": "Is the test timing in CET?",
        "answer": "Yes, the test timing is in Central European Summer Time (CEST). If there are any unclarities, please just orient yourself for Berlin time.",
        "request_id": "4a6a1b4936dfa75fb3a80385604970b1"
    },
    {
        "id": "e2432356-229e-453a-9a5c-8d69aa19647a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_469.txt",
        "created": 1737369180,
        "question": "What materials are allowed during the online test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "You will be allowed to use a calculator for this test. Other things will not be allowed.",
        "request_id": "a6e0b98f0e9755769fbaa14a78ae708f"
    },
    {
        "id": "c800dbe9-55b2-4a84-8b78-e705466a4ccc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_469.txt",
        "created": 1737369180,
        "question": "What is the specific time for the online test for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The test will be from 11:00 \u2013 12:30 German time (GMT+2) on June 26th.",
        "request_id": "a6e0b98f0e9755769fbaa14a78ae708f"
    },
    {
        "id": "809e63b5-7cb8-4251-b67c-05a331979a12",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_469.txt",
        "created": 1737369180,
        "question": "If a document was not accepted during the application process, is it necessary to start a new application?",
        "answer": "You do not need to start a new application \u2013 if you uploaded new documents, this application will be checked again.",
        "request_id": "a6e0b98f0e9755769fbaa14a78ae708f"
    },
    {
        "id": "c4f23388-7dd0-43b0-a2b3-6726e6795d2c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_469.txt",
        "created": 1737369180,
        "question": "Is it necessary to have documents translated by an official translator for the application to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Your own translation + university signature would suffice for us.",
        "request_id": "a6e0b98f0e9755769fbaa14a78ae708f"
    },
    {
        "id": "e6e772ee-bd90-41f5-8518-034a86867da2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_469.txt",
        "created": 1737369180,
        "question": "Can a certificate of participation in a competition be considered as proof of a practical project for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "If you have a certificate over your participation, this is sufficient as proof \u2013 please upload it in the field for practical projects as well (it should be translated to English, however).",
        "request_id": "a6e0b98f0e9755769fbaa14a78ae708f"
    },
    {
        "id": "44e84bea-e342-4661-b21e-c2258f56cd66",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_470.txt",
        "created": 1737369193,
        "question": "Is there any announcement of the upcoming aptitude test details on the 25th that I missed, especially the time, test platform, and room setup requirements with video calls (if any)?",
        "answer": "An invitation email will be sent out to all people admitted to the test in the next days with all the details. Some rough information regarding the setup of the test has been published on the website. The test has been moved to the 26th.",
        "request_id": "2cc211757383cda63d9c4a872692fcd1"
    },
    {
        "id": "9be4f269-5cf8-4af6-9d5c-71b6ee1f6f80",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_470.txt",
        "created": 1737369193,
        "question": "In case an interview is needed, will it be online or personal?",
        "answer": "In case an interview is needed, there will be an option to do it online if you are not able to come in person.",
        "request_id": "2cc211757383cda63d9c4a872692fcd1"
    },
    {
        "id": "486d6415-cf65-4855-a240-b393e2cb36af",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_470.txt",
        "created": 1737369193,
        "question": "What should a work certificate look like for the application to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "A work certificate should be a letter from your previous employer summarizing and verifying your work with them. It should state your role at the company, the type of work you did, the projects you participated in, and the duration of your employment. It should be evident that you didn\u2019t write the letter yourself, i.e. the employer/their HR department could sign at the bottom, have their logo on the letter, or similar.",
        "request_id": "2cc211757383cda63d9c4a872692fcd1"
    },
    {
        "id": "903be444-414a-4855-bf9e-35ea7401634b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_470.txt",
        "created": 1737369193,
        "question": "Can I use my INSEAD MBA certificate and dean's letter as proof of my English skills for the application to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "You should upload your old TOEFL certificate, which you got in 2018. This will be considered as proof for your English knowledge.",
        "request_id": "2cc211757383cda63d9c4a872692fcd1"
    },
    {
        "id": "177cdb09-8c10-4ea5-8d9d-ea765e14ac12",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_470.txt",
        "created": 1737369193,
        "question": "How should I list my grades for the application to the AI in Society program at TUM if there isn't enough space in the provided template?",
        "answer": "You should duplicate the form, fill out as many rows as you need, and then merge the documents back into one for uploading.",
        "request_id": "2cc211757383cda63d9c4a872692fcd1"
    },
    {
        "id": "c1f6543b-8d83-4322-99f4-15a7743079bd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_471.txt",
        "created": 1737369209,
        "question": "What to write in the 'grade' section for pass/fail modules when filling in grades for the application?",
        "answer": "Since you are supposed to list your best-graded 140 ECTS, if you listed all your graded modules already (without reaching 140 ECTS), and are now 'filling up' the rest with pass/non-pass modules, then please just write 'pass' in the grade section for those modules.",
        "request_id": "c63383632989aeb3591ff1d82f5f32f0"
    },
    {
        "id": "a89dbf9d-fa3a-4622-bea4-cbe5c84f55e4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_471.txt",
        "created": 1737369209,
        "question": "How can I prove the projects that I did in the courses?",
        "answer": "You don\u2019t need to submit your project reports in order to prove your completion of the module. Instead, you submit your Transcript of Records as part of the application procedure (this module should then of course be listed in this Transcript), as well as fill out a form which states the name of the project module, as well as the module/project description. For this, it is sufficient if you translate into English yourself.",
        "request_id": "c63383632989aeb3591ff1d82f5f32f0"
    },
    {
        "id": "541a5523-d893-4b96-b3a9-c0f093180a8d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_471.txt",
        "created": 1737369209,
        "question": "Would a weekly research & review work in a course count as a project in the requirement?",
        "answer": "The admission committee will decide whether or not this will be counted. However, you are highly encouraged to apply with these courses. If the course is 5 ECTS, then the project would also be recognized with the weight of the 5 ECTS.",
        "request_id": "c63383632989aeb3591ff1d82f5f32f0"
    },
    {
        "id": "68c62d69-158d-4e26-aa22-c0e06fce7862",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_471.txt",
        "created": 1737369209,
        "question": "Can practical projects that were not part of a university module be counted towards the application?",
        "answer": "Technically, practical projects that were not part of a university module can be counted. However, you would then need to provide an official documentation that those practical projects in total spanned at least 540 hours for completion (540h correspond to 18 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "c63383632989aeb3591ff1d82f5f32f0"
    },
    {
        "id": "c3b5fed8-469b-4184-aa28-f587306f89a1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_472.txt",
        "created": 1737369225,
        "question": "What topics will be covered in the aptitude test for the Master's programme 'AI in Society' at TUM?",
        "answer": "The topics covered by the test can be found on the TUM website at the following link: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/",
        "request_id": "46c8af4d4d285973e70f5bc25b688ab2"
    },
    {
        "id": "9871be63-dc8a-4b4b-b9ab-ca206130af45",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_473.txt",
        "created": 1737369229,
        "question": "Where can I apply for a tuition fees waiver at TUM?",
        "answer": "For this question, I would kindly refer you to TUM\u2019s student information: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/support-and-advice/support-during-studies/student-information",
        "request_id": "5b3f5be7f85824f939b146202cf8b5b6"
    },
    {
        "id": "6c523240-88f6-4817-ba76-567d72e35a7c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_479.txt",
        "created": 1737369240,
        "question": "What type of proctoring has been decided for the test?",
        "answer": "Automated proctoring with proctorio has been decided for the test.",
        "request_id": "21bd5f9aee48bccdb2cdff3f49c49f72"
    },
    {
        "id": "7d12d607-d69a-4ec6-be18-03fb64414836",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_479.txt",
        "created": 1737369240,
        "question": "Why are the questions in the test considered too difficult?",
        "answer": "The questions in the test (primarily the technical ones) are now considered a bit too difficult because it will be much harder for people to cheat with the automated proctoring.",
        "request_id": "21bd5f9aee48bccdb2cdff3f49c49f72"
    },
    {
        "id": "1aa0e4cc-caa8-49a2-b8c4-cf2fdba15038",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_479.txt",
        "created": 1737369240,
        "question": "What is the concern if the test questions are too difficult?",
        "answer": "The concern is that the test will filter out too many people, since detailed instructions on how to prepare for the questions are not really given.",
        "request_id": "21bd5f9aee48bccdb2cdff3f49c49f72"
    },
    {
        "id": "ec28c65e-8837-457b-b2f9-33e6183d72e1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_479.txt",
        "created": 1737369240,
        "question": "What is the request regarding the test questions?",
        "answer": "The request is to look over the test questions again and propose easier ones.",
        "request_id": "21bd5f9aee48bccdb2cdff3f49c49f72"
    },
    {
        "id": "13f39a71-6c88-4af7-b188-1a7d1b9aa0a1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_479.txt",
        "created": 1737369240,
        "question": "What is the deadline for proposing easier test questions?",
        "answer": "The deadline for proposing easier test questions is by the end of the week.",
        "request_id": "21bd5f9aee48bccdb2cdff3f49c49f72"
    },
    {
        "id": "d8a8c5a4-90a0-4013-91f3-9ac6a0978a3c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_482.txt",
        "created": 1737369251,
        "question": "What is the concern about not having a Science background when applying for the program?",
        "answer": "The concern is about the aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "98cceb34fbcc4e3b13ea7c24051b885d"
    },
    {
        "id": "9b072b8d-c7df-4fbb-b3dd-dc57e4d40609",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_482.txt",
        "created": 1737369251,
        "question": "What level of programming languages does the applicant have?",
        "answer": "The applicant has a basic level of programming languages in Java, Python, HTML, SQL, and Javascript. They can read code better than they can write it.",
        "request_id": "98cceb34fbcc4e3b13ea7c24051b885d"
    },
    {
        "id": "3f3e8d08-8bd7-4852-9e1d-4b33c83c64d8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_486.txt",
        "created": 1737369264,
        "question": "What are the requirements for project descriptions in the AI in Society application?",
        "answer": "The project descriptions should explain what exactly the applicant did in the project. Most importantly, the descriptions should be able to show a) the practical (technical) aspect, and b) the interdisciplinary aspect.",
        "request_id": "216365b3ca2c54f6d9db53ae3397ac26"
    },
    {
        "id": "a5644558-a3fa-4cb5-b2b7-6d7099bd12be",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_486.txt",
        "created": 1737369264,
        "question": "Can working experience that just started in the same month of application be considered in the AI in Society application?",
        "answer": "No, working experience that just started in the same month of application cannot be considered, especially if there is no proof for the employment.",
        "request_id": "216365b3ca2c54f6d9db53ae3397ac26"
    },
    {
        "id": "a471c437-d0f7-4415-8265-cac984c23938",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_491.txt",
        "created": 1737369279,
        "question": "Would my involvement in the positive psychology program, aimed at addressing the high depression rate among university students, count as a practical project?",
        "answer": "Yes, your project can be considered a practical project, if it fulfils our requirements content-wise (i.e. it must have an interdisciplinary and practical aspect, please see the description on our website).",
        "request_id": "956f9808e7123aeadf13c39cf046e276"
    },
    {
        "id": "a2c13229-9cae-42fb-a4dc-a6d981e40970",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_491.txt",
        "created": 1737369279,
        "question": "How the duration and ECTS would be considered for this project?",
        "answer": "1 ECTS corresponds to 30 hours of work. So, for example, if you tell us that you worked for one month, we would calculate a 40-hour work week (or 20-hour if part-time is stated), times 4 weeks. In this case, it would be 160 hours. 160 hours would correspond to 5,3 ECTS.",
        "request_id": "956f9808e7123aeadf13c39cf046e276"
    },
    {
        "id": "d2b0f4ac-2656-4f94-952d-66668bc53330",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_491.txt",
        "created": 1737369279,
        "question": "How would the practical project(for example the positive psychology program ) be counted as the ETCS?",
        "answer": "If this project was part of your studies (i.e. it is listed on your Transcript of Records), this is sufficient as proof. We will refer to the credits given to the module (and convert to ECTS if your credit system is not based on ECTS). If you participated in this project outside of university, i.e. it is not listed on your Transcript, then we need another form of proof. For example, if this was an internship or a work experience, we ask you to upload a work certificate issued by the place where you worked on this project. It should state exactly what you did there, and how long you were involved.",
        "request_id": "956f9808e7123aeadf13c39cf046e276"
    },
    {
        "id": "bbc2d805-6f0f-4191-a75f-868857246829",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_491.txt",
        "created": 1737369279,
        "question": "Could the declaration of the second project would satisfy the demand of the proof of the project?",
        "answer": "The declaration for the second project doesn\u2019t include the length for the internship. If you can\u2019t get a declaration with duration in time, please just write the duration yourself inside the project description box, and reupload the form.",
        "request_id": "956f9808e7123aeadf13c39cf046e276"
    },
    {
        "id": "b86dd5ff-53f5-4c3b-90bf-244820bc10a4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_491.txt",
        "created": 1737369279,
        "question": "I have already uploaded the document of the 18 ETCS proof, but the system still showed that \"[REDACTED] sind eingegangen, wurden jedoch noch nicht vollst\u00e4ndig gepr\u00fcft.\u201d May I know when will I know whether the document would be examined.",
        "answer": "We are currently finishing reviewing the applicants\u2019 documents. You can expect a result in around 1 week.",
        "request_id": "956f9808e7123aeadf13c39cf046e276"
    },
    {
        "id": "328f25c3-c67d-4b72-a935-0ce57dae3e18",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_492.txt",
        "created": 1737369297,
        "question": "Does the aptitude assessment test on 25th June provide an online form or do I need to show up in person?",
        "answer": "The test will be held online. You don\u2019t need to come in person.",
        "request_id": "d7e597cad2d0f36f3c05b92afbceac76"
    },
    {
        "id": "2d37358d-71ac-478a-bcd5-6e53b032150b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_493.txt",
        "created": 1737369300,
        "question": "When will the test invitation information for the 2024WS AI program be sent out?",
        "answer": "The invitations to the online test will be sent out at the latest one week before the test date.",
        "request_id": "c78c3556f36fc28f11759d586ad9bd82"
    },
    {
        "id": "4e38d6d4-1f4b-4938-bcde-e52e40afc541",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_494.txt",
        "created": 1737369303,
        "question": "What should I do if I accidentally uploaded the wrong file to the 'Subject and grade transcript of studies to date' section of my application and can't re-upload the correct one?",
        "answer": "You should contact the team handling the TUM application website. They may be able to open up your transcript upload again. Alternatively, you can send the correct transcript to the team directly.",
        "request_id": "286af18f10103f36e1d3541d05200ff8"
    },
    {
        "id": "459e9f62-83aa-401e-aea9-f9f432d82c44",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_494.txt",
        "created": 1737369303,
        "question": "What happens if I can't re-upload the correct document by the deadline?",
        "answer": "If you can't re-upload the correct document by the deadline, you can send the correct document directly to the team handling the TUM application website.",
        "request_id": "286af18f10103f36e1d3541d05200ff8"
    },
    {
        "id": "fd6cd5e5-eed6-4b94-87c9-312f0bb919c9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_494.txt",
        "created": 1737369303,
        "question": "Can I re-upload a document after I've already uploaded something?",
        "answer": "Normally, the system blocks re-uploads after you've already uploaded something. However, the team handling the TUM application website may be able to open up your upload again.",
        "request_id": "286af18f10103f36e1d3541d05200ff8"
    },
    {
        "id": "e602f124-ac16-41d6-b6f2-e351505dc1f9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_496.txt",
        "created": 1737369314,
        "question": "Could you please allow me to upload a correct document?",
        "answer": "The comment for the rejection states: \u201cInterdisciplinarity aspect not fulfilled sufficiently. Projects should combine technical and social aspects, not deal with them separately.\u201d So, it is not about having uploaded a wrong document. It is an explanation for why we had to reject your application.",
        "request_id": "2195bcb2daf53b4f22b30b6f78d0b7b3"
    },
    {
        "id": "74d77e71-0008-46c5-8968-14ae2afdb675",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_498.txt",
        "created": 1737369323,
        "question": "What is the purpose of the proposed meeting?",
        "answer": "The purpose of the proposed meeting is to discuss the process of setting up an online test for the MSc. AI in Society program at TUM.",
        "request_id": "40327289de49e551f5659a94162a8338"
    },
    {
        "id": "31ba8391-c3db-4bed-ac5a-00a176e1374c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_498.txt",
        "created": 1737369323,
        "question": "What platform does TUM use for digital aptitude tests?",
        "answer": "TUM uses a specially set up Moodle platform for digital aptitude tests.",
        "request_id": "40327289de49e551f5659a94162a8338"
    },
    {
        "id": "0d2e8825-1664-4a1f-92c1-f5c835a3af59",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_498.txt",
        "created": 1737369323,
        "question": "What is the proposed timeline for the planning of the aptitude test for the upcoming winter semester?",
        "answer": "The planning for the aptitude test for the upcoming winter semester should start as soon as possible.",
        "request_id": "40327289de49e551f5659a94162a8338"
    },
    {
        "id": "89884a1d-2770-46f8-a2e0-809f021634bc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_498.txt",
        "created": 1737369323,
        "question": "What are the proposed time slots for the meeting?",
        "answer": "The proposed time slots for the meeting are: Thursday, 06.06. at 16:30, Friday, 07.06. in the morning, and Monday, 10.06. in the afternoon, for example at 14:00.",
        "request_id": "40327289de49e551f5659a94162a8338"
    },
    {
        "id": "0e77a32e-a3e5-4c4c-92ed-5c16b49d4ff2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_498.txt",
        "created": 1737369323,
        "question": "Who is the appropriate contact person for the planning and implementation of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "Dr. [REDACTED] from ProLehre | Medien und Didaktik at Technische Universit\u00e4t M\u00fcnchen is the appropriate contact person for the planning and implementation of the aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "40327289de49e551f5659a94162a8338"
    },
    {
        "id": "b9e9b91f-992c-4524-a2e3-6e0cee661152",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_499.txt",
        "created": 1737369335,
        "question": "What is the process of setting up an online test for the MSc. AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The process involves using a specially set up Moodle platform at TUM, which has been used for digital aptitude tests for about 2 years. A consultation meeting is recommended for planning and discussing the details.",
        "request_id": "8fde10ba7d0836fda59d51dec577979f"
    },
    {
        "id": "b3c10155-1476-477d-b810-cfd7b2690c14",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_499.txt",
        "created": 1737369335,
        "question": "Does ProLehre have any recommendations for online platforms to conduct the online multiple choice test for the MSc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "ProLehre recommends using the Moodle platform at TUM for conducting the online multiple choice test.",
        "request_id": "8fde10ba7d0836fda59d51dec577979f"
    },
    {
        "id": "8fcc75b5-00cc-4911-b4e7-904581ba169c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_499.txt",
        "created": 1737369335,
        "question": "When should the planning for the aptitude test for the upcoming winter semester start?",
        "answer": "The planning for the aptitude test should start as soon as possible.",
        "request_id": "8fde10ba7d0836fda59d51dec577979f"
    },
    {
        "id": "f8198dc4-7521-4c4f-bff9-1a210688ed59",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_502.txt",
        "created": 1737369108,
        "question": "When will applicants be notified if they are admitted for the aptitude test for the masters program Ai in Society?",
        "answer": "Admitted applicants will be notified at the latest one week before the test date.",
        "request_id": "fae99bad34f33b509ca87a94d17175aa"
    },
    {
        "id": "e2846fea-7282-4025-9a24-90df37b1febd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_502.txt",
        "created": 1737369108,
        "question": "Is it possible to receive some information about what will be assessed in the aptitude test for the masters program Ai in Society?",
        "answer": "The test will assess general knowledge of social science and technical subjects. More information has been published on the program's website.",
        "request_id": "fae99bad34f33b509ca87a94d17175aa"
    },
    {
        "id": "5fcef48f-341d-4cd6-9db6-b21b668b4b3c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_502.txt",
        "created": 1737369108,
        "question": "Is it possible to speak with the heads of the masters program Ai in Society?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can reach out to the aptitude committee head, Prof. Dr. [REDACTED].",
        "request_id": "fae99bad34f33b509ca87a94d17175aa"
    },
    {
        "id": "9c70fd1e-fa67-4834-a944-016af86717d2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_503.txt",
        "created": 1737369113,
        "question": "When will applicants be notified if they are admitted for the aptitude test for the masters program Ai in Society?",
        "answer": "Admitted applicants will be notified at the latest one week before the test date.",
        "request_id": "ed38e11c2753d40f2657de5df447431c"
    },
    {
        "id": "eaf56ed0-e22d-49a9-b777-b621050a2802",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_504.txt",
        "created": 1737369118,
        "question": "When will applicants be notified if they are admitted for the aptitude test for the masters program Ai in Society?",
        "answer": "Admitted applicants will be notified at the latest one week before the test date.",
        "request_id": "ce412c5a57527aedf84c6a308be41ac1"
    },
    {
        "id": "80879913-6157-43b2-9a0a-a92a796b8199",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_504.txt",
        "created": 1737369118,
        "question": "Is it possible to receive some information about what will be assessed in the aptitude test for the masters program Ai in Society?",
        "answer": "The test will assess general knowledge of social science and technical subjects. More information has been published on the website.",
        "request_id": "ce412c5a57527aedf84c6a308be41ac1"
    },
    {
        "id": "8e7f0c4b-fa35-489d-bd88-79a1580cf88a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_506.txt",
        "created": 1737369126,
        "question": "When will applicants be notified if they are admitted for the aptitude test for the masters program Ai in Society?",
        "answer": "Admitted applicants will be notified at the latest one week before the test date.",
        "request_id": "fbdee7cc944e612f74c39b8f2a4cc3cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "1f54ba18-a107-4f15-babd-a0e4c44ffb90",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_506.txt",
        "created": 1737369126,
        "question": "Is it possible to receive some information about what will be assessed in the aptitude test for the masters program Ai in Society?",
        "answer": "The test will assess general knowledge of social science and technical subjects. More information has been published on the website.",
        "request_id": "fbdee7cc944e612f74c39b8f2a4cc3cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "abb5786b-cfe4-449e-abd2-2a215b276717",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_506.txt",
        "created": 1737369126,
        "question": "Are there any specific books or resources to study for the aptitude test for the masters program Ai in Society?",
        "answer": "No specific books or resources were mentioned for studying for the test.",
        "request_id": "fbdee7cc944e612f74c39b8f2a4cc3cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "ec2cf0b9-0665-43f8-af7e-db3d5186e793",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_508.txt",
        "created": 1737369138,
        "question": "When will applicants be notified whether they are admitted for the aptitude test for the masters program Ai in Society?",
        "answer": "Admitted applicants will be notified at the latest one week before the test date.",
        "request_id": "acbca1ecccccc37e34af74b557d14f9c"
    },
    {
        "id": "ce8a568d-ebbe-4e2c-ad48-9f56123c88d1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_510.txt",
        "created": 1737369142,
        "question": "Could you provide me with an update on whether my application for the Master's degree in 'AI in Society' has been accepted?",
        "answer": "We received your application and everything is fine.",
        "request_id": "8882dfca0ed4ff089a259b2a4d74f3c5"
    },
    {
        "id": "eef42845-56ad-4816-9adb-6f23af619bc4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_511.txt",
        "created": 1737369147,
        "question": "What should I do if I accidentally uploaded the wrong file to the 'Subject and grade transcript of studies to date' section of my application and can't re-upload the correct one?",
        "answer": "Contact the team handling the TUM application website. They may be able to open up your Transcript upload again. Alternatively, you can send the correct document to the team directly.",
        "request_id": "07be619a98cb13c9ba37c1cb97573290"
    },
    {
        "id": "3f6e1bb0-b977-43d2-b04c-22b9e3c910a2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_515.txt",
        "created": 1737369157,
        "question": "What is the format of the online written test for the 'AI in Society' course?",
        "answer": "The online written test will be a multiple-choice test.",
        "request_id": "55350dac973b14b4130f9a43f0f39849"
    },
    {
        "id": "cd746b4e-6f1f-47bf-a3e4-a17446740551",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_515.txt",
        "created": 1737369157,
        "question": "Will the online written test for the 'AI in Society' course be in English?",
        "answer": "Yes, the online written test will be in English.",
        "request_id": "55350dac973b14b4130f9a43f0f39849"
    },
    {
        "id": "d18b98b2-3a91-4eb3-8f01-425719066265",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_515.txt",
        "created": 1737369157,
        "question": "What kind of concepts will the online written test for the 'AI in Society' course cover?",
        "answer": "The test will cover more basic concepts, as applicants are not expected to be experts in law and mathematics at the same time. Knowledge that will only be taught during the program itself will not be asked.",
        "request_id": "55350dac973b14b4130f9a43f0f39849"
    },
    {
        "id": "788d184f-d3e8-4a9d-88b8-69126c49a1d1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_515.txt",
        "created": 1737369157,
        "question": "Has there been any update on the contents of the online written test for the 'AI in Society' course?",
        "answer": "Yes, some information regarding the contents of the test has been published.",
        "request_id": "55350dac973b14b4130f9a43f0f39849"
    },
    {
        "id": "5dce4df5-288f-422b-8983-6696d4d87de5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_516.txt",
        "created": 1737369163,
        "question": "What happens if the VPD takes time well beyond the deadline of May 31st?",
        "answer": "It is only important that you submit to us a verification that you have applied for a VPD. It is important that you applied for it with all necessary documents by May 31st. If this is the case, the deadline for submitting the final VPD to us is extended to whenever uni-assist sends you the final document.",
        "request_id": "8662f8f874bdc50d30c0168922e7d009"
    },
    {
        "id": "47b0089c-edca-4709-a5a3-ea80e1c5f123",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_516.txt",
        "created": 1737369163,
        "question": "What should be done if the processing period for the VPD is extended and affects the ability to meet the submission deadline?",
        "answer": "You should apply for the VPD with all necessary documents by May 31st and state this in your application to TUM. The deadline for submitting the final VPD is extended to whenever uni-assist sends you the final document.",
        "request_id": "8662f8f874bdc50d30c0168922e7d009"
    },
    {
        "id": "61ccf203-ed3a-4bdd-816c-9b7317e74f30",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_517.txt",
        "created": 1737369171,
        "question": "Can a personal module handbook be accepted as proof of English language proficiency for the application?",
        "answer": "The module handbook can be accepted as proof of English language proficiency if it lists English-taught modules that together make up 15 ECTS or a bit more. These modules should be listed in a document, with the respective pages from the module handbook appended to it. A transcript of records should also be provided for reference that the modules were actually passed.",
        "request_id": "3ade34e2f04162c05e357bd69104b70d"
    },
    {
        "id": "1663c021-a788-4cd7-9a7b-d599203b3ec7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_517.txt",
        "created": 1737369171,
        "question": "What should be done if the module handbook is deemed inadequate as proof of English language proficiency?",
        "answer": "If the module handbook is deemed inadequate, you should list English-taught modules from your degree that together make up 15 ECTS or a bit more in a document. Append the respective pages from the module handbook to this document. A transcript of records should also be provided for reference that the modules were actually passed.",
        "request_id": "3ade34e2f04162c05e357bd69104b70d"
    },
    {
        "id": "ca50d3ab-a7f5-416e-8aef-4a69bf71fa1c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_518.txt",
        "created": 1737369179,
        "question": "Can I submit the English language proficiency proof after the application deadline?",
        "answer": "No, the English language proficiency proof cannot be submitted after the application deadline.",
        "request_id": "b4b904608b6df708f1dd02137c57291c"
    },
    {
        "id": "8560b842-2e10-4e5c-bd8a-1161dd9637b3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_518.txt",
        "created": 1737369179,
        "question": "Can English-taught modules amounting to 15 ECTS be considered as proof of English proficiency?",
        "answer": "Yes, English-taught modules amounting to 15 ECTS can be considered as proof of English proficiency, but only if they have been successfully completed by the end of the application deadline.",
        "request_id": "b4b904608b6df708f1dd02137c57291c"
    },
    {
        "id": "79007393-f200-42bf-9d74-fa60819acce4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_518.txt",
        "created": 1737369179,
        "question": "Can I submit proof of English-taught modules that I am currently taking after the application deadline?",
        "answer": "No, you cannot submit proof of English-taught modules that you are currently taking after the application deadline.",
        "request_id": "b4b904608b6df708f1dd02137c57291c"
    },
    {
        "id": "51694a04-0c9f-4847-b96e-cf4ab402a811",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_518.txt",
        "created": 1737369179,
        "question": "Do the modules need to be completed by the application deadline or can I submit them afterwards with my bachelor's degree certificate?",
        "answer": "The modules need to be completed by the application deadline.",
        "request_id": "b4b904608b6df708f1dd02137c57291c"
    },
    {
        "id": "a605959f-e80d-433e-909a-3b3bb9f03c2f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_518.txt",
        "created": 1737369179,
        "question": "For the practical part of the application, is it sufficient to just mention them or do you need a proof?",
        "answer": "If the practical modules appear in [REDACTED], that's enough as proof. However, you will be asked in a form to describe the projects in more detail so that we can also imagine something in terms of content.",
        "request_id": "b4b904608b6df708f1dd02137c57291c"
    },
    {
        "id": "34e2b4c1-a17d-4f44-af85-274fe6549051",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_519.txt",
        "created": 1737369190,
        "question": "Could you kindly provide me with a list of modules that are conducted as part of the Master of Science (M.Sc.) program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "Apart from the studyplan you can find on our website (https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/), an excerpt of your study documentation is being sent where you can find more details about the modules.",
        "request_id": "b6fa96cd4f24ec7aa8e668b5fcef83b7"
    },
    {
        "id": "5e052ed6-b513-4ce4-b147-1089f2074973",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_519.txt",
        "created": 1737369190,
        "question": "What are the tuition fees for the Master's program in AI in Society for EU students?",
        "answer": "Students from Germany and the EU study at TUM free of tuition. You can find this information here: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/fees/tuition",
        "request_id": "b6fa96cd4f24ec7aa8e668b5fcef83b7"
    },
    {
        "id": "1b428dae-291d-4548-b03d-6fb42551a832",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_520.txt",
        "created": 1737369198,
        "question": "Can I apply for the AI in Society course if I already have a Master's in Informatics from TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can apply. However, your application is still being assessed based on your Bachelor\u2019s degree. When applying to a Master\u2019s program, another Master\u2019s program is technically irrelevant.",
        "request_id": "2b033a0128d8a5e1bfc998c07a1827b7"
    },
    {
        "id": "f437af87-7586-48b2-9b50-2de8415ddb45",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_520.txt",
        "created": 1737369198,
        "question": "As an international student who already has a degree from Germany, will I be subject to the international tuition fee for the AI in Society course?",
        "answer": "For this, please contact TUM\u2019s student information center: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/support-and-advice/support-during-studies/student-information",
        "request_id": "2b033a0128d8a5e1bfc998c07a1827b7"
    },
    {
        "id": "17365204-b91b-4868-81c7-ae967a4750ad",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_521.txt",
        "created": 1737369205,
        "question": "What are the content requirements for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The program requires certain content requirements to be fulfilled, such as 5 ECTS from Mathematics/Statistics and 18 ECTS practical experience from a mix of technology and social sciences.",
        "request_id": "9e1920f6035ac22729fae91f2d9df90f"
    },
    {
        "id": "62ed561a-2a71-46be-be68-32829c6368a0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_522.txt",
        "created": 1737369212,
        "question": "What to write in the 'grade' section for pass/fail modules when filling in the documents regarding 140 best credits?",
        "answer": "If you are filling up the rest with pass/non-pass modules, then please just write 'pass' in the grade section for those modules.",
        "request_id": "4e2f9e74e8ed00bef2e2f7f86ad2f5a1"
    },
    {
        "id": "48430794-1027-4b1b-a792-ca53244d41fa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_522.txt",
        "created": 1737369212,
        "question": "Does the practical project need to be recognized with credits, i.e. does it have to be part of my university course?",
        "answer": "Technically, we can count practical projects that were not part of a university module. However, you would then need to provide us with an official documentation that those practical projects in total spanned at least 540 hours for completion (540h correspond to 18 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "4e2f9e74e8ed00bef2e2f7f86ad2f5a1"
    },
    {
        "id": "68fc32f1-7006-42e6-867b-8921560cde12",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_522.txt",
        "created": 1737369212,
        "question": "How can I prove the projects that I did in the courses?",
        "answer": "You don\u2019t need to submit your project reports in order to prove your completion of the module. Instead, you submit your Transcript of Records as part of the application procedure (this module should then of course be listed in this Transcript), as well as fill out a form which states the name of the project module, as well as the module/project description. For this, it is sufficient if you translate into English yourself.",
        "request_id": "4e2f9e74e8ed00bef2e2f7f86ad2f5a1"
    },
    {
        "id": "af90caaf-aa9f-4360-8705-1cc53b3f95d6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_522.txt",
        "created": 1737369212,
        "question": "Does a document have to be translated by an official translator?",
        "answer": "No, your own translation + university signature would suffice for us.",
        "request_id": "4e2f9e74e8ed00bef2e2f7f86ad2f5a1"
    },
    {
        "id": "7b534c40-b7ab-45d2-9b20-dae0c99f777a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_522.txt",
        "created": 1737369212,
        "question": "If I received a notification that the document was not Okay and now I have reuploaded a correction in TUM Online, do I need to actually start another application?",
        "answer": "You do not need to start a new application \u2013 if you uploaded new documents, this application will be checked again.",
        "request_id": "4e2f9e74e8ed00bef2e2f7f86ad2f5a1"
    },
    {
        "id": "032f5887-7c8c-4f01-bccf-f26ac7c10243",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_523.txt",
        "created": 1737369226,
        "question": "Do I need to complete the English language modules before the application deadline for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Yes, the modules should ideally be completed before the application deadline.",
        "request_id": "19db28c1fa0bb6475b4f7e0fc1e2d628"
    },
    {
        "id": "88f2b793-890d-42e1-92ab-8398d9e6a1be",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_523.txt",
        "created": 1737369226,
        "question": "For the practical part of the application, is it enough to just mention them or do you need a proof?",
        "answer": "If the practical modules appear in [REDACTED], that would be sufficient as proof. However, you will be asked in a form to describe the projects in more detail so that we can also imagine the content.",
        "request_id": "19db28c1fa0bb6475b4f7e0fc1e2d628"
    },
    {
        "id": "d68f0d18-1936-4167-aa12-02558992fb0a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_523.txt",
        "created": 1737369226,
        "question": "Can I submit the language certificate after the application deadline?",
        "answer": "We can only accept certain documents afterwards (for example, the Bachelor's degree certificate) - unfortunately, the language certificate is not one of them.",
        "request_id": "19db28c1fa0bb6475b4f7e0fc1e2d628"
    },
    {
        "id": "6c23468a-2665-4cd5-a20e-da256d69cc11",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_523.txt",
        "created": 1737369226,
        "question": "If I have completed English modules totaling at least 15 ECTS, do these also count as proof?",
        "answer": "Yes, if you have completed English modules totaling at least 15 ECTS, these also count as proof.",
        "request_id": "19db28c1fa0bb6475b4f7e0fc1e2d628"
    },
    {
        "id": "565c55ac-7071-4a2a-b6dd-2fec771de312",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_523.txt",
        "created": 1737369226,
        "question": "Does writing [REDACTED] fulfill the requirement for a practical part of the application?",
        "answer": "It depends on what exactly you did in the seminar papers. If no practical part in the form of, for example, data analyses or similar technical tools were used for the works, and it is, for example, pure literature research, unfortunately, this does not meet our requirements.",
        "request_id": "19db28c1fa0bb6475b4f7e0fc1e2d628"
    },
    {
        "id": "e0a608a3-9a4c-46db-a67a-0b5262ddbc32",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_524.txt",
        "created": 1737369241,
        "question": "Would my involvement in the positive psychology program, aimed at addressing the high depression rate among university students, count as a practical project?",
        "answer": "Yes, your project can be considered a practical project, if it fulfils our requirements content-wise (i.e. it must have an interdisciplinary and practical aspect, please see the description on our website). From your short description, it sounds suitable, but we would need a more detailed description of what you did there.",
        "request_id": "bcfa8c6e5a1ba3b43c9da90321220802"
    },
    {
        "id": "8e014c41-305f-4029-a63b-c3275f9827fc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_524.txt",
        "created": 1737369241,
        "question": "How would the duration and ECTS be considered for this project?",
        "answer": "If this project was part of your studies (i.e. it is listed on your Transcript of Records), this is sufficient as proof. We will refer to the credits given to the module (and convert to ECTS if your credit system is not based on ECTS). If you participated in this project outside of university, i.e. it is not listed on your Transcript, then we need another form of proof. For example, if this was an internship or a work experience, we ask you to upload a work certificate issued by the place where you worked on this project. It should state exactly what you did there, and how long you were involved.",
        "request_id": "bcfa8c6e5a1ba3b43c9da90321220802"
    },
    {
        "id": "cd2e7dc6-515c-421b-84b4-186be3348add",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_524.txt",
        "created": 1737369241,
        "question": "How would the practical project(for example the positive psychology program ) be counted as the ETCS? How would the time that I invested be counted?",
        "answer": "1 ECTS corresponds to 30 hours of work. So, for example, if you tell us that you worked for one month, we would calculate a 40-hour work week (or 20-hour if part-time is stated), times 4 weeks. In this case, it would be 160 hours. 160 hours would correspond to 5,3 ECTS.",
        "request_id": "bcfa8c6e5a1ba3b43c9da90321220802"
    },
    {
        "id": "a12e0586-e2d3-40da-a0c4-35d14afbe4a2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_524.txt",
        "created": 1737369241,
        "question": "The system said that \"we can only see the duration for one of your internships. Please also provide the duration for the other internship\". Could the declaration of the second project would satisfy the demand of the proof of the project?",
        "answer": "The declaration for the second project doesn\u2019t include the length for the internship. If you can\u2019t get a declaration with duration in time, please just write the duration yourself inside the project description box, and reupload the form.",
        "request_id": "bcfa8c6e5a1ba3b43c9da90321220802"
    },
    {
        "id": "afbf04fa-fee4-4836-8254-c1ed31cc1818",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_525.txt",
        "created": 1737369265,
        "question": "Does the practical project need to be recognized with credits, i.e. does it have to be part of my university course? Would individual projects or volunteer experience be able to also contribute to the requirement?",
        "answer": "Technically, we can count practical projects that were not part of a university module. However, you would then need to provide us with an official documentation that those practical projects in total spanned at least 540 hours for completion (540h correspond to 18 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "14300805fe4d454188eb8bdce7a25bbe"
    },
    {
        "id": "710acc00-f3e2-4977-b59d-6df4372e9d1c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_525.txt",
        "created": 1737369265,
        "question": "Can the project be part of a course or does it have to stand indiviually?",
        "answer": "The project can be part of a course.",
        "request_id": "14300805fe4d454188eb8bdce7a25bbe"
    },
    {
        "id": "e5f442a1-4649-46af-9a59-af505cac6992",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_525.txt",
        "created": 1737369265,
        "question": "If from my university, I do not officially 18 credits for a practical project in social science, is there a way to make up for this requirement?",
        "answer": "If it's somehow possible for you to officially document your projects with hours invested, we'd be happy to receive your application!",
        "request_id": "14300805fe4d454188eb8bdce7a25bbe"
    },
    {
        "id": "edba462c-d56d-4b8c-9ceb-cd4a7a35ac25",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_525.txt",
        "created": 1737369265,
        "question": "May I ask how I can prove the projects that I did in the courses?",
        "answer": "You don\u2019t need to submit your project reports in order to prove your completion of the module. Instead, you submit your Transcript of Records as part of the application procedure (this module should then of course be listed in this Transcript), as well as fill out a form which states the name of the project module, as well as the module/project description.",
        "request_id": "14300805fe4d454188eb8bdce7a25bbe"
    },
    {
        "id": "7b3c7bc4-4c61-4a44-847b-7bf69fbb46b1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_525.txt",
        "created": 1737369265,
        "question": "Does it have to be translated by an official translator? If I ask the university to sign an english translated version, would this suffice?",
        "answer": "Yes, your own translation + university signature would suffice for us.",
        "request_id": "14300805fe4d454188eb8bdce7a25bbe"
    },
    {
        "id": "f8d76954-f16d-4611-8eac-3bac0e496fe5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_526.txt",
        "created": 1737369281,
        "question": "Do I fulfill all the application requirements for the AI in Society Master's Program at TUM with my Bachelor's in Business, Economics and [REDACTED] (BESC) from WU Vienna?",
        "answer": "Regarding the number of credits, it would fit. However, for the content, you would need to briefly describe what you did in each module.",
        "request_id": "ee251dacc7bdc33072cee3637384440a"
    },
    {
        "id": "fe068e16-3dfb-4667-99fe-b785594fc413",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_526.txt",
        "created": 1737369281,
        "question": "Would my practical experience, including my Bachelor's Thesis, Project Courses in [REDACTED] and Innovation with Fraunhofer and RHI Magnesita, and a Project Course in [REDACTED] and [REDACTED] with Mayr-[REDACTED] AG, fulfill the 18 ECTS requirement for the AI in Society Master's Program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Regarding the number of credits, it would fit. However, for the content, you would need to briefly describe what you did in each module.",
        "request_id": "ee251dacc7bdc33072cee3637384440a"
    },
    {
        "id": "100d921b-1661-4a36-a158-5fd19e57c993",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_528.txt",
        "created": 1737369329,
        "question": "Does the practical project need to be recognized with credits, i.e. does it have to be part of my university course? Would individual projects or volunteer experience be able to also contribute to the requirement?",
        "answer": "Technically, we can count practical projects that were not part of a university module. However, you would then need to provide us with an official documentation that those practical projects in total spanned at least 540 hours for completion (540h correspond to 18 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "9561f3f40362634e42a1216f00b4ecd3"
    },
    {
        "id": "4bb5447f-99f6-4489-a99c-4f46316cd4df",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_528.txt",
        "created": 1737369329,
        "question": "Can the project be part of a course or does it have to stand indiviually?",
        "answer": "The project can be part of a course.",
        "request_id": "9561f3f40362634e42a1216f00b4ecd3"
    },
    {
        "id": "ba15a6a8-c09d-4007-8118-5d163084f027",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_528.txt",
        "created": 1737369329,
        "question": "If from my university, I do not officially 18 credits for a practical project in social science, is there a way to make up for this requirement?",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, as much as we would want to, we can't just let you compile an own project without an official documentation about how much time was spent for it. Please understand that we need to compare students' achievements universally somehow; this we can do by setting a minimum of ECTS credits, or, hours invested.",
        "request_id": "9561f3f40362634e42a1216f00b4ecd3"
    },
    {
        "id": "4bae5fef-8c02-49be-a3af-68f146541a1d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_528.txt",
        "created": 1737369329,
        "question": "May I ask how I can prove the projects that I did in the courses?",
        "answer": "You don\u2019t need to submit your project reports in order to prove your completion of the module. Instead, you submit your Transcript of Records as part of the application procedure (this module should then of course be listed in this Transcript), as well as fill out a form which states the name of the project module, as well as the module/project description. For this, it is sufficient if you translate into English yourself.",
        "request_id": "9561f3f40362634e42a1216f00b4ecd3"
    },
    {
        "id": "eb453222-7a70-4a1e-8903-f968940e2cd5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_528.txt",
        "created": 1737369329,
        "question": "May I know if there is a timeline on when we will be informed if we met all formal requirements, also on the final announcement itself?",
        "answer": "The test will be held online on June 25th. We will inform everyone about their admission to the test one week before the test at the latest. We will try our best to finish the decisions as early as possible.",
        "request_id": "9561f3f40362634e42a1216f00b4ecd3"
    },
    {
        "id": "70b73318-3de2-4cd5-97ee-e40875672805",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_529.txt",
        "created": 1737369348,
        "question": "I am lacking 1 ECTS in proof of practical experience for the M. Sc. AI in Society program. Can I compensate for this with my other practical experiences?",
        "answer": "The committee has agreed to recognize your practical experience in terms of credits. The content of your practical experience is now being examined.",
        "request_id": "e9aafe037328cb75e611e9cca983c424"
    },
    {
        "id": "a2db0fd3-63ab-4035-928b-710e0991fc57",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_535.txt",
        "created": 1737369363,
        "question": "Is it possible to submit the language certificate after the application deadline for the AI in Society Master's program?",
        "answer": "Only certain documents can be accepted after the application deadline, and unfortunately, the language certificate is not one of them.",
        "request_id": "95e81c87a17b9b6c06f2e74f18109155"
    },
    {
        "id": "1819bfa5-b95d-4ab6-9139-0e7058e46910",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_535.txt",
        "created": 1737369363,
        "question": "Can English-taught modules with a total of at least 15 ECTS be considered as proof of language proficiency for the AI in Society Master's program?",
        "answer": "If you have completed English-taught modules with a total of at least 15 ECTS, these can also be considered as proof of language proficiency.",
        "request_id": "95e81c87a17b9b6c06f2e74f18109155"
    },
    {
        "id": "ad18a0a1-ad36-4d07-bc8a-dd3f5e7e0985",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_535.txt",
        "created": 1737369363,
        "question": "What qualifies as the practical part required for the application to the AI in Society Master's program?",
        "answer": "The practical part depends on what exactly you have done in your seminar papers. If no practical part in the form of data analyses or similar technical tools has been used and it is purely literature research, it unfortunately does not meet our requirements.",
        "request_id": "95e81c87a17b9b6c06f2e74f18109155"
    },
    {
        "id": "aa792a45-7e96-4d0f-a8f2-19df88f646b5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_536.txt",
        "created": 1737369372,
        "question": "What is the documentation requirement for the list of best 140 credits for the Master of Science AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "For the list of 140 best credits, there will be a form to fill out inside the application portal. You will also be asked to upload your transcript of records.",
        "request_id": "7c8feac7aca61bb56a9960768d86dc67"
    },
    {
        "id": "74c5ce29-e030-4a14-8935-2983382e5f0a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_537.txt",
        "created": 1737369375,
        "question": "Could you please provide detailed information on the format and structure of the aptitude assessment for the Master of Science | AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "We will shortly publish more information regarding the test on our website \u2013 please check back soon.",
        "request_id": "4750e7e58966c99e0ae2a54f5d2c6988"
    },
    {
        "id": "763ad5d4-a989-43d4-82e8-47673dbbfcdf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_538.txt",
        "created": 1737369384,
        "question": "Can the INSEAD MBA certificate and dean's letter be used as proof of English skills for the AI in Society master's program at TUM?",
        "answer": "If you want to prove your English skills with a previous degree, it needs to be a degree conforming to EU standard durations (bachelor's: 6-8 semester, master's: 4 semesters minimum). With a 2 semester MBA, the requirement to prove English language skills cannot be met. Please submit a different proof of English language skills like a TOEFL, IELTS or other accepted test score as instructed.",
        "request_id": "f4aca95ba53daa4e80401b16924f9e2c"
    },
    {
        "id": "6f786f71-5d28-4390-afd1-0d0955d909dd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_538.txt",
        "created": 1737369384,
        "question": "How can I list all my credits in the application form for the AI in Society master's program at TUM when I have two bachelor's degrees and an MBA degree?",
        "answer": "In the list of credits you need to select the best 140 credits of the Bachelor you're applying with. This means the relevant subjects are only from the Bachelor in Economics.",
        "request_id": "f4aca95ba53daa4e80401b16924f9e2c"
    },
    {
        "id": "bdbbf618-245f-4c6a-9691-48cc7bb4b3c3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_538.txt",
        "created": 1737369384,
        "question": "What should a work certificate look like for the AI in Society master's program at TUM?",
        "answer": "There is no strict form on work certificates. Normally they are letters handed out by your (previous) employer, summarizing what the employee (you) did at their company (e.g. for reference for the person\u2019s future employer). It should simply state what your role was at the company, which type of work you did, which projects you participated in, as well as the duration of your employment with them. It should be evident to us that you didn\u2019t write the letter yourself, i.e. the employer/their HR department could sign at the bottom, have their logo on the letter, or similar.",
        "request_id": "f4aca95ba53daa4e80401b16924f9e2c"
    },
    {
        "id": "fe3a19bd-331d-4e09-9068-ea360abd6f98",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_538.txt",
        "created": 1737369384,
        "question": "Can I list internships or work experience as a practical project for the AI in Society master's program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes. In this case, please (additionally to the form) submit a work certificate in the field for practical projects, which states the duration as well as the content of your work. Since work certificates are not credit based, we will recalculate from work hours to credits (30 hours = 1 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "f4aca95ba53daa4e80401b16924f9e2c"
    },
    {
        "id": "2263dae0-5cff-47d4-9c4f-400733062a00",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_538.txt",
        "created": 1737369384,
        "question": "Will the interviews for the AI in Society master's program at TUM be online or in person?",
        "answer": "In case an interview is needed, there will be an option to do it online (if you are not able to come in person).",
        "request_id": "f4aca95ba53daa4e80401b16924f9e2c"
    },
    {
        "id": "84982108-c9b5-4a3a-83f4-3718f751d4e6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_539.txt",
        "created": 1737369398,
        "question": "When should the final VPD be uploaded for the 'AI in Society' application?",
        "answer": "You don\u2019t need to upload the final VPD by May 31st, but can upload it to us later, as soon as you receive it.",
        "request_id": "8e2d16723843bf6923dcd609a8379200"
    },
    {
        "id": "b06d6397-bf56-4480-9ee3-c048a248fbd6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_539.txt",
        "created": 1737369398,
        "question": "What is the deadline for sending full documents to uni-assist for the 'AI in Society' application?",
        "answer": "What is important however, is that you have sent your full documents to uni-assist by May 31st.",
        "request_id": "8e2d16723843bf6923dcd609a8379200"
    },
    {
        "id": "06237254-1ef0-4bc5-a268-f9d1cc46a495",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_539.txt",
        "created": 1737369398,
        "question": "What happens if the documents have not been received by uni-assist in full by the deadline?",
        "answer": "If we then discover that your documents have not been received by [REDACTED] in full by the deadline, you will be excluded from the application process.",
        "request_id": "8e2d16723843bf6923dcd609a8379200"
    },
    {
        "id": "f251adfb-7c7a-409e-9dc0-b588334b7d31",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_541.txt",
        "created": 1737369406,
        "question": "Do I need to submit any manuscripts or presentation files that prove the projects? Or is filling out the form with a clear description sufficient for all of them?",
        "answer": "If your projects are all listed in your transcript of records, the transcript is enough for us as proof. Please provide the exact names of the project modules though, so we can refer to them in your transcript. As for the content, we trust you on providing correct information about the contents of the projects inside the form.",
        "request_id": "12c41e6fb72badbac9512d96e4b8fa3b"
    },
    {
        "id": "eac79c9d-3f75-4e33-9283-6c5493a20921",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_541.txt",
        "created": 1737369406,
        "question": "Which of the credits belonging to the [REDACTED] are counted for the 'practical project' requirement? Do these short descriptions of the [REDACTED] and the projects accomplished for the [REDACTED] courses seem to be fitting the 18 ECTS requirement?",
        "answer": "The 12 ECTS of the actual thesis project would count. Regarding the contents of your projects: they sound fitting. It does depend, however, if they incorporated a practical aspect with technical tools such as programming, statistical/data analysis, or similar. In case you decide to apply, please make sure to highlight such aspects in the project descriptions.",
        "request_id": "12c41e6fb72badbac9512d96e4b8fa3b"
    },
    {
        "id": "c2e9a24a-54ab-4369-9301-92532b2998c2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_542.txt",
        "created": 1737369415,
        "question": "Which of the credits belonging to the [REDACTED] are counted for the 'practical project' requirement for the Master degree program 'AI in Society'?",
        "answer": "The 12 ECTS of the actual thesis project would count.",
        "request_id": "c9b1818a2e487d52d2706e3c302ece27"
    },
    {
        "id": "c26476da-bf3f-4832-9a62-de7abd36485e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_542.txt",
        "created": 1737369415,
        "question": "Do the projects accomplished for the [REDACTED] courses seem to be fitting the 18 ECTS requirement for the Master degree program 'AI in Society'?",
        "answer": "The contents of your projects sound fitting. However, it depends if they incorporated a practical aspect with technical tools such as programming, statistical/data analysis, or similar. In case you decide to apply, please make sure to highlight such aspects in the project descriptions.",
        "request_id": "c9b1818a2e487d52d2706e3c302ece27"
    },
    {
        "id": "8aeef953-b705-44c5-a65c-01cf12b5dc9b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_543.txt",
        "created": 1737369422,
        "question": "What are the formal requirements for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The formal requirements can be found at https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/. One of the most important requirements is having passed 140 ECTS (out of normally 180 ECTS for a full Bachelor\u2019s degree).",
        "request_id": "4305ead30e20eb127d157fc0d7558056"
    },
    {
        "id": "fb5e8393-f576-4742-be17-875595e72192",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_543.txt",
        "created": 1737369422,
        "question": "Can students begin the AI in Society program in a summer semester?",
        "answer": "No, students can only begin the AI in Society program in a winter semester.",
        "request_id": "4305ead30e20eb127d157fc0d7558056"
    },
    {
        "id": "4918b88d-3191-46a8-901b-64261c1c706d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_543.txt",
        "created": 1737369422,
        "question": "If I apply to this application cycle and get accepted, would it be possible to begin studies in summer semester 2025?",
        "answer": "No, you could not start in the summer semester. You could, however, apply now, and accept the study place for winter semester 2025/26, in case you get admitted.",
        "request_id": "4305ead30e20eb127d157fc0d7558056"
    },
    {
        "id": "32e89213-2cf3-464c-b9c1-d19755501ce9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_546.txt",
        "created": 1737369434,
        "question": "Is it permissible to submit my current IELTS score first and subsequently provide an updated score for the Master AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, we cannot accept late submission of documents, i.e. you cannot upload an improved score to us later than the deadline.",
        "request_id": "6bcb960399c79af83c71bae1ef21e598"
    },
    {
        "id": "8c2a9955-c25a-45be-a6dd-bea2c0dc3f58",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_546.txt",
        "created": 1737369434,
        "question": "What is the latest deadline for submitting the improved IELTS score for the Master AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "We need to be fair among all applicants, therefore we need to stick to the same deadline for all.",
        "request_id": "6bcb960399c79af83c71bae1ef21e598"
    },
    {
        "id": "d8da6d5e-80ca-4f99-9713-53d9cb1e9d38",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_546.txt",
        "created": 1737369434,
        "question": "Can I use completed courses at university that were taught in English as English proof for the Master AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "In case you have completed courses at university that were taught in English, you can also use this as English proof.",
        "request_id": "6bcb960399c79af83c71bae1ef21e598"
    },
    {
        "id": "587ae1b6-58b4-4aef-8987-569874b8d314",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_548.txt",
        "created": 1737369441,
        "question": "Can I use the 15 credits of English-speaking modules as proof of English proficiency for the Master AI in Society application?",
        "answer": "Only English-speaking modules that you have passed are usually recognized. However, you could try to get a certificate stating that you are currently attending courses XY and that they are held in English, as well as their ECTS scope. Whether this will then be recognized as proof is not decided by me, but you could try that.",
        "request_id": "25acb79b39b6972244f35e57b3f53eb0"
    },
    {
        "id": "87dd46a0-c8c8-4fbe-9007-4b73850a3963",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_548.txt",
        "created": 1737369441,
        "question": "What can I do if I cannot afford another IELTS test and I only have 5 English-speaking credits passed?",
        "answer": "You could try to get a certificate stating that you are currently attending English-speaking courses and their ECTS scope. Whether this will then be recognized as proof is not decided by me, but you could try that. Otherwise, I cannot offer you an alternative.",
        "request_id": "25acb79b39b6972244f35e57b3f53eb0"
    },
    {
        "id": "e586f62f-391e-4587-8fcd-edeca0e9ced9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_549.txt",
        "created": 1737369449,
        "question": "When will the test for the AI in Society program be held?",
        "answer": "The test will be held online on June 25th.",
        "request_id": "393fe434e8081889f2c9cb483d31bb72"
    },
    {
        "id": "f2c35fc7-a346-4503-ab2a-cf558851db22",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_549.txt",
        "created": 1737369449,
        "question": "When will applicants be informed about their admission to the test for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Applicants will be informed about their admission to the test one week before the test at the latest.",
        "request_id": "393fe434e8081889f2c9cb483d31bb72"
    },
    {
        "id": "970a90a0-788a-431f-b5af-add859af29e6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_549.txt",
        "created": 1737369449,
        "question": "What happens if an applicant is not able to take the test on June 25th for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "If an applicant is not able to take the test on June 25th and can provide a valid explanation, there will be a second test date in September.",
        "request_id": "393fe434e8081889f2c9cb483d31bb72"
    },
    {
        "id": "0187374b-e511-41f9-8cbd-2ea7eb45cd75",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_549.txt",
        "created": 1737369449,
        "question": "What should be written in the 'grade' section for pass/fail modules when filling in grades for the AI in Society program application?",
        "answer": "For pass/fail modules, 'pass' should be written in the 'grade' section.",
        "request_id": "393fe434e8081889f2c9cb483d31bb72"
    },
    {
        "id": "d046c8e8-a18f-4490-9b31-c3c3b992813a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_549.txt",
        "created": 1737369449,
        "question": "How can an applicant prove the projects that they did in the courses for the AI in Society program application?",
        "answer": "Applicants don't need to submit their project reports to prove completion of the module. Instead, they submit their Transcript of Records as part of the application procedure, as well as fill out a form which states the name of the project module, as well as the module/project description. For this, it is sufficient if they translate into English themselves.",
        "request_id": "393fe434e8081889f2c9cb483d31bb72"
    },
    {
        "id": "3328ffdb-bec8-4be6-bd11-88dc7b719a12",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_551.txt",
        "created": 1737369112,
        "question": "Do we need to offer a replacement date for the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "Yes, we need to offer a replacement date because people have a right to it (according to FPSO) if they are prevented from attending the first date for reasons not their fault. We need it mainly because more people will be added to the process. We can only further examine people (allow them to take the test) once the final VPD is available. And that can be 4+ weeks after May 31 (and thus after the first test date). We need this second date especially for these people.",
        "request_id": "75f2b5f9dd9569433f96e9c9a36b37db"
    },
    {
        "id": "aef6c885-5e4b-4f50-b9b3-fd2f8460f601",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_551.txt",
        "created": 1737369112,
        "question": "Do we need to create a new set of questions for the replacement date of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "No, we do not need to create a new set of questions for the replacement date. We can have the same test written again.",
        "request_id": "75f2b5f9dd9569433f96e9c9a36b37db"
    },
    {
        "id": "5ea3e305-050f-4dee-ab4c-5570359275a2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_551.txt",
        "created": 1737369112,
        "question": "Is it problematic that we have set the aptitude test to be online-only, while the FPSO states that it is offered in person at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, it is not problematic if we primarily offer the test as an online version (even if the FPSO states that it takes place in person). However, we must still offer an in-person test to people upon request, they have the right to it. For example, if someone is technically unable to take the test and only in-person is an option. We already have a room reserved for the test, we can simply keep it. If people report that they can only take the test in person, we will let them write the test on paper there.",
        "request_id": "75f2b5f9dd9569433f96e9c9a36b37db"
    },
    {
        "id": "33156405-0c6f-44d7-bf68-72972ff0c1a7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_552.txt",
        "created": 1737369124,
        "question": "What is the issue with candidate 1-00865352's application for the Praxisprojekt?",
        "answer": "The candidate is formally missing 1 ECTS. They have provided additional practical experience, but they need to upload an official document stating the content of their work and the duration.",
        "request_id": "a447dfa36991ea3db999a9475673a6c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "cf285652-d8ec-46ef-a39d-621d1f789455",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_552.txt",
        "created": 1737369124,
        "question": "What is the problem with candidate 1-00862215's application for the Praxisprojekt?",
        "answer": "The candidate provided 13 ECTS worth of modules, which does not meet the 18 ECTS requirement. They need to provide additional practical experience spanning at least 5 ECTS.",
        "request_id": "a447dfa36991ea3db999a9475673a6c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "9dbe51ac-219a-478b-a1aa-3e11652a703d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_552.txt",
        "created": 1737369124,
        "question": "What is the issue with candidate 1-00865541's application for the Mathe/[REDACTED]?",
        "answer": "The content of mathematics/statistics is unclear from the module titles alone. The candidate needs to provide some clarification, like official module descriptions, for these modules, to make apparent their relation to mathematics and/or statistics.",
        "request_id": "a447dfa36991ea3db999a9475673a6c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "cbc635e1-affb-41db-b87f-859acebdb373",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_553.txt",
        "created": 1737369134,
        "question": "How rigorous are the application requirements for the practical project aspect of the 'AI in Society' program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The program adheres to the 18 ECTS requirement for the practical project. However, working experience can also be included to reach this requirement.",
        "request_id": "0a681d9aae1ce7564440cf95ef110275"
    },
    {
        "id": "11a4b870-b108-4a28-8666-a15e9fc87612",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_553.txt",
        "created": 1737369134,
        "question": "Can working experience be included to meet the ECTS requirement for the 'AI in Society' program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes, working experience can be included to reach the 18 ECTS requirement for the practical project.",
        "request_id": "0a681d9aae1ce7564440cf95ef110275"
    },
    {
        "id": "08971e9c-7908-441b-966a-3316d882b4d6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_554.txt",
        "created": 1737369139,
        "question": "Is it already fixed, the aptitude test will take place online?",
        "answer": "Yes, we are planning to make the test online.",
        "request_id": "d67019853fb69f6c62926676648f5f60"
    },
    {
        "id": "525d41c2-d210-4fde-bee3-cdead774c03b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_556.txt",
        "created": 1737369144,
        "question": "Should we offer a replacement date for the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "Yes, we must offer a replacement date because people have a right to it (according to FPSO) if they are prevented from attending the first date for reasons not their fault. We especially need it because more people will be added to the process.",
        "request_id": "63b1837f51e49b481b3a5ce121c8e115"
    },
    {
        "id": "58d305f7-ac94-449c-8aaf-aca3a3cb0edf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_556.txt",
        "created": 1737369144,
        "question": "Why do we need a replacement date for the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "We need a replacement date because some applicants may not receive their Preliminary Review Documentation (VPD) in time for the first test date. We can only further examine these applicants (allow them to take the test) once the final VPD is available, which can be 4+ weeks after May 31 (and thus after the first test date).",
        "request_id": "63b1837f51e49b481b3a5ce121c8e115"
    },
    {
        "id": "6a1c091b-d06d-4408-8462-e16a611725fa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_556.txt",
        "created": 1737369144,
        "question": "Do we need to create a new set of questions for the replacement date of the aptitude test?",
        "answer": "No, we do not need to create a new set of questions for the replacement date. We can have the applicants take the same test again.",
        "request_id": "63b1837f51e49b481b3a5ce121c8e115"
    },
    {
        "id": "1db16b4d-6abc-480e-8dd0-f70327a81f35",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_556.txt",
        "created": 1737369144,
        "question": "Can we offer the test primarily online, even though the FPSO states it takes place in person?",
        "answer": "Yes, it is okay to primarily offer the test as an online version. However, we must offer an in-person test upon request, as it is the right of the applicants. For example, if someone cannot take the test online due to technical reasons, and only in-person is an option.",
        "request_id": "63b1837f51e49b481b3a5ce121c8e115"
    },
    {
        "id": "b17715e9-af4f-4924-bd96-951b824a43dd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_556.txt",
        "created": 1737369144,
        "question": "What should we do if an applicant cannot take the online test?",
        "answer": "If an applicant cannot take the online test, we should let them take the test on paper at the reserved room.",
        "request_id": "63b1837f51e49b481b3a5ce121c8e115"
    },
    {
        "id": "fb3fb95f-34e1-4653-90d3-36ab2fb377ac",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_561.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "Can I apply for a VPD without an APS certificate and then use that VPD application proof to apply for TUM without a VPD before the deadline of 31st May?",
        "answer": "All documents needed to issue a VPD need to be sent to uni-assist until our application deadline, May 31st. If you can send them all your documents (including the APS) by then, we can consider this as adhering to our deadline.",
        "request_id": "242c175571d146fddcd9568b1c22c4ac"
    },
    {
        "id": "3f3ec939-8efb-4cac-8637-089b143821b4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_561.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "Can the APS application form and payment receipt be enough proof to initiate my application?",
        "answer": "You will need to check this with uni-assist. I cannot give information on which documents are sufficient for them.",
        "request_id": "242c175571d146fddcd9568b1c22c4ac"
    },
    {
        "id": "c37ca716-742b-4017-8da6-53b7ede6dde0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_561.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "Once I have my APS and all necessary documents can I apply for MSC AI in Society directly using TUMonline?",
        "answer": "As soon as you have all documents we are asking for, you are ready to apply. There is no additional step (other than taking care of the VPD, in case you haven\u2019t already).",
        "request_id": "242c175571d146fddcd9568b1c22c4ac"
    },
    {
        "id": "6e66d45e-bea2-4c91-9b1c-501bb429ed34",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_561.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "Can I apply for the MSC AI in Society at TUM with my academic transcript until the 7th sem and a reference letter given by the capstone supervisor stating that I will pass my capstone phase 2 assessment?",
        "answer": "Thank you for the documents, this should suffice for the application. Please make sure to upload this letter issued by your professor inside your application. Additionally, in the form for practical projects (you will see it inside the application portal), please write a clear and concise description of what exactly you accomplished in your capstone project.",
        "request_id": "242c175571d146fddcd9568b1c22c4ac"
    },
    {
        "id": "a91cf664-f430-41fe-acfa-79ec856678a9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_561.txt",
        "created": 1737369164,
        "question": "What can I do if I won't have my Capstone project phase 2 listed in my transcript by the application deadline (May 31st)?",
        "answer": "If you will not have your Capstone project phase 2 listed in your transcript by May 31st, it could be a possibility to have your professor issue a letter, in which he verifies that you took the course, what you did in it, and how many ECTS the course spanned. The grade is not needed for us, we only need to know that you passed, and how many ECTS you earned from the course. This letter should then also have some type of university stamp on it.",
        "request_id": "242c175571d146fddcd9568b1c22c4ac"
    },
    {
        "id": "c2dc1e13-461d-4bdb-91b0-af83794cd7ca",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_562.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "Do I need to obtain an official letter from the university confirming that the courses were taught in English, or is this information sufficient as proof of English proficiency?",
        "answer": "To be formally correct, I would ask you to obtain an official statement that most of your degree was taught in English.",
        "request_id": "2e5a475c4e56a4409dd33f1dbf1be727"
    },
    {
        "id": "1c7b7cf7-5ffa-46c7-b4d6-83ba30cd82b1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_562.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "Could you please clarify if there will be additional information provided regarding the content and structure of the written aptitude test?",
        "answer": "There will be additional information regarding the aptitude test. Please check back on the website soon.",
        "request_id": "2e5a475c4e56a4409dd33f1dbf1be727"
    },
    {
        "id": "83c47fae-3167-46ca-ab0d-2627ce5cee0d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_562.txt",
        "created": 1737369177,
        "question": "At which stage and in what manner does the motivational letter influence the outcome of the application?",
        "answer": "The motivation letter is an optional element of your application. In case you are invited to an interview, your motivation letter can serve as the basis for the interview. Please don\u2019t put crucial information like contents of your practical projects only in the motivation letter, as it will not be read unless you are invited to an interview.",
        "request_id": "2e5a475c4e56a4409dd33f1dbf1be727"
    },
    {
        "id": "eb9a8909-080b-47ce-83c3-0ff78f5d9f7b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_564.txt",
        "created": 1737369191,
        "question": "Has my employment verification letter been received yet?",
        "answer": "It has probably not been reviewed yet due to a high number of applications.",
        "request_id": "52f75cf666a1438b0395f2759288307a"
    },
    {
        "id": "f13b8f9e-cc9b-45c0-8b35-299f801cbdce",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_564.txt",
        "created": 1737369191,
        "question": "When will the admission decisions be rendered and by when should applicants know if they are selected for an aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You will be notified whether or not you are invited to take the aptitude test at the very latest one week before the actual test (which is currently scheduled for June 25).",
        "request_id": "52f75cf666a1438b0395f2759288307a"
    },
    {
        "id": "c23cfabd-c573-4a19-bc2e-7f53fde06536",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_567.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "Can I initially apply for a VPD without an APS certificate and then use that VPD application proof to apply for TUM before the deadline of 31st May?",
        "answer": "All documents needed to issue a VPD need to be sent to uni-assist until our application deadline, May 31st. If you can send them all your documents (including the APS) by then, we can consider this as adhering to our deadline.",
        "request_id": "6a254a36d3d10db88c85a804bbb2a0d7"
    },
    {
        "id": "571fea8e-57b4-418a-856a-8abdafc270b1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_567.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "Can the APS application form and payment receipt be enough proof to initiate my application?",
        "answer": "You will need to check this with uni-assist. I cannot give information on which documents are sufficient for them.",
        "request_id": "6a254a36d3d10db88c85a804bbb2a0d7"
    },
    {
        "id": "4a507a1b-4515-4eb9-86f2-1f2ca08128b7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_567.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "Once I have my APS and all necessary documents can I apply for MSC AI in Society directly using TUMonline? Or is there any intermediary step?",
        "answer": "As soon as you have all documents we are asking for, you are ready to apply. There is no additional step (other than taking care of the VPD, in case you haven\u2019t already: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/application/application-info-portal/uni-assist)",
        "request_id": "6a254a36d3d10db88c85a804bbb2a0d7"
    },
    {
        "id": "8f9ad86e-de5d-4f1f-b47e-0e9f5a0ac2b5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_567.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "Can I apply for MSC AI in Society at TUM if my Capstone project phase 2 is not listed in my transcript by May 31st?",
        "answer": "If you will not have your Capstone project phase 2 listed in your transcript by May 31st, it could be a possibility to have your professor issue a letter, in which he verifies that you took the course, what you did in it, and how many ECTS the course spanned. The grade is not needed for us, we only need to know that you passed, and how many ECTS you earned from the course. This letter should then also have some type of university stamp on it.",
        "request_id": "6a254a36d3d10db88c85a804bbb2a0d7"
    },
    {
        "id": "9c949883-4898-4f58-a541-fffb1cce06e5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_567.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "What should I include in the form for practical projects inside the application portal?",
        "answer": "In the form for practical projects, please write a clear and concise description of what exactly you accomplished in your capstone project. Make sure to highlight the practical and interdisciplinary aspects.",
        "request_id": "6a254a36d3d10db88c85a804bbb2a0d7"
    },
    {
        "id": "57c5dd9c-ea39-46fa-bf20-a56f16b6c06b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_568.txt",
        "created": 1737369218,
        "question": "Is the English proof for the AI in Society program not sufficient if it is said that only 12 ECTS instead of 15 ECTS have been presented?",
        "answer": "The English proof is now set to \u201cOK\u201d.",
        "request_id": "9546b5de240082ba9111fb98243cd481"
    },
    {
        "id": "6d121ba6-c57f-492b-a98d-ed69f166807b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_569.txt",
        "created": 1737369223,
        "question": "Do you know if I am able to change my documents / reupload documents that have been submitted and not reviewed?",
        "answer": "You should be able to upload additional documents/swap them out if they still haven\u2019t been reviewed.",
        "request_id": "fe6ad85fab1f5d07dff71175bf97ebad"
    },
    {
        "id": "5bd124d8-1589-4168-8c44-36a141af534d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_569.txt",
        "created": 1737369223,
        "question": "Do you know someone whom I could contact about the management of the application?",
        "answer": "You should be able to upload a new document for that field now, please give it a try.",
        "request_id": "fe6ad85fab1f5d07dff71175bf97ebad"
    },
    {
        "id": "7b057749-80e7-41d8-b450-cc0680a5f0f9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_569.txt",
        "created": 1737369223,
        "question": "Do you happen to have a copy of the course catalog for AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "I am forwarding you our degree program documentation, as it is a public document (but not to be found online yet). You can find information about the different modules in there.",
        "request_id": "fe6ad85fab1f5d07dff71175bf97ebad"
    },
    {
        "id": "96595992-c963-45b9-836a-737e0ad30aaf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_570.txt",
        "created": 1737369231,
        "question": "Is there an error in my application form for the online Master's program in AI in Society?",
        "answer": "Yes, you mistakenly entered your bachelor's grade in the section about your current TUM master's program.",
        "request_id": "04052404418b269bd0c66394cea07097"
    },
    {
        "id": "da237bbd-e6a1-4a74-bbdb-ff9879590265",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_570.txt",
        "created": 1737369231,
        "question": "Could you please make the necessary correction in my application form?",
        "answer": "I have forwarded this information. Everything is fine regarding your grades now, no need to worry.",
        "request_id": "04052404418b269bd0c66394cea07097"
    },
    {
        "id": "ff858060-0fe7-4ad2-b19b-a69cffb22219",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_572.txt",
        "created": 1737369237,
        "question": "Where can I find the form to fill in the best credits for the AI in Society program application?",
        "answer": "The form to fill in the best credits will be provided to you inside the application portal, as soon as you start filling out your application. There is no public excel sheet.",
        "request_id": "011e87c6dfb817a5e82ced26461d9820"
    },
    {
        "id": "bf386414-7a68-47f4-8183-dc627193e89e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_572.txt",
        "created": 1737369237,
        "question": "Does the form to fill in the best credits need to be additionally approved by my university?",
        "answer": "It doesn\u2019t need to be additionally approved by your university. You should upload your official transcript of records, however.",
        "request_id": "011e87c6dfb817a5e82ced26461d9820"
    },
    {
        "id": "5177db41-89b6-4907-9fd2-d089812989ce",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_572.txt",
        "created": 1737369237,
        "question": "What should I do after completing the form to fill in the best credits?",
        "answer": "You should upload it directly in the TUM Online application portal. The application portal will guide you through the documents you need to submit.",
        "request_id": "011e87c6dfb817a5e82ced26461d9820"
    },
    {
        "id": "34816c84-6fbe-442c-a538-c73d66ef63ca",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_573.txt",
        "created": 1737369245,
        "question": "Is it possible to manage a full-time job alongside a full-time Master\u2019s study program?",
        "answer": "These kinds of situations are highly individual \u2013 it is up to you whether you are able to manage a full-time job alongside a full-time Master\u2019s study program. However, from our experience, it is nearly impossible to combine full-time work with full-time studies, as a full-time Master\u2019s program is very time intensive (we assume a 40 hour weekly work load here).",
        "request_id": "19e685a44bfe8ee31087c9f2afaf8ed0"
    },
    {
        "id": "486c318e-664d-47e2-a790-6f1ed4afa40b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_573.txt",
        "created": 1737369245,
        "question": "What is the maximum time allowed for finishing the degree?",
        "answer": "You can take up to 6 semesters max. for finishing the degree. You cannot stretch it out beyond this (in some cases up to a 7th exception semester).",
        "request_id": "19e685a44bfe8ee31087c9f2afaf8ed0"
    },
    {
        "id": "2b45a0cb-d47d-4cd5-8d45-633c721866bd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_573.txt",
        "created": 1737369245,
        "question": "Is it recommended to combine working full-time with taking up a full-time Master\u2019s degree?",
        "answer": "In general, we would not recommend trying to combine working full-time with taking up a full-time Master\u2019s degree. The decision is, however, of course up to you.",
        "request_id": "19e685a44bfe8ee31087c9f2afaf8ed0"
    },
    {
        "id": "0ebe065c-0ba9-45d5-be35-7e6ec436b603",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_574.txt",
        "created": 1737369254,
        "question": "Has my employment verification letter been received yet?",
        "answer": "It has probably not been reviewed yet due to a high number of applications.",
        "request_id": "de040451f30835878097142c5e9dfd2b"
    },
    {
        "id": "d63ed822-cf81-4990-a31a-3b652a41f832",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_574.txt",
        "created": 1737369254,
        "question": "When will the admission decisions be rendered and by when should applicants know if they are selected for an aptitude test?",
        "answer": "You will be notified whether or not you are invited to take the aptitude test at the very latest one week before the actual test, which is currently scheduled for June 25.",
        "request_id": "de040451f30835878097142c5e9dfd2b"
    },
    {
        "id": "4d0c919f-edf7-48dd-9965-25b7e0945006",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_575.txt",
        "created": 1737369259,
        "question": "What is the rule regarding the English language proof for applications?",
        "answer": "If the English Bachelor's thesis comes under 15 ECTS, it can be supplemented with additional English modules.",
        "request_id": "cf2d3cdf5448e615c007d27efcfe4429"
    },
    {
        "id": "dd5931be-9ae3-4c3e-863f-c87e58b88183",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_575.txt",
        "created": 1737369259,
        "question": "Can a course taught in English be considered as part of the English language proof?",
        "answer": "Yes, a course taught in English can be considered as part of the English language proof if the English Bachelor's thesis comes under 15 ECTS.",
        "request_id": "cf2d3cdf5448e615c007d27efcfe4429"
    },
    {
        "id": "b25198cd-4c97-4434-adc2-047b8b49bf87",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_576.txt",
        "created": 1737369265,
        "question": "Is it worthwhile to apply for the masters in 'AI in Society' at TUM, given the professional experience of 1.5 years in the field of AI?",
        "answer": "Given your background, we of course welcome your application. Please make sure that you fulfil the prerequisites as listed on our website (i.e. credits from mathematics and/or statistics courses, practical experience.",
        "request_id": "71a1408179ac54c43314d6f53ab7e922"
    },
    {
        "id": "a39811a0-cd7a-4341-b197-fa2451fe7de4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_577.txt",
        "created": 1737369269,
        "question": "Do I need to obtain an official letter from the university confirming that the courses were taught in English, or is this information sufficient as proof of English proficiency for the M.Sc. AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "To be formally correct, you should obtain an official statement that most of your degree was taught in English.",
        "request_id": "bc9ba32ca3001a846a9cdbbbdc506f74"
    },
    {
        "id": "504dbf1d-4b89-4f73-80ef-d4c4fa43fc95",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_578.txt",
        "created": 1737369272,
        "question": "What is the tuition fee for a semester in the 'AI in society' program?",
        "answer": "The tuition fee for international applicants amounts to 4000\u20ac per semester.",
        "request_id": "e0ae1b8ec07509bac32d6ae9c032b80c"
    },
    {
        "id": "4c9ea171-fcdc-490f-a981-0c19dcc5fd00",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_578.txt",
        "created": 1737369272,
        "question": "Can I apply as an international student to the 'AI in society' program?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can.",
        "request_id": "e0ae1b8ec07509bac32d6ae9c032b80c"
    },
    {
        "id": "abcd944b-83b7-4502-8b3c-f0543ef90024",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_578.txt",
        "created": 1737369272,
        "question": "How would I give the aptitude test in person for the 'AI in society' program as I'm not in Germany right now? Are there any online options available?",
        "answer": "We are not yet sure if we are offering an online option. If the test will only be conducted in person, we are requiring the applicants to take the test in person.",
        "request_id": "e0ae1b8ec07509bac32d6ae9c032b80c"
    },
    {
        "id": "db33c8e5-13ab-48d4-ac52-6a3ace397a8d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_579.txt",
        "created": 1737369279,
        "question": "During the bachelor I had some courses that were called \u201cProject\u201d, so in total that makes 3 projects of 6 credits. Would it be posible to apply with 3 of them instead of 1 of 18 credits?",
        "answer": "Yes, this is possible \u2013 please refer to our FAQ section: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/",
        "request_id": "035bd5a7fd02b859e3ffe8d2ab1ac14a"
    },
    {
        "id": "fd8c2935-ffa4-4116-87d3-65de93d5a0cb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_581.txt",
        "created": 1737369285,
        "question": "What kind of concepts will the aptitude test for the AI in Society course cover?",
        "answer": "The aptitude test is planning on asking more basic concepts, not expecting applicants to be experts in law and mathematics at the same time. It also won't be asking knowledge that will only be taught during the program itself.",
        "request_id": "7c8f24effa838a7aa6797a73fa538a04"
    },
    {
        "id": "0b032bb7-014c-4871-b6fa-fa11ae0d0828",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_581.txt",
        "created": 1737369285,
        "question": "When will more information on the aptitude test for the AI in Society course be released?",
        "answer": "More information on the test will be released in the coming weeks.",
        "request_id": "7c8f24effa838a7aa6797a73fa538a04"
    },
    {
        "id": "e8f4d9bb-a47e-4c6a-9cb9-5d87d248d46b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_583.txt",
        "created": 1737369294,
        "question": "What is the maximum number of students for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The program aims for a maximum of 40-50 students.",
        "request_id": "24e13dce2af63af762ba2e49536b8998"
    },
    {
        "id": "c91858af-373c-412f-97f8-091bfbfafa5c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_583.txt",
        "created": 1737369294,
        "question": "How many applications have been received for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Approximately 150 applications have been received.",
        "request_id": "24e13dce2af63af762ba2e49536b8998"
    },
    {
        "id": "c63753c7-81ac-46b1-9782-2362e874eaf3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_583.txt",
        "created": 1737369294,
        "question": "Can living in an English-speaking country be used as proof of English proficiency for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "No, a formal proof of English proficiency is required. This can be provided through one of the listed tests or in the case of a thesis written in English, provided it corresponds to at least 15 ECTS.",
        "request_id": "24e13dce2af63af762ba2e49536b8998"
    },
    {
        "id": "def291df-584a-4ab6-a4f6-68335ae4f1fb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_583.txt",
        "created": 1737369294,
        "question": "What is required to prove completion of at least 5 credits worth of modules from mathematics or statistics during the bachelor\u2019s studies?",
        "answer": "A proof is required, such as official documents confirming the completed modules and the workload in hours. Without these, the prerequisites cannot be recognized as fulfilled.",
        "request_id": "24e13dce2af63af762ba2e49536b8998"
    },
    {
        "id": "5c399b3d-1e7e-4c00-8eee-41d1782245f5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_583.txt",
        "created": 1737369294,
        "question": "Is work experience recognized as a practical project worth at least 18 credits completed during the bachelor\u2019s studies?",
        "answer": "Work experience is recognized if it meets the content requirements of the aptitude committee. Detailed documents describing the activity and the timeframe should be uploaded.",
        "request_id": "24e13dce2af63af762ba2e49536b8998"
    },
    {
        "id": "9c451e4f-cee4-41a0-877a-71b9e5969fa5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_583.txt",
        "created": 1737369294,
        "question": "Is the aptitude test mandatory for all applicants?",
        "answer": "Yes, the aptitude test is mandatory for all applicants who meet the formal requirements.",
        "request_id": "24e13dce2af63af762ba2e49536b8998"
    },
    {
        "id": "77b089c3-8d6a-4ef1-8a4c-524ed737f29f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_584.txt",
        "created": 1737369306,
        "question": "What is the issue with my application for uni assist VPD as indicated in the attached screenshot?",
        "answer": "You have indicated that you have applied for the VPD in full. Your proof of this has been received and provisionally OK. The document is now only set to 'not OK' so that you can upload the final VPD here. Uni-assist will email you the final VPD once it is complete. Please upload the final VPD for TUM here as soon as you receive it. However, if we then discover that your documents have not been received by [REDACTED] in full by the deadline, you will be excluded from the application process.",
        "request_id": "56d70d287e3d922ae64f650fa4a1ac56"
    },
    {
        "id": "adad2bcf-8640-43e3-9598-73e810294b42",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_587.txt",
        "created": 1737369314,
        "question": "What are the requirements for applying to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The requirements include: a qualified bachelor\u2019s degree of at least 6 semesters obtained at a domestic or foreign university, adequate knowledge of the English language, at least 5 credits worth of modules from mathematics or statistics passed during the bachelor\u2019s studies, a practical project worth at least 18 credits completed during the bachelor\u2019s studies, and passing of the aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "8230646852670a0339cdc53173d58a26"
    },
    {
        "id": "edacf530-088a-4ff4-864f-3f84015bfbbf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_587.txt",
        "created": 1737369314,
        "question": "How can I apply to the AI in Society program at TUM with a diploma degree?",
        "answer": "You need to upload all the documents you have, such as a transcript of records, semester study plans, etc. The aptitude committee of the program will decide whether this is sufficient.",
        "request_id": "8230646852670a0339cdc53173d58a26"
    },
    {
        "id": "fe631f1e-7c54-4a4a-b76d-533e8e4cdd6c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_587.txt",
        "created": 1737369314,
        "question": "How can I prove my English language proficiency for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "TUM requires an official proof for the completeness of the application documents. This can be demonstrated either with one of the tests listed on the TUM website or in the case of a thesis written in English (where we would also have to ensure that it corresponds to a scope of at least 15 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "8230646852670a0339cdc53173d58a26"
    },
    {
        "id": "ca601f1a-b0ac-4bce-b3fc-e9bff9e21f6f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_587.txt",
        "created": 1737369314,
        "question": "How can I prove that I have completed at least 5 credits worth of modules from mathematics or statistics during my bachelor\u2019s studies?",
        "answer": "You need to provide a proof for this. Without official documents confirming the modules you have taken (and the workload involved, e.g., in hours), TUM cannot acknowledge that the requirements have been met.",
        "request_id": "8230646852670a0339cdc53173d58a26"
    },
    {
        "id": "fc6fbd5e-f680-4bab-8261-afa89b534de9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_587.txt",
        "created": 1737369314,
        "question": "Is the aptitude test necessary for all applicants to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The aptitude test is mandatory for all applicants who have met the formal requirements. More detailed information about the test can be found on the TUM website.",
        "request_id": "8230646852670a0339cdc53173d58a26"
    },
    {
        "id": "c7ec020e-c783-4a1a-9d48-4d4b0d230836",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_589.txt",
        "created": 1737369333,
        "question": "Would my involvement in the positive psychology program, aimed at addressing the high depression rate among university students, count as a practical project?",
        "answer": "Yes, your project can be considered a practical project, if it fulfils our requirements content-wise (i.e. it must have an interdisciplinary and practical aspect, please see the description on our website). From your short description, it sounds suitable, but we would need a more detailed description of what you did there.",
        "request_id": "5ab654514aa56d54316fb959f9eec32c"
    },
    {
        "id": "bf4c50b5-6f25-4f45-9849-3299eee9abd8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_589.txt",
        "created": 1737369333,
        "question": "Could you please advise on how the duration and ECTS would be considered for this project?",
        "answer": "If this project was part of your studies (i.e. it is listed on your Transcript of Records), this is sufficient as proof. We will refer to the credits given to the module (and convert to ECTS if your credit system is not based on ECTS). If you participated in this project outside of university, i.e. it is not listed on your Transcript, then we need another form of proof. For example, if this was an internship or a work experience, we ask you to upload a work certificate issued by the place where you worked on this project. It should state exactly what you did there, and how long you were involved.",
        "request_id": "5ab654514aa56d54316fb959f9eec32c"
    },
    {
        "id": "9893d2ec-e926-4dd1-bd23-f67ba33710c1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_589.txt",
        "created": 1737369333,
        "question": "How would the practical project(for example the positive psychology program ) be counted as the ETCS? How would the time that I invested be counted? If I did it outside the university myself with the group of students?",
        "answer": "1 ECTS corresponds to 30 hours of work. So, for example, if you tell us that you worked for one month, we would calculate a 40-hour work week (or 20-hour if part-time is stated), times 4 weeks. In this case, it would be 160 hours. 160 hours would correspond to 5,3 ECTS. In any case, you need to provide to us some kind of statement (as I described in the previous email), from the positive psychology program you participated in.",
        "request_id": "5ab654514aa56d54316fb959f9eec32c"
    },
    {
        "id": "56839840-b017-476f-8a06-b7b0a463f754",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_590.txt",
        "created": 1737369346,
        "question": "Once I have my APS and all necessary documents can I apply for MSC AI in Society directly using TUMonline?",
        "answer": "As soon as you have all documents we are asking for, you are ready to apply. There is no additional step (other than taking care of the VPD, in case you haven\u2019t already).",
        "request_id": "9cbcf819ebbd44e4804fe48728130af8"
    },
    {
        "id": "731cdfad-f3c7-48bf-9ff6-f5f1ce1539c9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_590.txt",
        "created": 1737369346,
        "question": "Can the APS application form and payment receipt be enough proof to initiate my application?",
        "answer": "You will need to check this with uni-assist. I cannot give information on which documents are sufficient for them.",
        "request_id": "9cbcf819ebbd44e4804fe48728130af8"
    },
    {
        "id": "bc69a4bf-eb61-4b36-b96d-e7d77347e245",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_590.txt",
        "created": 1737369346,
        "question": "Can I apply for VPD via this way?",
        "answer": "You will need to check this with uni-assist. I cannot give information on which documents are sufficient for them.",
        "request_id": "9cbcf819ebbd44e4804fe48728130af8"
    },
    {
        "id": "c64c5268-83d7-4417-a9f3-c8974f453d3a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_590.txt",
        "created": 1737369346,
        "question": "I am attaching two documents to this mail, one is my academic transcript until the 7th sem and one is the reference letter given by the capstone supervisor stating that I will pass my capstone phase 2 assessment as well. Is this enough for the application?",
        "answer": "This should suffice for the application. Please make sure to upload this letter issued by your professor inside your application. Additionally, in the form for practical projects, please write a clear and concise description of what exactly you accomplished in your capstone project.",
        "request_id": "9cbcf819ebbd44e4804fe48728130af8"
    },
    {
        "id": "149de645-f7f1-4526-8873-00667430acb8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_590.txt",
        "created": 1737369346,
        "question": "I want to apply for MSC AI in Society at TUM and meet all the requirements but I have a bit of clutter regarding the point 'a practical project worth at least 18 credits completed during the bachelor\u2019s studies.' My project phase 2 will be completed by 1st May 2024 which suffices this requirement but its APS verified transcripts won't be available before the TUM application deadline ends. Can I apply with the phase one APS verified results and give the phase 2 results as soon as they are available?",
        "answer": "We need to have all of your documents by the application deadline (May 31st), we cannot make exceptions. If you will not have your Capstone project phase 2 listed in your transcript by May 31st, it could be a possibility to have your professor issue a letter, in which he verifies that you took the course, what you did in it, and how many ECTS the course spanned. The grade is not needed for us, we only need to know that you passed, and how many ECTS you earned from the course. This letter should then also have some type of university stamp on it.",
        "request_id": "9cbcf819ebbd44e4804fe48728130af8"
    },
    {
        "id": "476d82e9-a8c7-4c45-bc8c-36c5e5a7b9cc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_591.txt",
        "created": 1737369396,
        "question": "Is there a specific form for the declaration that needs to be signed at the end of the motivational letter for the Msc in AI in Society application at TUM?",
        "answer": "There is no specific form. Please simply state at the bottom of your motivational letter, in your own words, that you have written the letter yourself and without external help.",
        "request_id": "ece03380d27f04e7aa6b4dc16c163cd6"
    },
    {
        "id": "94e7d15a-029f-4193-9381-0c75ae30fe67",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_592.txt",
        "created": 1737369400,
        "question": "Once I have my APS and all necessary documents can I apply for MSC AI in Society directly using TUMonline?",
        "answer": "As soon as you have all documents we are asking for, you are ready to apply. There is no additional step (other than taking care of the VPD, in case you haven\u2019t already).",
        "request_id": "7940c2e7c301bca6e2fd5d64434298a3"
    },
    {
        "id": "b63c1b85-4aee-4951-b1a4-d447a6313101",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_592.txt",
        "created": 1737369400,
        "question": "Can't the APS application form and payment receipt be enough proof to initiate my application?",
        "answer": "TUM does not specifically ask for APS approved documents for your application. Therefore, it is good to have, but not actually a requirement. We also don\u2019t state so on any of our websites. What we do state however, is the VPD, which also checks your university documents.",
        "request_id": "7940c2e7c301bca6e2fd5d64434298a3"
    },
    {
        "id": "eab65854-009f-48f9-b44d-1b4305ec2f36",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_592.txt",
        "created": 1737369400,
        "question": "Can I apply for my application in TUM AI in Society via TUMonline once I get my initial VPD verification done via uni assist? I need not wait for my APS certification to arrive right?",
        "answer": "You do not need an APS certification, at least I have not heard about it nor have I seen other applicants submit it. But the VPD: yes.",
        "request_id": "7940c2e7c301bca6e2fd5d64434298a3"
    },
    {
        "id": "ee4fee43-d07f-427d-9c35-a58b723f746a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_592.txt",
        "created": 1737369400,
        "question": "What is the deadline for applying for the VPD for the MSC AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "You need to have *applied* for the VPD by May 31st the latest (our application deadline). If by May 31st you can upload to us the confirmation over your VPD application, this is sufficient for us. I.e., if you do not have the final VPD by then yet, this is still okay, you just need to have applied for it by then.",
        "request_id": "7940c2e7c301bca6e2fd5d64434298a3"
    },
    {
        "id": "a2b31ff0-a839-45e8-9f8c-1442e51ba559",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_592.txt",
        "created": 1737369400,
        "question": "What should I do if my Capstone project phase 2 is not listed in my transcript by the application deadline?",
        "answer": "If you will not have your Capstone project phase 2 listed in your transcript by May 31st, it could be a possibility to have your professor issue a letter, in which he verifies that you took the course, what you did in it, and how many ECTS the course spanned. The grade is not needed for us, we only need to know that you passed, and how many ECTS you earned from the course. This letter should then also have some type of university stamp on it.",
        "request_id": "7940c2e7c301bca6e2fd5d64434298a3"
    },
    {
        "id": "2d22e569-ec97-4a80-829e-a869993a2651",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_593.txt",
        "created": 1737369420,
        "question": "What are the eligibility requirements for the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "For details on the program requirements, please see here: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/, https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/, https://www.tum.de/en/studies/degree-programs/detail/ai-in-society",
        "request_id": "b799de7e4bc022c483abf63aa862fb22"
    },
    {
        "id": "d9647a31-a4b7-4aea-b3c7-af3ecafbe11e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_593.txt",
        "created": 1737369420,
        "question": "Would the program consider applications received after the deadline due to the time taken for applying through uni-assist?",
        "answer": "It is only important that you have applied for the VPD by the end of our application deadline (May 31st). Please upload the confirmation over your VPD application to us \u2013 the final VPD you can hand in to us later. We understand that this process takes time.",
        "request_id": "b799de7e4bc022c483abf63aa862fb22"
    },
    {
        "id": "8008cfaf-b238-42c3-a8f5-b8a4680a782b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_593.txt",
        "created": 1737369420,
        "question": "Does the program accept the PTE academic test as proof of English language proficiency?",
        "answer": "Yes, TUM also accepts the PTE test. Please see here: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/application/application-info-portal/admission-requirements/language-certificates",
        "request_id": "b799de7e4bc022c483abf63aa862fb22"
    },
    {
        "id": "e161a3bd-352a-4099-a11f-5bfda87e26da",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_593.txt",
        "created": 1737369420,
        "question": "Which programs am I eligible to apply for at your university? Does the tuition fee for a program affect the admissions difficulty?",
        "answer": "I cannot provide you general information on other TUM study programs. For this, I would kindly refer you to TUM\u2019s student information center: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/support-and-advice/support-during-studies/student-information.",
        "request_id": "b799de7e4bc022c483abf63aa862fb22"
    },
    {
        "id": "8c68d03a-1972-4edc-86b7-f4e3392a8785",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_594.txt",
        "created": 1737369432,
        "question": "Would my involvement in the positive psychology program, aimed at addressing the high depression rate among university students, count as a practical project?",
        "answer": "Yes, your project can be considered a practical project, if it fulfils our requirements content-wise (i.e. it must have an interdisciplinary and practical aspect, please see the description on our website). From your short description, it sounds suitable, but we would need a more detailed description of what you did there. You will be asked for a detailed description inside the application portal (there will be a form to fill out).",
        "request_id": "e3733ebceb3863dabce2b392d1a6ab0c"
    },
    {
        "id": "988e0b97-7e8a-4a84-a66c-e538ba90b18f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_594.txt",
        "created": 1737369432,
        "question": "How would the duration and ECTS be considered for this project?",
        "answer": "If this project was part of your studies (i.e. it is listed on your Transcript of Records), this is sufficient as proof. We will refer to the credits given to the module (and convert to ECTS if your credit system is not based on ECTS). If you participated in this project outside of university, i.e. it is not listed on your Transcript, then we need another form of proof. For example, if this was an internship or a work experience, we ask you to upload a work certificate issued by the place where you worked on this project. It should state exactly what you did there, and how long you were involved.",
        "request_id": "e3733ebceb3863dabce2b392d1a6ab0c"
    },
    {
        "id": "4b343bc9-aa0f-4011-8d10-2cba7f899bc9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_595.txt",
        "created": 1737369440,
        "question": "Once I have my APS and all necessary documents can I apply for MSC AI in Society directly using TUMonline?",
        "answer": "As soon as you have all documents we are asking for, you are ready to apply. There is no additional step (other than taking care of the VPD, in case you haven\u2019t already).",
        "request_id": "6342b5bb1419155ce69dddaf11a68cef"
    },
    {
        "id": "c6385f2e-21c7-48c2-85a5-ad72d393e3fc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_595.txt",
        "created": 1737369440,
        "question": "Can't the APS application form and payment receipt be enough proof to initiate my application?",
        "answer": "TUM does not specifically ask for APS approved documents for your application. What we do state however, is the VPD, which also checks your university documents.",
        "request_id": "6342b5bb1419155ce69dddaf11a68cef"
    },
    {
        "id": "046139d7-faae-4888-9b1f-a08ca5a7ca60",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_595.txt",
        "created": 1737369440,
        "question": "Do I need an APS certification to apply for the VPD via uni-assist?",
        "answer": "You do need the APS in order to apply for the VPD via uni-assist. You need to have applied for the VPD by May 31st the latest (our application deadline). If by May 31st you can upload to us the confirmation over your VPD application, this is sufficient for us.",
        "request_id": "6342b5bb1419155ce69dddaf11a68cef"
    },
    {
        "id": "466c96e1-f226-48ad-9d65-d48ff5efc84d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_595.txt",
        "created": 1737369440,
        "question": "What should I do if my Capstone project phase 2 won't be listed in my transcript by the application deadline?",
        "answer": "If you will not have your Capstone project phase 2 listed in your transcript by May 31st, it could be a possibility to have your professor issue a letter, in which he verifies that you took the course, what you did in it, and how many ECTS the course spanned. The grade is not needed for us, we only need to know that you passed, and how many ECTS you earned from the course. This letter should then also have some type of university stamp on it.",
        "request_id": "6342b5bb1419155ce69dddaf11a68cef"
    },
    {
        "id": "a2bc8394-fda4-4090-b726-8c90850802c4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_595.txt",
        "created": 1737369440,
        "question": "What should I include in the form for practical projects?",
        "answer": "In the form for practical projects, please write a clear and concise description of what exactly you accomplished in your capstone project. Make sure to highlight the practical and interdisciplinary aspects.",
        "request_id": "6342b5bb1419155ce69dddaf11a68cef"
    },
    {
        "id": "d9d9b7f0-3966-4319-8e2a-34ebc4493326",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_596.txt",
        "created": 1737369456,
        "question": "Are APS and VPD fundamentally the same?",
        "answer": "APS and VPD are fundamentally different. Applications with MZB (Master's entry requirement) from China and India always have to apply for a VPD as well. Without a present APS (always digital, unless very old in the date of issue), no evaluation of the HZB or MZB can take place.",
        "request_id": "75cf2a043c3f7b42b8281a5aa3ece013"
    },
    {
        "id": "e3da00a4-aeec-49c2-a787-aa428f607aea",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_596.txt",
        "created": 1737369456,
        "question": "What happens if the APS for WiSe 24/25 including the other required certificates is not in Berlin by the deadline of 31.05.24?",
        "answer": "If this is not the case, a VPD can still be issued at some point, but it can then no longer be taken into account for WiSe 24/25.",
        "request_id": "75cf2a043c3f7b42b8281a5aa3ece013"
    },
    {
        "id": "f971af5f-72c8-4910-adcb-90b98019e267",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_597.txt",
        "created": 1737369463,
        "question": "Do you know if I am able to change my documents / reupload documents that have been submitted and not reviewed?",
        "answer": "You could upload additional documents/swap them out if they still haven\u2019t been reviewed.",
        "request_id": "8892b1312a1b4e43550d58eb48880c5b"
    },
    {
        "id": "21a72049-b440-4d8e-a7ff-ff2aa3c901da",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_598.txt",
        "created": 1737369467,
        "question": "Is there a general time of day for the lectures, as in mornings, afternoons, evenings or does that vary?",
        "answer": "There is no general rule here. The time of each module depends on the professor who teaches the module.",
        "request_id": "ea139800d2c6ee0918414c455473154b"
    },
    {
        "id": "0066ad3d-6ac8-4da3-9c77-d4cf8f5fc8b8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_598.txt",
        "created": 1737369467,
        "question": "Is it possible to complete this program while working (full time or reduced hours)?",
        "answer": "Formally, the program is only offered for full-time study. It might be possible for you to work part-time if you can manage. Full-time work, however, would not work in parallel, as the study load is quite high.",
        "request_id": "ea139800d2c6ee0918414c455473154b"
    },
    {
        "id": "d4647115-8722-4c97-a9ab-52295addaf3d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_598.txt",
        "created": 1737369467,
        "question": "Since when do you offer this program?",
        "answer": "The first time we are offering this program will be the coming winter semester 2024/25. This is a new program. However, many of the courses taught as part of the program are established modules at TUM.",
        "request_id": "ea139800d2c6ee0918414c455473154b"
    },
    {
        "id": "6cb066cf-578a-4d03-b23d-c4ddc82ae851",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_599.txt",
        "created": 1737369473,
        "question": "Can I use my INSEAD MBA certificate and dean's letter as proof of my English skills for the AI in Society master's program at TUM?",
        "answer": "If you want to prove your English skills with a previous degree, it needs to be a degree conforming to EU standard durations (bachelor's: 6-8 semester, master's: 4 semesters minimum). With a 2 semester MBA, the requirement to prove English language skills cannot be met. Please submit a different proof of English language skills like a TOEFL, IELTS or other accepted test score as instructed.",
        "request_id": "3b83412302435cf4821ed55ba6efdb16"
    },
    {
        "id": "0655d168-2ac4-4752-a97a-79691ec17cf2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_599.txt",
        "created": 1737369473,
        "question": "How should I fill out the credit list for the AI in Society master's program at TUM if I have more credits than the form allows?",
        "answer": "In this case, we ask them to simply duplicate the form, fill out as many rows as they need, and then merge the documents back into one for uploading.",
        "request_id": "3b83412302435cf4821ed55ba6efdb16"
    },
    {
        "id": "237568b0-b61a-4c5e-8206-f83be9279975",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_599.txt",
        "created": 1737369473,
        "question": "Can I list internships or work experience as a practical project for the AI in Society master's program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes. In this case, please (additionally to the form) submit a work certificate in the field for practical projects, which states the duration as well as the content of your work. Since work certificates are not credit based, we will recalculate from work hours to credits (30 hours = 1 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "3b83412302435cf4821ed55ba6efdb16"
    },
    {
        "id": "235867d7-d8bb-4fd6-b774-ae21b63e00cc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_599.txt",
        "created": 1737369473,
        "question": "What should a work certificate for the AI in Society master's program at TUM look like?",
        "answer": "There is no strict form on work certificates. Normally they are letters handed out by your (previous) employer, summarizing what the employee (you) did at their company (e.g. for reference for the person\u2019s future employer). It should simply state what your role was at the company, which type of work you did, which projects you participated in, as well as the duration of your employment with them. It should be evident to us that you didn\u2019t write the letter yourself, i.e. the employer/their HR department could sign at the bottom, have their logo on the letter, or similar.",
        "request_id": "3b83412302435cf4821ed55ba6efdb16"
    },
    {
        "id": "712aeb0b-5523-4b13-8377-0ac89bdf8edf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_601.txt",
        "created": 1737369127,
        "question": "Can I apply for my application in TUM AI in Society via TUMonline once I get my initial VPD verification done via uni assist, without waiting for my APS certification to arrive?",
        "answer": "Yes, you do not need an APS certification to apply for the TUM AI in Society program. TUM does not specifically ask for APS approved documents for your application. What is required is the VPD, which also checks your university documents.",
        "request_id": "7269a3e5bb765a2cc0968dfb7b348f21"
    },
    {
        "id": "246afe02-0521-4c8d-bbe5-35a7b91a8cb8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_602.txt",
        "created": 1737369133,
        "question": "Is APS approved documents a requirement for the application to TUM?",
        "answer": "TUM does not specifically ask for APS approved documents for your application. It is good to have, but not actually a requirement.",
        "request_id": "596c9bf93e84a02423c5f7a44475640a"
    },
    {
        "id": "ac69cb16-7e01-45f1-943e-34b062690afc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_602.txt",
        "created": 1737369133,
        "question": "What is the VPD requirement for the application to TUM?",
        "answer": "The VPD checks your university documents. It is stated as a requirement on TUM's websites.",
        "request_id": "596c9bf93e84a02423c5f7a44475640a"
    },
    {
        "id": "f87e9d45-77d1-4725-9bff-ca9c12969dae",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_603.txt",
        "created": 1737369139,
        "question": "What to write in the 'grade' section for pass/fail modules when filling in my grades for the documents regarding 140 best credits?",
        "answer": "If you are filling up the rest with pass/non-pass modules after listing all your graded modules, then please just write 'pass' in the grade section for those modules.",
        "request_id": "b4c01fff9bc7dbaa74ff5ca4e3819b4b"
    },
    {
        "id": "6ac65e53-8436-4b66-8f98-1f164818de2d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_603.txt",
        "created": 1737369139,
        "question": "How can I prove the projects that I did in the courses?",
        "answer": "You don\u2019t need to submit your project reports in order to prove your completion of the module. Instead, you submit your Transcript of Records as part of the application procedure (this module should then of course be listed in this Transcript), as well as fill out a form which states the name of the project module, as well as the module/project description. For this, it is sufficient if you translate into English yourself.",
        "request_id": "b4c01fff9bc7dbaa74ff5ca4e3819b4b"
    },
    {
        "id": "fb659e26-f9f8-42ee-a16a-ac675fea5466",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_603.txt",
        "created": 1737369139,
        "question": "Would a weekly research & review work in a course count as a project in the requirement?",
        "answer": "It is up for the admission committee to decide whether or not this will be counted. However, it is highly encouraged to apply with these courses. If the course is 5 ECTS, then the project would also be recognized with the weight of the 5 ECTS.",
        "request_id": "b4c01fff9bc7dbaa74ff5ca4e3819b4b"
    },
    {
        "id": "6c7ae40b-8afd-4b90-9e2e-65ef39ecf80b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_603.txt",
        "created": 1737369139,
        "question": "Does the practical project need to be recognized with credits, i.e. does it have to be part of my university course? Would individual projects or volunteer experience be able to also contribute to the requirement?",
        "answer": "Technically, practical projects that were not part of a university module can be counted. However, you would then need to provide us with an official documentation that those practical projects in total spanned at least 540 hours for completion (540h correspond to 18 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "b4c01fff9bc7dbaa74ff5ca4e3819b4b"
    },
    {
        "id": "770d334f-f14a-4d61-a8cb-9f720ee2ad0f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_603.txt",
        "created": 1737369139,
        "question": "If from my university, I do not officially have 18 credits for a practical project in social science, is there a way to make up for this requirement?",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, as much as we would want to, we can't just let you compile an own project without an official documentation about how much time was spent for it. Please understand that we need to compare students' achievements universally somehow; this we can do by setting a minimum of ECTS credits, or, hours invested.",
        "request_id": "b4c01fff9bc7dbaa74ff5ca4e3819b4b"
    },
    {
        "id": "533abc08-f860-4e25-88db-d82e411aa4f7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_605.txt",
        "created": 1737369159,
        "question": "What to write in the 'grade' section for pass/fail modules when filling in my grades for the documents regarding 140 best credits?",
        "answer": "For pass/fail modules, you should write 'pass' in the grade section.",
        "request_id": "7e95de77848da055c7aa51bbeca28273"
    },
    {
        "id": "540b4406-1ba3-4288-86ea-0ca0348ed4fc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_605.txt",
        "created": 1737369159,
        "question": "How can I prove the projects that I did in the courses?",
        "answer": "You don\u2019t need to submit your project reports to prove your completion of the module. Instead, you submit your Transcript of Records as part of the application procedure (this module should then of course be listed in this Transcript), as well as fill out a form which states the name of the project module, as well as the module/project description. For this, it is sufficient if you translate into English yourself.",
        "request_id": "7e95de77848da055c7aa51bbeca28273"
    },
    {
        "id": "e1d801d3-143e-4168-9e6d-a84513c03b45",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_605.txt",
        "created": 1737369159,
        "question": "Would a weekly research & review work in a course count as a project in the requirement?",
        "answer": "It is not definitively stated whether or not this will be counted. This is up for the admission committee to decide. However, you are encouraged to apply with these courses. If the course is 5 ECTS, then the project would also be recognized with the weight of the 5 ECTS.",
        "request_id": "7e95de77848da055c7aa51bbeca28273"
    },
    {
        "id": "ac65b5f3-b210-403c-9307-a5ccce8373ec",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_605.txt",
        "created": 1737369159,
        "question": "Does the practical project need to be recognized with credits, i.e. does it have to be part of my university course? Would individual projects or volunteer experience be able to also contribute to the requirement?",
        "answer": "Practical projects that were not part of a university module can be counted. However, you would then need to provide official documentation that those practical projects in total spanned at least 540 hours for completion (540h correspond to 18 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "7e95de77848da055c7aa51bbeca28273"
    },
    {
        "id": "d60ccbc6-22ff-4dce-9d8c-9a0bbb6fccbe",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_605.txt",
        "created": 1737369159,
        "question": "Can the project be part of a course or does it have to stand individually?",
        "answer": "The email does not provide a clear answer to this question. NO ANSWER.",
        "request_id": "7e95de77848da055c7aa51bbeca28273"
    },
    {
        "id": "69e71407-fd87-42d2-8056-bda6c8ec5194",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_606.txt",
        "created": 1737369173,
        "question": "Once I have my APS and all necessary documents can I apply for MSC AI in Society directly using TUMonline?",
        "answer": "As soon as you have all documents we are asking for, you are ready to apply. There is no additional step (other than taking care of the VPD, in case you haven\u2019t already).",
        "request_id": "dd4f6442c345c63657e1232d1f689a1f"
    },
    {
        "id": "afb52f78-dd53-4e1f-b8c2-f2ab3deb8685",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_606.txt",
        "created": 1737369173,
        "question": "What should I do if my Capstone project phase 2 results won't be available before the TUM application deadline ends?",
        "answer": "If you will not have your Capstone project phase 2 listed in your transcript by May 31st, it could be a possibility to have your professor issue a letter, in which he verifies that you took the course, what you did in it, and how many ECTS the course spanned. The grade is not needed for us, we only need to know that you passed, and how many ECTS you earned from the course. This letter should then also have some type of university stamp on it.",
        "request_id": "dd4f6442c345c63657e1232d1f689a1f"
    },
    {
        "id": "c1e4f736-866d-42e8-9e72-87ce26d1686b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_606.txt",
        "created": 1737369173,
        "question": "What should I include in the form for practical projects in the application portal?",
        "answer": "In the form for practical projects, please write a clear and concise description of what exactly you accomplished in your capstone project. Make sure to highlight the practical and interdisciplinary aspects.",
        "request_id": "dd4f6442c345c63657e1232d1f689a1f"
    },
    {
        "id": "976c1ea1-182a-4f9b-a8ee-a3eac3903b16",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_609.txt",
        "created": 1737369189,
        "question": "What should I do when I find a bug in the pdf template \u201cbest_credits_form_ais final\u201d?",
        "answer": "Please don\u2019t use the form filling function in those fields, but instead just put the text on top.",
        "request_id": "3bea55eb63ce4a21cdffa290dca25516"
    },
    {
        "id": "c2c53608-0172-4332-8500-b322feac0316",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_609.txt",
        "created": 1737369189,
        "question": "Should I attach the official document \u201cErg\u00e4nzende Erkl\u00e4rung zur Studienleistungsanrechnung_CDHAW\u201d directly to \u201cbest_credits_form_ais final\u201d for your reference?",
        "answer": "Yes, please attach this to your application. You can attach it to the end or beginning of the form, whichever way works.",
        "request_id": "3bea55eb63ce4a21cdffa290dca25516"
    },
    {
        "id": "960366b4-9962-4ba2-ab78-8c93eceeeaaa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_609.txt",
        "created": 1737369189,
        "question": "Would you recognize this document for your evaluation process?",
        "answer": "We will refer to it when converting your credits to ECTS, since it is an official statement from your university.",
        "request_id": "3bea55eb63ce4a21cdffa290dca25516"
    },
    {
        "id": "ce0f3392-bc94-4ffc-ac3b-a9b160cf0585",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_609.txt",
        "created": 1737369189,
        "question": "For the application for AI for Society, should I choose \u201cConsecutive masters courses\u201d OR \u201cSecond degree\u201d?",
        "answer": "I would choose \u201cSecond degree\u201d in this case, since it would be your second Master\u2019s degree.",
        "request_id": "3bea55eb63ce4a21cdffa290dca25516"
    },
    {
        "id": "3379cf41-dc5b-4d54-ad22-e816d9df1b5e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_609.txt",
        "created": 1737369189,
        "question": "For the \u201cEntrance qualification for Master\u2019s program\u201d in the application procedure, should I choose my on-going master program RCI at TUM OR choose one of my bachelor?",
        "answer": "Please name your Bachelor\u2019s degree here, as you can not apply to a Master\u2019s program with another Master\u2019s program.",
        "request_id": "3bea55eb63ce4a21cdffa290dca25516"
    },
    {
        "id": "8b8abb6a-5d44-4f6a-8fd4-b5e5f3584584",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_609.txt",
        "created": 1737369189,
        "question": "For the \u201cProof of passing module in math or statistics\u201d, can I use the course \u201c[REDACTED] and [REDACTED] (IN2028, 5 ECTS)\u201d at TUM?",
        "answer": "As mathematics and statistics are inherently part of [REDACTED], we would let this pass.",
        "request_id": "3bea55eb63ce4a21cdffa290dca25516"
    },
    {
        "id": "222070ab-0094-4f4f-9bfb-eef96a91a90a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_609.txt",
        "created": 1737369189,
        "question": "For the \u201cProof of successful participation in a practical project.. at least 18 credits\u201d, can I use my bachelor praktikum (10 ECTS) + TUM practical course (10 ECTS) to fulfill this requirement? Is my bachelor thesis (12 ECTS, a computer vision project) can also be recognized as a practical project here?",
        "answer": "For all three of your options: yes. In any case, please make sure their contents adhere to our requirements. As you come from a technical background, please make sure to especially highlight the interdisciplinary aspect of your projects.",
        "request_id": "3bea55eb63ce4a21cdffa290dca25516"
    },
    {
        "id": "eb1e83cc-6483-4749-a61b-55207d0b84ce",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_609.txt",
        "created": 1737369189,
        "question": "For the \u201cEvidence of English\u201d, I have already been checked with IELTS when I apply for the RCI master program, how can I fulfill this requirement automatically?",
        "answer": "In this case, please upload the same IELTS certificate again in your application to AI in Society.",
        "request_id": "3bea55eb63ce4a21cdffa290dca25516"
    },
    {
        "id": "c41b9c23-186d-43cc-8a1e-1ad18480f0e6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_610.txt",
        "created": 1737369210,
        "question": "Am I able to change my documents / reupload documents that have been submitted and not reviewed?",
        "answer": "You could upload additional documents/swap them out if they still haven\u2019t been reviewed.",
        "request_id": "4d3d6015510dcaaf3958e5e0c92f4146"
    },
    {
        "id": "83d13879-fcce-453e-b664-8c7e1edb2a9e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_611.txt",
        "created": 1737369216,
        "question": "What documents are needed for the application?",
        "answer": "All of your documents are needed by the application deadline (May 31st). If you will not have your Capstone project phase 2 listed in your transcript by May 31st, it could be a possibility to have your professor issue a letter, in which he verifies that you took the course, what you did in it, and how many ECTS the course spanned. The grade is not needed, only the information that you passed, and how many ECTS you earned from the course. This letter should then also have some type of university stamp on it.",
        "request_id": "929ec0f6b20f6cfe6f04b88ca44ddd3f"
    },
    {
        "id": "75eddaa9-a65a-44bb-b093-1299af5be4e0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_611.txt",
        "created": 1737369216,
        "question": "What should be included in the form for practical projects?",
        "answer": "In the form for practical projects, you should write a clear and concise description of what exactly you accomplished in your capstone project. The letter from your professor should be uploaded in your application, but in the form, you should describe in your own words what you did exactly. Make sure to highlight the practical and interdisciplinary aspects.",
        "request_id": "929ec0f6b20f6cfe6f04b88ca44ddd3f"
    },
    {
        "id": "ac886e46-4f2d-4bdf-8c75-6016722089f6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_611.txt",
        "created": 1737369216,
        "question": "What is the requirement for the letter issued by the professor?",
        "answer": "The letter issued by your professor should verify that you took the course, what you did in it, and how many ECTS the course spanned. The grade is not needed, only the information that you passed, and how many ECTS you earned from the course. This letter should also have some type of university stamp on it.",
        "request_id": "929ec0f6b20f6cfe6f04b88ca44ddd3f"
    },
    {
        "id": "1245cf93-755d-43e6-8ea2-eb2611bdcc74",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_612.txt",
        "created": 1737369228,
        "question": "In the application for AI for Society, should a student currently studying a master's degree at TUM select 'Consecutive masters courses' or 'Second degree'?",
        "answer": "In this case, 'Second degree' should be selected, as it would be the student's second Master\u2019s degree.",
        "request_id": "3a361ba0d9ab9a4ceda89d0bc2c034c3"
    },
    {
        "id": "f5db31aa-5a9f-45ed-b6d8-a341f6e172fb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_612.txt",
        "created": 1737369228,
        "question": "What should be referred to for the 'best 140 ECTS' in the form?",
        "answer": "For the 'best 140 ECTS', please refer to your bachelor\u2019s transcript.",
        "request_id": "3a361ba0d9ab9a4ceda89d0bc2c034c3"
    },
    {
        "id": "589d2772-9f42-40cc-9a90-0ffa54354740",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_613.txt",
        "created": 1737369234,
        "question": "For the \u201cEntrance qualification for Master\u2019s program\u201d in the application procedure, should I choose my on-going master program RCI at TUM OR choose one of my bachelor (I have a double bachelor degree)?",
        "answer": "Please name your Bachelor\u2019s degree here, as you can not apply to a Master\u2019s program with another Master\u2019s program.",
        "request_id": "85e4966c2cd34a2ba234faccecba49cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "97e4c6ff-407b-48ff-9a25-ff6fc34d5cde",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_613.txt",
        "created": 1737369234,
        "question": "For the \u201cProof of passing module in math or statistics\u201d, I would like to use the course \u201c[REDACTED] and [REDACTED] (IN2028, 5 ECTS)\u201d at TUM, Is it appropriate? Does this option strictly have to be pure math? E.g., linear algebra, statistics, etc.",
        "answer": "As mathematics and statistics are inherently part of [REDACTED], we would let this pass.",
        "request_id": "85e4966c2cd34a2ba234faccecba49cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "d52f7638-773e-41bb-9d02-05bba8ee01fb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_613.txt",
        "created": 1737369234,
        "question": "For the \u201cProof of successful participation in a practical project.. at leat 18 credits\u201d, can I use my bachelor praktikum (10 ECTS) + TUM practical course (10 ECTS) to fullfill this requirement? Is my bachelor thesis (12 ECTS, a computer vision project) can also be recognized as a practical project here?",
        "answer": "For all three of your options: yes. In any case, please make sure their contents adhere to our requirements: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/ As you come from a technical background, please make sure to especially highlight the interdisciplinary aspect of your projects.",
        "request_id": "85e4966c2cd34a2ba234faccecba49cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "97de2a9e-a383-44fa-bfd0-56756a02391f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_613.txt",
        "created": 1737369234,
        "question": "For the \u201cEvidence of English\u201d, I have already been checked with IELTS when I apply for the RCI master program, how can I fullfill this requirement automatically?",
        "answer": "In this case, please upload the same IELTS certificate again in your application to AI in Society.",
        "request_id": "85e4966c2cd34a2ba234faccecba49cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "9e3fd8f0-8987-48e7-9119-9f59d8d71c41",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_615.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "What is the application deadline for the MSC AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "The application deadline is May 31st.",
        "request_id": "6ed5d45568aa5135d9e63e4f0133e74f"
    },
    {
        "id": "a2b37af8-f64e-4dce-aefd-69c80f73899b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_615.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "Can exceptions be made if all documents are not available by the application deadline?",
        "answer": "No, all documents need to be submitted by the application deadline and no exceptions can be made.",
        "request_id": "6ed5d45568aa5135d9e63e4f0133e74f"
    },
    {
        "id": "7f6d9974-6e5e-4f81-a233-fbb1ca72d0b6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_615.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "What can be done if a course that fulfills the requirement of a practical project worth at least 18 credits is not listed in the transcript by the application deadline?",
        "answer": "It might be possible to have the professor issue a letter verifying that the course was taken, what was done in it, and how many ECTS the course spanned. The letter should also have some type of university stamp on it. The grade is not needed, only the information that the course was passed and how many ECTS were earned from it.",
        "request_id": "6ed5d45568aa5135d9e63e4f0133e74f"
    },
    {
        "id": "3272591b-3be7-41be-a20e-ce71c4c1ffab",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_615.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "Is the grade of the practical project required for the application to the MSC AI in Society at TUM?",
        "answer": "No, the grade is not needed. The application only needs to know that the course was passed and how many ECTS were earned from it.",
        "request_id": "6ed5d45568aa5135d9e63e4f0133e74f"
    },
    {
        "id": "cc577216-42e0-454e-80bf-cb36b91b06b8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_616.txt",
        "created": 1737369260,
        "question": "Does the university accept the result of the IELTS single subject having the 'retake' logo in one transcript or the result of the component of two tests?",
        "answer": "This should be fine, but it is advised to also add an explanation when uploading this document (for example, add another page at the very beginning, where you write this explanation). Otherwise, it will not be clear.",
        "request_id": "5687ca1f97fea25da9c6ee1644ec1a4f"
    },
    {
        "id": "7e7c4da4-3db5-4704-90c4-23005fdb12d2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_617.txt",
        "created": 1737369263,
        "question": "What is the missing documentation in my application for the AI in [REDACTED]'s Program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The practical project 'MIT ADSP Capstone Project' did not have sufficient proof to verify it.",
        "request_id": "0df2bee5597b3d6ac7b6a7d68da39d3e"
    },
    {
        "id": "84327569-1b12-4ae8-a40b-46e0b6306497",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_617.txt",
        "created": 1737369263,
        "question": "What can I do if I don't have the certificate from the MIT ADSP program yet?",
        "answer": "You can provide the certificate as soon as it is available to you. For now, you can submit your final submission document as proof.",
        "request_id": "0df2bee5597b3d6ac7b6a7d68da39d3e"
    },
    {
        "id": "692d812c-0a98-41ff-b42d-e58b7ab2fb24",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_617.txt",
        "created": 1737369263,
        "question": "Is it acceptable to provide the certificate for the MIT ADSP Capstone Project after the application deadline?",
        "answer": "If you can provide the certificate until the application deadline (May 31st), it will be fine.",
        "request_id": "0df2bee5597b3d6ac7b6a7d68da39d3e"
    },
    {
        "id": "f0b130ea-9e02-4317-bbd6-c44adea6661f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_618.txt",
        "created": 1737369269,
        "question": "Can I use my INSEAD MBA certificate and dean's letter as proof of my English skills for the AI in Society master's program application?",
        "answer": "You should upload your old TOEFL certificate, which you got in 2018. We will consider this as proof for your English knowledge.",
        "request_id": "cdd1af611f4aad869fac985b20e3b5d0"
    },
    {
        "id": "f2b7a667-16a6-4257-888f-a01235b03f99",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_618.txt",
        "created": 1737369269,
        "question": "The application form does not have enough space to list all my grades from my 2 bachelor's degrees and MBA. What should I do?",
        "answer": "You should duplicate the form, fill out as many rows as you need, and then merge the documents back into one for uploading.",
        "request_id": "cdd1af611f4aad869fac985b20e3b5d0"
    },
    {
        "id": "57a6aa9e-2cc5-4483-90c4-32eda2986b35",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_618.txt",
        "created": 1737369269,
        "question": "Can I use my INSEAD MBA degree certificate to prove that I have passed a program conducted in English?",
        "answer": "If you want to prove your English skills with a previous degree, it needs to be a degree conforming to EU standard durations (bachelor's: 6-8 semester, master's: 4 semesters minimum). With a 2 semester MBA, the requirement to prove English language skills cannot be met. Please submit a different proof of English language skills like a TOEFL, IELTS or other accepted test score as instructed.",
        "request_id": "cdd1af611f4aad869fac985b20e3b5d0"
    },
    {
        "id": "82de0125-6980-4f0c-8c24-56a87cb32d0b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_618.txt",
        "created": 1737369269,
        "question": "In the list of credits, do I need to select the best 140 credits of the Bachelor I'm applying with?",
        "answer": "In the list of credits you need to select the best 140 credits of the Bachelor you're applying with. This means the relevant subjects are only from the Bachelor in Economics.",
        "request_id": "cdd1af611f4aad869fac985b20e3b5d0"
    },
    {
        "id": "f07e5b3c-55de-48c5-a2c0-77b135f0c8fa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_621.txt",
        "created": 1737369284,
        "question": "Regarding the English language proficiency requirement, would my master\u2019s degree be sufficient proof of language proficiency if it was taught entirely in English?",
        "answer": "Yes, if your previous study program was taught entirely in English, it is accepted as proof of your English knowledge. If the certificate you upload states the language of the study program, this is enough.",
        "request_id": "40586e785dd099c7a22e68881edb0a27"
    },
    {
        "id": "75edaa8f-df59-4e1b-aaac-0014409127c8",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_621.txt",
        "created": 1737369284,
        "question": "Can a previous master\u2019s degree be an entrance qualification for a master\u2019s degree?",
        "answer": "No, you can\u2019t actually apply to a Master\u2019s program with another Master\u2019s degree. Please apply with your Bachelor\u2019s degree \u2013 it is not a problem if that degree was obtained from another country.",
        "request_id": "40586e785dd099c7a22e68881edb0a27"
    },
    {
        "id": "65ea8995-7282-4474-9eea-9438a9e6b583",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_622.txt",
        "created": 1737369293,
        "question": "Is the MSc. AI in Society program at TUM open to students with an engineering background?",
        "answer": "Yes, students with an engineering background can apply to the MSc. AI in Society program.",
        "request_id": "4cb90d57fb7d0ec975d4a4b9d1b9126c"
    },
    {
        "id": "a8e31b7f-0acf-4fb4-94bd-1dfdc3a05718",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_622.txt",
        "created": 1737369293,
        "question": "Is a practical project with a minimum of 18 ECTS required for application to the MSc. AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Yes, the admission requirements state that a practical project of at least 18 ECTS must be demonstrated at the time of application.",
        "request_id": "4cb90d57fb7d0ec975d4a4b9d1b9126c"
    },
    {
        "id": "d932d014-57d3-4dcb-a331-96e210a8d296",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_625.txt",
        "created": 1737369304,
        "question": "How can I fill in my courses equivalent to 140 credits if the given form is not enough?",
        "answer": "Duplicate the form, fill out however many fields you need, merge the documents back into one, and upload it like this.",
        "request_id": "4c3681aa9136a65a0e4f14dca65f56f9"
    },
    {
        "id": "be03f10f-114b-4cb5-bac6-d8dc2adf3525",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_630.txt",
        "created": 1737369310,
        "question": "Can I apply to the Masters program in AI in society at TUM if I have not yet completed my Bachelor's degree?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can apply to the study program even if you still haven\u2019t finished your Bachelors degree. Instead, you should submit your current Transcript of Records, which should span at least 140 ECTS credits. However, you will need to submit your final Bachelors certificate if you get admitted to the study program.",
        "request_id": "ea0bef6d7ca7d562b547871083a1703e"
    },
    {
        "id": "3848f396-e145-40dd-9ab8-4236d20a9e65",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_631.txt",
        "created": 1737369128,
        "question": "Do I only need to list the courses with the highest grades from top to low, or do I need to list the courses with the highest credits?",
        "answer": "You should list your courses sorted from highest grade to lowest grade.",
        "request_id": "cb9fd428b16af1a9833fde79d8094eff"
    },
    {
        "id": "a406830b-3688-4c8a-809e-1540f5654934",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_631.txt",
        "created": 1737369128,
        "question": "Will the content of this course I list affect the outcome of my application?",
        "answer": "The content of the course will affect your application only in a good way: the form is essentially just some help for the admissions team to see right away, which of your modules are your best, without manually sorting through your Transcript of Records.",
        "request_id": "cb9fd428b16af1a9833fde79d8094eff"
    },
    {
        "id": "ac1b286d-0be5-42f2-8cea-f5534c18794b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_631.txt",
        "created": 1737369128,
        "question": "If I filled all the tables of the document, but it didn't reach the requirement of 140 ECT in total, can I duplicate the table and add courses to let the total number of credits of all courses listed reach 140 ECT?",
        "answer": "Yes, if there is not enough space, you can duplicate the form.",
        "request_id": "cb9fd428b16af1a9833fde79d8094eff"
    },
    {
        "id": "e77f5005-87a3-41a5-ab37-735584404d95",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_632.txt",
        "created": 1737369137,
        "question": "Do I only need to list the courses with the highest grades from top to low, or do I need to list the courses with the highest credits for the 'List of 140 best credits' document?",
        "answer": "You should list your courses sorted from highest grade to lowest grade.",
        "request_id": "7179e3c54220def07396418468c2043b"
    },
    {
        "id": "e3ec439b-d2b7-416c-b870-9956312ed0d5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_632.txt",
        "created": 1737369137,
        "question": "Will the content of the courses I list in the 'List of 140 best credits' document affect the outcome of my application?",
        "answer": "This will affect your application only in a good way: we're asking for this sorting, because we only consider your best grades for calculating your admission score. This form is essentially just some help for us to see right away, which of your modules are your best, without manually sorting through your Transcript of Records.",
        "request_id": "7179e3c54220def07396418468c2043b"
    },
    {
        "id": "b9889f27-53a1-4eb7-a35a-bf3181812af5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_633.txt",
        "created": 1737369314,
        "question": "Is a Bachelor's thesis written in English sufficient as proof of English proficiency for the MSc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Yes, a Bachelor's thesis written in English is also sufficient as proof for our program.",
        "request_id": "55bd4c4a928e2b5403eb13f6986d4fa8"
    },
    {
        "id": "451c5e34-2c13-4deb-bddc-6e1291b5298f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_633.txt",
        "created": 1737369314,
        "question": "What are the requirements for the proof of English proficiency for the MSc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The proof of English proficiency must include at least 15 ECTS. If your Bachelor's thesis has fewer ECTS (e.g., 12 ECTS), you would formally need to provide an additional 3 ECTS from an English-taught module that you have attended.",
        "request_id": "55bd4c4a928e2b5403eb13f6986d4fa8"
    },
    {
        "id": "5edddeb6-c8d3-4391-aaca-66141c3df36a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_633.txt",
        "created": 1737369314,
        "question": "What documents are acceptable as proof of English proficiency for the MSc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The English title must be noted in the transcript as a successful academic achievement and it must be evident from the transcript that the thesis was written in English; otherwise, a separate certificate from the university about the language of the Bachelor's thesis must be submitted. If you want to count a different document as proof, please upload either a) a corresponding transcript (see above), or b) a separate certificate from your university.",
        "request_id": "55bd4c4a928e2b5403eb13f6986d4fa8"
    },
    {
        "id": "bf5d2bdb-8381-4a19-8e5c-dcc1c909f321",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_633.txt",
        "created": 1737369314,
        "question": "What should I do if I don't have enough ECTS for the practical project for the MSc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "If you don't have enough ECTS for the practical project, you might want to consider whether you can gather 6 ECTS - perhaps you have done practical projects during your semester abroad, or completed internships, or worked as a working student, or similar. We also credit non-university experience. Here we then roughly go by the number of hours (1 ECTS = 30h).",
        "request_id": "55bd4c4a928e2b5403eb13f6986d4fa8"
    },
    {
        "id": "3a57f054-e681-497d-9fad-93c49fceb963",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_633.txt",
        "created": 1737369314,
        "question": "What documents are required if I want to submit work experience/internships/etc. for the practical project for the MSc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "If you want to submit work experience/internships/etc., we would need a work certificate that shows: a) what you did there in terms of content, and b) how long the relationship lasted.",
        "request_id": "55bd4c4a928e2b5403eb13f6986d4fa8"
    },
    {
        "id": "bddf2a14-4d54-4b97-a4f6-ceeba9632964",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_634.txt",
        "created": 1737369143,
        "question": "What is the ECTS requirement for the English proficiency proof in the AIS application?",
        "answer": "The English proficiency proof should cover 15 ECTS. If an English Bachelor's thesis, for example, only covers 12 ECTS, it is not sufficient, and the applicant would need to prove the missing 3 ECTS through another module conducted in English.",
        "request_id": "cc26105b3ce04d8ac49fa36ec388282e"
    },
    {
        "id": "4aa4f8eb-5238-47ca-81e9-d3458ea195a4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_634.txt",
        "created": 1737369143,
        "question": "Can an English Bachelor's thesis be used as proof of English proficiency in the AIS application?",
        "answer": "Yes, an English Bachelor's thesis can be used as proof of English proficiency in the AIS application.",
        "request_id": "cc26105b3ce04d8ac49fa36ec388282e"
    },
    {
        "id": "3840d5d0-e298-465b-ab27-d2f41a322ce7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_635.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "Is an English-written Bachelor's thesis sufficient as a language proof for the AI and Society Master's program?",
        "answer": "For our program, an English-written Bachelor's thesis is also sufficient as proof.",
        "request_id": "4fbc37814cd49725f2eb35d550d8b7f1"
    },
    {
        "id": "06ed145d-846d-4c4a-9bb8-73d2ceb628f4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_635.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "What are the requirements for the English language proof to be accepted for the AI and Society Master's program?",
        "answer": "The English language proof, provided by university courses, must cover at least 15 ECTS. If your Bachelor's thesis covers less (e.g., 12 ECTS), you would formally have to prove 3 ECTS through an English module that you have attended.",
        "request_id": "4fbc37814cd49725f2eb35d550d8b7f1"
    },
    {
        "id": "f8fb1717-2cef-47aa-af8a-ec5d656759ff",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_635.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "What should be noted for the English language proof for the AI and Society Master's program?",
        "answer": "Please note that the Bachelor's thesis must already have been submitted and graded for it to be considered as proof. The English title must be noted in the transcript as a successful academic achievement and it must be clear from the transcript that the work was written in English; otherwise, a separate certificate from the university about the language of the Bachelor's thesis must be submitted.",
        "request_id": "4fbc37814cd49725f2eb35d550d8b7f1"
    },
    {
        "id": "b7cf4e9f-317c-4011-9c6d-07f63e726872",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_635.txt",
        "created": 1737369149,
        "question": "What should be done if the document uploaded in the application portal cannot be considered as English language proof for the AI and Society Master's program?",
        "answer": "If you want to count your Bachelor's thesis as proof instead, please upload either a) a corresponding transcript (see above), or b) a separate certificate from the university at this point.",
        "request_id": "4fbc37814cd49725f2eb35d550d8b7f1"
    },
    {
        "id": "85307b38-69df-49d2-8ca6-0cb0418d33cf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_637.txt",
        "created": 1737369162,
        "question": "Do I meet the criteria required for admission to the Master's program AI in Society if I have a degree program of 180 ECTS, 79 ECTS in the legal field and 101 ECTS in the business field, a Bachelor of Science degree, and practical experience through a mandatory internship of 2 months, a 3-month working student job and a 3-month internship in the legal and tax area?",
        "answer": "You bring along sufficient experience, since we also count practical experience outside of university (i.e. work experience, internships, etc). The way we make this ECTS-comparable is by calculating from hours to credits (1 ECTS credit = 30 hrs). So your in total 7 months of internships/jobs would cover the requirement. However, the content of your practical experiences should have interdisciplinarity and strongly require a practical aspect in the form of implementation(programming), some kind of data analysis, or similar, applied to some sort of field in society.",
        "request_id": "315e89edc714ab93b4bae1140aed2ba8"
    },
    {
        "id": "3d6cefcc-3a79-41f0-a0b3-07428046bd07",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_637.txt",
        "created": 1737369162,
        "question": "Do I fulfill the requirement of the practical project worth at least 18 ECTS or can I make up for it during the course of my studies?",
        "answer": "We need proof of 18 ECTS practical experience by the application deadline. Anything that is only available afterwards cannot be taken into account. If you have taken any suitable practical modules, or if you can think of any other practical experience, we could credit that. Unfortunately, we cannot issue requirements to catch up.",
        "request_id": "315e89edc714ab93b4bae1140aed2ba8"
    },
    {
        "id": "7ba3ca2e-705e-438a-8efd-d8c862415ccd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_638.txt",
        "created": 1737369335,
        "question": "Do I meet the criteria required for admission to the AI in Society Master's program at the University of Augsburg?",
        "answer": "Regarding the scope of the 18 ECTS, you bring along sufficient experience, since we also count practical experience outside of university (i.e. work experience, internships, etc). The way we make this ECTS-comparable is by calculating from hours to credits (1 ECTS credit = 30 hrs). So your in total 7 months of internships/jobs would cover the requirement.",
        "request_id": "767649214d0807c7495de2d2e6893b45"
    },
    {
        "id": "8b9a4ca7-4e9c-4203-92cd-1f4af68f5b0e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_638.txt",
        "created": 1737369335,
        "question": "Do I fulfill the requirement of the practical project worth at least 18 ECTS or can I make up for it during the course of my studies?",
        "answer": "The problem might rather be concerning the content of your practical experiences: what do you mean exactly by legal/tax area? When we are screening applications, we are looking for interdisciplinarity in the applicant\u2019s project(s) and strongly require a practical aspect in the form of implementation(programming), some kind of data analysis, or similar, applied to some sort of field in society (which would, in your case, be the legal/tax area).",
        "request_id": "767649214d0807c7495de2d2e6893b45"
    },
    {
        "id": "b48af1ce-856a-4f3f-8293-3a1ed042f618",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_639.txt",
        "created": 1737369175,
        "question": "Do I meet the criteria required for admission to the Master's program AI in Society with a degree program of 180 ECTS, 79 ECTS in the legal field, 101 ECTS in the business field, a Bachelor of Science degree, and practical experience through internships and jobs in the legal and tax area?",
        "answer": "You bring along sufficient experience, since we also count practical experience outside of university. The way we make this ECTS-comparable is by calculating from hours to credits (1 ECTS credit = 30 hrs). So your in total 7 months of internships/jobs would cover the requirement. However, the content of your practical experiences is also important. We are looking for interdisciplinarity in the applicant\u2019s project(s) and strongly require a practical aspect in the form of implementation(programming), some kind of data analysis, or similar, applied to some sort of field in society.",
        "request_id": "3eac30fa7cc7cfffb1e5d85b37875940"
    },
    {
        "id": "1ee95343-5417-4ce0-a3dd-ff7381e4ab33",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_639.txt",
        "created": 1737369175,
        "question": "Do I fulfill the requirement of the practical project worth at least 18 ECTS or can I make up for it during the course of my studies?",
        "answer": "Your total 7 months of internships/jobs would cover the requirement of the practical project worth at least 18 ECTS. However, the content of your practical experiences is also important. We are looking for interdisciplinarity in the applicant\u2019s project(s) and strongly require a practical aspect in the form of implementation(programming), some kind of data analysis, or similar, applied to some sort of field in society.",
        "request_id": "3eac30fa7cc7cfffb1e5d85b37875940"
    },
    {
        "id": "00a52f17-16b1-47bc-acf2-beab214ff61c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_640.txt",
        "created": 1737369185,
        "question": "Do I need to submit a language proficiency certificate for the AI in Society Master's program application?",
        "answer": "Yes, a language proficiency certificate is required for the application.",
        "request_id": "39bc2aa6f24a913d737ec1d576c20bbc"
    },
    {
        "id": "412cde60-6262-4607-bcb7-2299321b07ac",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_640.txt",
        "created": 1737369185,
        "question": "Can a Bachelor's thesis written in English be considered as proof of English proficiency for the AI in Society Master's program?",
        "answer": "Yes, a Bachelor's thesis written in English is sufficient as proof of English proficiency for the AI in Society program.",
        "request_id": "39bc2aa6f24a913d737ec1d576c20bbc"
    },
    {
        "id": "5025a551-b7ec-4f9a-86cc-42d8da8cec96",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_640.txt",
        "created": 1737369185,
        "question": "What are the requirements for the Bachelor's thesis to be considered as proof of English proficiency?",
        "answer": "The Bachelor's thesis must already be submitted and graded. The English title must be noted in the transcript as a successful academic achievement, and it must be clear from the transcript that the thesis was written in English. Otherwise, a separate certificate from the university about the language of the Bachelor's thesis must be submitted.",
        "request_id": "39bc2aa6f24a913d737ec1d576c20bbc"
    },
    {
        "id": "d74dd722-3b18-4571-bcea-890ac3c30597",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_640.txt",
        "created": 1737369185,
        "question": "What should I do if the document I uploaded as proof of English proficiency is not accepted?",
        "answer": "If the document you uploaded cannot be considered as proof of English proficiency, please upload either a) a corresponding transcript (as described above), or b) a separate certificate from the university.",
        "request_id": "39bc2aa6f24a913d737ec1d576c20bbc"
    },
    {
        "id": "820000a7-2a5b-4d58-8de7-c2214e001ee9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_642.txt",
        "created": 1737369197,
        "question": "Is a Bachelor's thesis written in English sufficient as a language proficiency proof for the AI and Society Master's program?",
        "answer": "For the AI in Society program, a Bachelor's thesis written in English is also sufficient as proof of language proficiency.",
        "request_id": "c14ef7035bc134daf4cc3db1fbd8b127"
    },
    {
        "id": "ab2f8a61-4312-4338-8656-2d78ab6141cf",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_643.txt",
        "created": 1737369347,
        "question": "Is it possible for / would TUM consider my Masters degree which is quantitatively heavier than my Bachelors degree, in addition to my Bachelors degree and count it towards achieving the 48 points in Part 1 of the application process when I submit my application to this program?",
        "answer": "For this part, we can only consider the applicants\u2019 Bachelors degrees. However, if you completed some projects in your Masters that could count towards e.g. the 18 ECTS practical project requirement, you are welcome to list them there (in this case, please provide your Masters degree transcript as well).",
        "request_id": "ac63f954a2f513207eefd5d0f5c9c3ad"
    },
    {
        "id": "1b1d95e2-b83a-40ce-b8bd-630a6bddfd70",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_643.txt",
        "created": 1737369347,
        "question": "Is it possible / would TUM consider my internship experience gained during my Masters degree and/or my six (6) plus years of professional experience working for the [REDACTED] Department of Transportation as a [REDACTED] in lieu of these 18 ECTS credit hours?",
        "answer": "Yes, it is possible to provide evidence of practical experience that was not gained as part of your studies, but rather as working experience or similar. In this case, please provide us some documents (like a certificate of employment), which indicates to us: a) the content of your work, and b) the duration (18 ECTS are equivalent to 540 hours of work). Same thing applies to your internship experience.",
        "request_id": "ac63f954a2f513207eefd5d0f5c9c3ad"
    },
    {
        "id": "6dad1b7c-9365-4fa6-9f86-d68832c10597",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_643.txt",
        "created": 1737369347,
        "question": "Once I submit my documents and if I am fortunate enough to be admitted, would I be able to defer enrollment by a year?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can apply for the study program, get an offer for a place, and accept it only a year later. In this case, you\u2019d do the following: refuse the offer. Re-apply to the program a year later (please then upload the basic documents again, like an up-to-date CV, since a year will have passed). Afterwards, you won\u2019t have to go through the aptitude assessment process anymore, but will go straight to admission.",
        "request_id": "ac63f954a2f513207eefd5d0f5c9c3ad"
    },
    {
        "id": "604631db-4737-4019-a9e5-01848ae2d653",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_643.txt",
        "created": 1737369347,
        "question": "If the decision rendered is admitted/accepted and I chose to defer would I automatically be accepted for the following academic year?",
        "answer": "As far as I know, you will not be automatically accepted into the next year\u2019s cohort, since you will have declined the offer. However, if you then re-apply the following year, the system will still \u201cremember\u201d you passing the procedure the year prior, allowing us to accept you right away. But please keep in mind that you also need to pass the written aptitude test in order to receive an offer.",
        "request_id": "ac63f954a2f513207eefd5d0f5c9c3ad"
    },
    {
        "id": "b6115246-2213-42c8-8481-733c429f585d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_643.txt",
        "created": 1737369347,
        "question": "Regarding the Math and Statistics portion of submitting my documents, I received an email saying it was incorrect, however I am uncertain how to correct it.",
        "answer": "The portal says: \u201cPlease list only academic achievements in mathematics\u201d as the issue. And looking at your filled out form, you have indeed listed modules such as economics. The issue doesn\u2019t seem to have anything to do with the modules stemming from your Masters degree. If you fix this and re-upload the form, it should be fine.",
        "request_id": "ac63f954a2f513207eefd5d0f5c9c3ad"
    },
    {
        "id": "5394f694-f3c1-4cdb-b5a6-26584f90f412",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_645.txt",
        "created": 1737369200,
        "question": "Who converts credits from non-ECTS systems for AIS applications and how is this done?",
        "answer": "Sandra is responsible for converting credits from non-ECTS systems for AIS applications.",
        "request_id": "e3d97822cf43bdd140788e07d59b666e"
    },
    {
        "id": "90c2ff90-2a10-4c07-b7f3-cebec7eb2293",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_646.txt",
        "created": 1737369372,
        "question": "Who is responsible for converting credits from non-ECTS systems for AIS applications, and how is this done?",
        "answer": "Sandra, who is included in the email, can explain how she converts performance points and credits from non-ECTS areas.",
        "request_id": "bdcf92437365a2fe90ed86c2cf540acb"
    },
    {
        "id": "e0ad2a88-1113-41a9-bd8d-db6f39f216c3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_649.txt",
        "created": 1737369208,
        "question": "Is it possible for / would TUM consider my Masters degree which is quantitatively heavier than my Bachelors degree, in addition to my Bachelors degree and count it towards achieving the 48 points in Part 1 of the application process when I submit my application to this program?",
        "answer": "For this part, we can only consider the applicants\u2019 Bachelors degrees. However, if you completed some projects in your Masters that could count towards e.g. the 18 ECTS practical project requirement, you are welcome to list them there (in this case, please provide your Masters degree transcript as well).",
        "request_id": "dbe4d2f4a21eb786cc38bb0df7db56cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "1940e392-7492-4571-84eb-e948766da5e6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_649.txt",
        "created": 1737369208,
        "question": "Is it possible / would TUM consider my internship experience gained during my Masters degree and/or my six (6) plus years of professional experience working for the [REDACTED] Department of Transportation as a [REDACTED] in lieu of these 18 ECTS credit hours?",
        "answer": "Yes, it is possible to provide evidence of practical experience that was not gained as part of your studies, but rather as working experience or similar. In this case, please provide us some documents (like a certificate of employment), which indicates to us: a) the content of your work, and b) the duration (18 ECTS are equivalent to 540 hours of work). Same thing applies to your internship experience.",
        "request_id": "dbe4d2f4a21eb786cc38bb0df7db56cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "cbc1b75d-644e-4fb4-8683-105c49eac421",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_649.txt",
        "created": 1737369208,
        "question": "Once I submit my documents and if I am fortunate enough to be admitted, would I be able to defer enrollment by a year?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can apply for the study program, get an offer for a place, and accept it only a year later. In this case, you\u2019d do the following: refuse the offer. Re-apply to the program a year later (please then upload the basic documents again, like an up-to-date CV, since a year will have passed). Afterwards, you won\u2019t have to go through the aptitude assessment process anymore, but will go straight to admission.",
        "request_id": "dbe4d2f4a21eb786cc38bb0df7db56cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "3faad6e6-0105-4840-81cc-22f82f727598",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_649.txt",
        "created": 1737369208,
        "question": "If the decision rendered is admitted/accepted and I chose to defer would I automatically be accepted for the following academic year?",
        "answer": "You will not be automatically accepted into the next year\u2019s cohort, since you will have declined the offer. However, if you then re-apply the following year, the system will still \u201cremember\u201d you passing the procedure the year prior, allowing us to accept you right away. But please keep in mind that you also need to pass the written aptitude test in order to receive an offer.",
        "request_id": "dbe4d2f4a21eb786cc38bb0df7db56cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "7dfa385e-672d-40df-a43d-1bb38bed8997",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_649.txt",
        "created": 1737369208,
        "question": "Is the list of best credits different from a transcript? Do I need to provide this?",
        "answer": "In the application form, there will be a separate form for you to fill in your list of best 140 ECTS credits. This is simply some help for us in order to calculate your aptitude score, where we only consider (a fraction of) your grades during your studies, i.e. the best ones. So, yes, this is different from your official transcript, which lists all your modules. You\u2019re correct, AI in Society is indeed not listed as one of the programs asking for this document.",
        "request_id": "dbe4d2f4a21eb786cc38bb0df7db56cf"
    },
    {
        "id": "9b97825b-ae79-4a28-b9c5-7670a67013d3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_650.txt",
        "created": 1737369234,
        "question": "Can I include my Bachelor thesis as part of the proof for the completed practical project requirement for the M.Sc. AI in Society application, even if it won't be officially finalized by the application deadline?",
        "answer": "No, practical projects which will not be finalized by the application deadline cannot be accepted.",
        "request_id": "3247eb3308ce12b1177de949b649c7c1"
    },
    {
        "id": "aad1c897-4a9c-42bb-9286-b1b6147637fe",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_650.txt",
        "created": 1737369234,
        "question": "Can I include my 2 years of work experience in analyzing social media trends as part of the proof for the completed practical project requirement for the M.Sc. AI in Society application?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can include your work experience. You need to submit a work certificate from your company, which states what you have been working on and how long you have been working there. The duration of your work is relevant for the ECTS requirement \u2013 it is recalculated from hours to ECTS to make it comparable. For reference, 1 ECTS corresponds to 30 hours. Your work experience should cover 6x30 hours = 180 hours, which should suffice if you've been working there for over 2 years.",
        "request_id": "3247eb3308ce12b1177de949b649c7c1"
    },
    {
        "id": "b7e23d7d-2b6e-48af-a62d-2efa8d7c6916",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_650.txt",
        "created": 1737369234,
        "question": "What kind of work experience is considered relevant for the M.Sc. AI in Society application?",
        "answer": "Interdisciplinary work experience is considered relevant. Pure computer science/programming work is not interdisciplinary. Work experience such as social media trend analysis, data analytics, generating insights, building a program to help solve societal problems, etc., is what is looked for when screening the applications.",
        "request_id": "3247eb3308ce12b1177de949b649c7c1"
    },
    {
        "id": "77b7ae3e-dce5-48cc-a78f-37e3839603d7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_650.txt",
        "created": 1737369234,
        "question": "Can I include my research paper on meat production analysis as part of the proof for the completed practical project requirement for the M.Sc. AI in Society application?",
        "answer": "Yes, if there was some practical/implementation aspect included (i.e. it was not a literature review kind of paper, but you actually ran some analysis yourself), it would make sense to include this.",
        "request_id": "3247eb3308ce12b1177de949b649c7c1"
    },
    {
        "id": "1b95c6aa-913e-43f5-a13c-6544d6ff31e4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_651.txt",
        "created": 1737369379,
        "question": "Do the 18 ECTS required for the practical project need to come from a single project or can they be combined from different projects?",
        "answer": "The credits for the practical project do not need to come from a single module. They can be summed up from several modules.",
        "request_id": "8a5b12b9f28a8f698d818330533e24dd"
    },
    {
        "id": "50e41ec8-8b5c-4872-a6b5-582b8b756b7b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_651.txt",
        "created": 1737369379,
        "question": "Is it a problem for the application if my bachelor's thesis is not completed at the time of my application, so I will not have a grade or ECTS for it at that time?",
        "answer": "If you do not have the credits for the bachelor's thesis at the time of application, it is a problem insofar as you cannot provide them as proof for the practical project. It is also not possible to submit evidence for the 'practical project' requirement afterwards. These must be available at the end of the application.",
        "request_id": "8a5b12b9f28a8f698d818330533e24dd"
    },
    {
        "id": "1993013b-df1e-4955-845c-fa4ea9c3e968",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_651.txt",
        "created": 1737369379,
        "question": "Can I possibly prove the missing 6 ECTS through professional experience or other relevant (extracurricular) activities?",
        "answer": "For non-ECTS-based experiences (i.e., professional experience), we ask applicants to submit a work certificate or similar documentation. It must be clear to us: a) what the applicant has dealt with in terms of content, and b) the period in which the employment relationship existed (we roughly convert to hours. 1 ECTS corresponds to approx. 30h. Your missing 2 ECTS should be easily covered).",
        "request_id": "8a5b12b9f28a8f698d818330533e24dd"
    },
    {
        "id": "243fb64b-56a3-45cf-a44a-bb6cde16c3c9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_651.txt",
        "created": 1737369379,
        "question": "Is it possible to credit my professional experience for the 'practical project' requirement?",
        "answer": "You should indicate your work-student activity in the 'Practical Project' section when applying. For non-ECTS-based experiences (i.e., professional experience), we ask applicants to submit a work certificate or similar documentation. It must be clear to us: a) what the applicant has dealt with in terms of content, and b) the period in which the employment relationship existed (we roughly convert to hours. 1 ECTS corresponds to approx. 30h. Your missing 2 ECTS should be easily covered).",
        "request_id": "8a5b12b9f28a8f698d818330533e24dd"
    },
    {
        "id": "4523c851-723a-4bbb-ba17-14fc46d17d17",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_652.txt",
        "created": 1737369249,
        "question": "In the requirements for the MSc. AI in Society, it is mentioned that applicants should have completed a practical project worth at least 18 credits during their bachelor\u2019s studies. Would I still be eligible for this program if the sum of my completed modules would meet the required 18 credit points?",
        "answer": "Yes, you are free to submit multiple practical modules which in sum make up 18 ECTS. The wording is a bit confusing, leading people to think that we require one single project worth 18 credits.",
        "request_id": "70fb42d61e1e136e27c7b8d698ce03fa"
    },
    {
        "id": "648f487f-2f61-4846-b600-cf987dcb40ae",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_653.txt",
        "created": 1737369394,
        "question": "What should I write as a declaration of authorship in my motivation letter?",
        "answer": "You can write the following: \u201cI hereby certify that this letter is solely my own work, developed without assistance, and any external sources are marked as such.\u201d",
        "request_id": "a0db821092b03bd67dbf04caa491ec05"
    },
    {
        "id": "2e592e53-1b8c-4ca4-bca2-c56589024149",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_653.txt",
        "created": 1737369394,
        "question": "Where can I upload my letter of recommendation to document my previous professional experience?",
        "answer": "Please attach it in the field for the proof of practical project.",
        "request_id": "a0db821092b03bd67dbf04caa491ec05"
    },
    {
        "id": "a46f29df-6ea7-4ec6-8590-579fcbf22ecb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_653.txt",
        "created": 1737369394,
        "question": "Do you also need proof of my self-employment, or are my examinations in the motivation letter and CV enough?",
        "answer": "Unfortunately, we cannot accept self-employment as evidence of practical experience, since no formal, objective, and independent certificate of employment can be issued. Please list evidence such as university modules, internships, or (\u201cregular\u201d) employment.",
        "request_id": "a0db821092b03bd67dbf04caa491ec05"
    },
    {
        "id": "eb4c2d06-1faf-4146-b3b0-03e1fe405b0d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_653.txt",
        "created": 1737369394,
        "question": "Why only the test score and GPA are considered for credit, while other application processes, such as Politics & Technology, MMT etc., credit the motivation letter and core modules from the previous academic background?",
        "answer": "Different study programs have different requirements for their prospective students. In our case, for example, we put a high weight on the applicant\u2019s ability to complete practical projects as well as bring along background knowledge in certain fields, which we are testing in the aptitude test. Other study programs might have different requirements.",
        "request_id": "a0db821092b03bd67dbf04caa491ec05"
    },
    {
        "id": "3d7ae600-d914-49c0-abb7-de9bfa9be4b0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_654.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "Can I apply for the study program, get an offer for a place, and accept it only a year later?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can apply for the study program, get an offer for a place, and accept it only a year later. In this case, you\u2019d do the following: refuse the offer. Re-apply to the program a year later (please then upload the basic documents again, like an up-to-date CV, since a year will have passed). Afterwards, you won\u2019t have to go through the aptitude assessment process anymore, but will go straight to admission.",
        "request_id": "4a29318ed236942407233d0a3134c8bc"
    },
    {
        "id": "3d706a7f-3378-4b25-ba37-194f85cf8bcd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_654.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "Can I submit my proof over maths/statistics modules from my Master\u2019s?",
        "answer": "You can submit your proof over maths/statistics modules from your Master\u2019s, as well. In this case, please also attach the Transcript of Records from your Master\u2019s, so we can verify.",
        "request_id": "4a29318ed236942407233d0a3134c8bc"
    },
    {
        "id": "dae58a67-4c70-4217-a81c-bf4e63d18dd5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_654.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "Can I submit an offer letter as proof of employment?",
        "answer": "It would be better if you could submit the certificates of employment to us, since an offer letter doesn\u2019t indicate that you actually took the offer.",
        "request_id": "4a29318ed236942407233d0a3134c8bc"
    },
    {
        "id": "6d61aa68-6e88-4f8e-8bd0-a62b1f6b6043",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_654.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "What is the 'list of best credits' and do I need to provide it for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The 'list of best credits' is a separate form for you to fill in your list of best 140 ECTS credits. This is simply some help for us in order to calculate your aptitude score, where we only consider (a fraction of) your grades during your studies, i.e. the best ones. This is different from your official transcript, which lists all your modules. AI in Society is indeed not listed as one of the programs asking for this document.",
        "request_id": "4a29318ed236942407233d0a3134c8bc"
    },
    {
        "id": "e09a8376-5c57-4255-bbed-ffbe697d954e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_654.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "Can TUM consider my Masters degree, which is quantitatively heavier than my Bachelors degree, in addition to my Bachelors degree and count it towards achieving the 48 points in Part 1 of the application process?",
        "answer": "For this part, we can only consider the applicants\u2019 Bachelors degrees. However, if you completed some projects in your Masters that could count towards e.g. the 18 ECTS practical project requirement, you are welcome to list them there (in this case, please provide your Masters degree transcript as well).",
        "request_id": "4a29318ed236942407233d0a3134c8bc"
    },
    {
        "id": "f29ee45d-925e-4858-b80c-cad58ee98d7a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_654.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "Can TUM consider my internship experience gained during my Masters degree and/or my six (6) plus years of professional experience working for the Department of Transportation as a in lieu of these 18 ECTS credit hours?",
        "answer": "Yes, it is possible to provide evidence of practical experience that was not gained as part of your studies, but rather as working experience or similar. In this case, please provide us some documents (like a certificate of employment), which indicates to us: a) the content of your work, and b) the duration (18 ECTS are equivalent to 540 hours of work). Same thing applies to your internship experience.",
        "request_id": "4a29318ed236942407233d0a3134c8bc"
    },
    {
        "id": "5d417d7d-59c4-40a6-bc34-83305573bd86",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_655.txt",
        "created": 1737369282,
        "question": "Can the email about the VR study be forwarded to the students of the upcoming course?",
        "answer": "The course only starts next winter semester, so there are currently no students to forward the email to.",
        "request_id": "d28c57e806725fdf746884ebc1073199"
    },
    {
        "id": "36f51212-4e1b-4c09-bf99-6a69cbac5879",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_655.txt",
        "created": 1737369282,
        "question": "What is the VR study about?",
        "answer": "The VR study is about understanding the integration of immersive media into the classroom. It is conducted by the Chair of Teaching and Learning with digital media at TUM.",
        "request_id": "d28c57e806725fdf746884ebc1073199"
    },
    {
        "id": "0f844904-cd40-4623-a3cd-facf9ef83f97",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_655.txt",
        "created": 1737369282,
        "question": "When and where will the VR study be conducted?",
        "answer": "The study will be conducted between November 2023 and April 2024 in Marsstra\u00dfe 20-22 Room 282 (80335 M\u00fcnchen).",
        "request_id": "d28c57e806725fdf746884ebc1073199"
    },
    {
        "id": "a43bba2f-1e80-42fd-8bea-82f2b1e86eda",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_655.txt",
        "created": 1737369282,
        "question": "What is the duration and compensation for participating in the VR study?",
        "answer": "Participation in the study will take about two hours, for which participants will be compensated with \u20ac25.",
        "request_id": "d28c57e806725fdf746884ebc1073199"
    },
    {
        "id": "d12036b8-a9dd-461f-af0d-7e247bce6002",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_655.txt",
        "created": 1737369282,
        "question": "How can one participate in the VR study?",
        "answer": "Interested participants should send an email to the provided address expressing their desire to participate. Participation will be determined based on availability.",
        "request_id": "d28c57e806725fdf746884ebc1073199"
    },
    {
        "id": "a2ff7c85-83e2-4591-80e7-8bcdbb719cae",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_656.txt",
        "created": 1737369406,
        "question": "Is there an issue with the application and applicant numbers in the system?",
        "answer": "Everything is correct in the system (regarding the application and applicant numbers), there is no issue.",
        "request_id": "b64ba4c76389ee8891921aa9cd1683bb"
    },
    {
        "id": "9465e39c-8582-4db7-b4de-253b169bccbe",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_657.txt",
        "created": 1737369292,
        "question": "Does a course titled 'Introduction to AI (5 ECTS)' and a Bachelor's thesis on AI chatbots, focusing on their various use cases (15 ECTS), meet the criteria for the practical project requirement for the TUM M.Sc. program 'AI in Society'?",
        "answer": "The final decision is subject to the aptitude committee. However, judging from your description, it should be fine topic-wise.",
        "request_id": "53c4740236dd97bf424b1cc1d49bf0c4"
    },
    {
        "id": "bd206233-18cc-45d7-8858-30b755c1cf7c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_658.txt",
        "created": 1737369412,
        "question": "What is the requirement for a study programme to be included in the 'International Programmes in Germany 2024/25' database?",
        "answer": "The study programme must meet certain criteria for international orientation, including that German language skills below B2 are required.",
        "request_id": "de8a76bb326ffcd52ced22e0f1d65251"
    },
    {
        "id": "d52f7746-8176-42cc-977c-dd5e51bf44af",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_658.txt",
        "created": 1737369412,
        "question": "What are the costs for publishing a study programme in the 'International Programmes in Germany 2024/25' database?",
        "answer": "The costs for publication in this online database are 100 Euros for a basic entry or 600 Euros for a premium entry with images, videos, etc. The TUM CST covers the costs for basic entries, while the respective faculty covers the costs for premium entries.",
        "request_id": "de8a76bb326ffcd52ced22e0f1d65251"
    },
    {
        "id": "fe32d0c3-41bf-44f6-9f9c-d5da557b7a43",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_658.txt",
        "created": 1737369412,
        "question": "What is the deadline for submitting entries for the 'International Programmes in Germany 2024/25' database?",
        "answer": "Entries must be submitted and approved by 03.05.2023.",
        "request_id": "de8a76bb326ffcd52ced22e0f1d65251"
    },
    {
        "id": "377be6e0-46bb-44cd-8f4d-6b36a6827249",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_658.txt",
        "created": 1737369412,
        "question": "What is the accreditation status of the AI in Society programme at TUM?",
        "answer": "The AI in Society programme at TUM is accredited until 30.11.2028.",
        "request_id": "de8a76bb326ffcd52ced22e0f1d65251"
    },
    {
        "id": "6063a565-ee7b-4749-b2df-4c226487bd10",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_658.txt",
        "created": 1737369412,
        "question": "What should be selected for the '\u00dcbertragungsweg der Rechnung' and 'Email address for digital invoice' fields when creating an entry for the 'International Programmes in Germany 2024/25' database?",
        "answer": "For the '\u00dcbertragungsweg der Rechnung', 'no' should be selected. The 'Email address for digital invoice' field can be left blank as the data for all basic entries will be entered on 03.05.",
        "request_id": "de8a76bb326ffcd52ced22e0f1d65251"
    },
    {
        "id": "65ea3ec3-bf5f-436a-9e75-a4913e600cb1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_659.txt",
        "created": 1737369296,
        "question": "What does the criterion 'Accreditation' mean in the portal?",
        "answer": "The criterion 'Accreditation' refers to whether the study programme is accredited or registered for accreditation.",
        "request_id": "8d0eaac174e09ba6ec2da6853457c50e"
    },
    {
        "id": "89a2cc55-ee72-408d-a3bb-0888ca002d50",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_659.txt",
        "created": 1737369296,
        "question": "What should be selected for 'I want a collective invoice (Sammelrechnung)'?",
        "answer": "For 'I want a collective invoice (Sammelrechnung)', 'No' should be selected.",
        "request_id": "8d0eaac174e09ba6ec2da6853457c50e"
    },
    {
        "id": "1c4d5d68-798e-4433-8d44-2eefa01d9fd5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_659.txt",
        "created": 1737369296,
        "question": "What should be selected for '\u00dcbertragungsweg der Rechnung'?",
        "answer": "For '\u00dcbertragungsweg der Rechnung', you can leave the fields empty. The data for all basic entries will be entered on 03.05.",
        "request_id": "8d0eaac174e09ba6ec2da6853457c50e"
    },
    {
        "id": "71278c9f-e6fd-4c3a-8078-f8ef8b822b86",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_659.txt",
        "created": 1737369296,
        "question": "What happens if the study programme is not released by 03.05.2023?",
        "answer": "If the study programme is not released by 03.05.2023, the costs must be borne by the faculties themselves.",
        "request_id": "8d0eaac174e09ba6ec2da6853457c50e"
    },
    {
        "id": "d0307683-ce4e-4c2d-9fa1-9e48afc6fb5d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_659.txt",
        "created": 1737369296,
        "question": "What is the cost for publishing in the 'International Programmes in Germany 2024/25' database?",
        "answer": "The cost for publishing in the 'International Programmes in Germany 2024/25' database is 100 Euros for basic entries and 600 Euros for premium entries with images, videos, etc.",
        "request_id": "8d0eaac174e09ba6ec2da6853457c50e"
    },
    {
        "id": "241c2e5e-76e7-4941-82bd-684a9387f865",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_661.txt",
        "created": 1737369427,
        "question": "Should I select 'yes' for 'I want a collective invoice (Sammelrechnung)'?",
        "answer": "No, you should select 'no'.",
        "request_id": "2b248558d298a9d5caf3417b57ee3886"
    },
    {
        "id": "ecd8121c-fb3c-4c61-b029-9ef4dc87fa9e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_661.txt",
        "created": 1737369427,
        "question": "What should be selected for '\u00dcbertragungsweg der Rechnung'?",
        "answer": "You can leave these fields empty. The data for all basic entries will be entered on 03.05.",
        "request_id": "2b248558d298a9d5caf3417b57ee3886"
    },
    {
        "id": "90da971f-481a-4004-82c3-611e46e6a8ce",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_661.txt",
        "created": 1737369427,
        "question": "Do I need to enter anything for '\u00dcbertragungsweg der Rechnung' and 'Email address for digital invoice'?",
        "answer": "You need to enter something, otherwise you cannot release the entry.",
        "request_id": "2b248558d298a9d5caf3417b57ee3886"
    },
    {
        "id": "47056bee-838f-493b-8232-3106b08a67b0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_663.txt",
        "created": 1737369433,
        "question": "Is it possible for / would TUM consider my Masters degree which is quantitatively heavier than my Bachelors degree, in addition to my Bachelors degree and count it towards achieving the 48 points in Part 1 of the application process when I submit my application to this program?",
        "answer": "For this part, we can only consider the applicants\u2019 Bachelors degrees. However, if you completed some projects in your Masters that could count towards e.g. the 18 ECTS practical project requirement, you are welcome to list them there (in this case, please provide your Masters degree transcript as well).",
        "request_id": "bc50f7e202903e99dd56a47e1e940978"
    },
    {
        "id": "e6701e59-5606-4012-955a-65ae73787ea9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_663.txt",
        "created": 1737369433,
        "question": "I completed one internship during my bachelors studies. However, is it possible / would TUM consider my internship experience gained during my Masters degree and/or my six (6) plus years of professional experience working for the [REDACTED] Department of Transportation as a [REDACTED] in lieu of these 18 ECTS credit hours?",
        "answer": "Yes, it is possible to provide evidence of practical experience that was not gained as part of your studies, but rather as working experience or similar. In this case, please provide us some documents (like a certificate of employment), which indicates to us: a) the content of your work, and b) the duration (18 ECTS are equivalent to 540 hours of work). Same thing applies to your internship experience.",
        "request_id": "bc50f7e202903e99dd56a47e1e940978"
    },
    {
        "id": "4eb5beb4-e01a-44d1-b210-97ade51bfcb7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_669.txt",
        "created": 1737369327,
        "question": "What is the concern about credit to ECTS conversion of the transcript?",
        "answer": "The concern is about the conversion rate from the applicant's credit to ECTS. The applicant is from a five-year Bachelor of Architecture program, which according to 30 ECTS per semester, should include 300 ECTS in total. However, the credits needed to graduate from this program is 204 credits in five years, leading to a conversion rate of about 1.5.",
        "request_id": "6039283f7708600ab0f9971b9fc50b60"
    },
    {
        "id": "f0a072d3-50c1-4cf2-a301-2e92efc5227c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_669.txt",
        "created": 1737369327,
        "question": "What is the proof of passing module in mathematics?",
        "answer": "The applicant has 4 credits in a mathematics course, which is equal to 6 ECTS. This has already surpassed the requirement.",
        "request_id": "6039283f7708600ab0f9971b9fc50b60"
    },
    {
        "id": "319590f5-b479-4a53-812c-dbbfbc9393d1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_669.txt",
        "created": 1737369327,
        "question": "What is the request regarding the five-year program for architecture students?",
        "answer": "The applicant requests that the five-year program for architecture students be considered when reviewing their application materials.",
        "request_id": "6039283f7708600ab0f9971b9fc50b60"
    },
    {
        "id": "74573eec-1d1a-49b9-95a2-8f2261892d75",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_670.txt",
        "created": 1737369334,
        "question": "Is it possible to submit an application for the AI in Society master\u2019s program before completing the APS process and obtaining the VPD certificate, and provide these documents at a later stage?",
        "answer": "No, incomplete applications cannot be accepted, and applicants cannot submit certain documents after the deadline (May 31) has passed.",
        "request_id": "3cb0e79123b8b0cd9d6dd1608eb23c7f"
    },
    {
        "id": "3241879e-050f-4a6c-8000-a314f96cd385",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_671.txt",
        "created": 1737369447,
        "question": "Does the AI in Society master's program at TUM focus on developing AI or integrating this technology into multiple projects?",
        "answer": "The AI in Society master's program at TUM does provide opportunities to code, such as the modules \u201cIntro to Programming & [REDACTED]\u201d, \u201cIntro to [REDACTED]\u201d, \u201c[REDACTED]\u201d, \u201c[REDACTED]\u201d. However, the course is not intended to make you an AI engineer. If you would like to focus on the technical side, it is recommended to apply to the Master\u2019s in [REDACTED] or similar at TUM.",
        "request_id": "e629ab10bd7c4f194ddf22eb802b7218"
    },
    {
        "id": "d008c21e-b096-4044-b913-51c8b387286d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_671.txt",
        "created": 1737369447,
        "question": "Is the AI in Society master's program at TUM suited for someone who comes from a [REDACTED] bachelor's degree with a Business but also some technical understanding?",
        "answer": "The course is highly interdisciplinary and a background in business is a plus. If you have some technical understanding, it will already be a great help for you. It should not be a problem.",
        "request_id": "e629ab10bd7c4f194ddf22eb802b7218"
    },
    {
        "id": "fdcfe6a7-f9d8-49dc-8b95-b891f0079684",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_671.txt",
        "created": 1737369447,
        "question": "Will it be possible for me to work part-time in a company while I study the AI in Society master's program at TUM?",
        "answer": "It is possible to work part-time, but the study load (especially in the first 1-2 semesters) is not low. You will have to try and see if it works out for you.",
        "request_id": "e629ab10bd7c4f194ddf22eb802b7218"
    },
    {
        "id": "83f8d5d2-ead8-4424-9fea-6df85ea7df6d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_671.txt",
        "created": 1737369447,
        "question": "How does the timetable look for the AI in Society master's program at TUM? Is it only classes in the morning or only classes in the evening, or a mix?",
        "answer": "The scheduling is up to the professors and many courses are not set up yet, since the degree program is under active construction at the moment. It cannot be confirmed whether the courses will be rather in the morning or rather in the evening.",
        "request_id": "e629ab10bd7c4f194ddf22eb802b7218"
    },
    {
        "id": "81442f0e-ffd6-4712-a1b5-d25f0bb6244d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_673.txt",
        "created": 1737369462,
        "question": "Would a practical project on 'data-driven marketing strategy with a customer-centred approach' be valid for the application to the dual study programme?",
        "answer": "Your topic sounds very suitable - this should work out well.",
        "request_id": "3e125b7fb3a9d188ec38af479cd86de2"
    },
    {
        "id": "2e8845e5-874d-4939-94b2-777e60ea718c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_673.txt",
        "created": 1737369462,
        "question": "Is there any further information on how the admission test is structured and what questions can be expected?",
        "answer": "For now, you can refer to the rough topics that can be found on our website (https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/). We will try our best to publish more in-depth information surrounding the test as soon as we can.",
        "request_id": "3e125b7fb3a9d188ec38af479cd86de2"
    },
    {
        "id": "3f429cd4-e7c9-4d0b-9201-7bed85b6486a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_675.txt",
        "created": 1737369468,
        "question": "If my degree program was taught in English, do I need to provide an IELTS test or similar?",
        "answer": "If your degree program was taught in English, you do not need to provide us an IELTS test or similar. Please instead get a confirmation about the language of instruction from your university.",
        "request_id": "1fcf79b9d2672ee30443fe4df7e254c5"
    },
    {
        "id": "f0235122-6c21-43f0-acde-668174602db0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_675.txt",
        "created": 1737369468,
        "question": "Where can I find more information about the application process for the M.Sc. AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "You can find all information on our website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/ More information about the application process can be found here: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/ For an extensive overview over the required application documents and procedure, please see here: https://www.tum.de/studium/studienangebot/detail/ai-in-society",
        "request_id": "1fcf79b9d2672ee30443fe4df7e254c5"
    },
    {
        "id": "255a0900-6225-4853-aa8d-10a620fce908",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_675.txt",
        "created": 1737369468,
        "question": "Where can I find more information about scholarships at TUM?",
        "answer": "Regarding scholarships, I would kindly redirect you to TUM\u2019s scholarship office. For more information and their contact, please see here: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/fees-and-financial-aid/scholarships",
        "request_id": "1fcf79b9d2672ee30443fe4df7e254c5"
    },
    {
        "id": "136b8f9d-97ad-445a-b379-7d0369f596de",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_676.txt",
        "created": 1737369341,
        "question": "Can I still apply for the Master in AI in Society program at TUM if I lack the requirement of a thesis or project with credits from my Bachelor degree?",
        "answer": "You can prove your practical expertise through work experience as well, it doesn\u2019t necessarily have to be a university course. You might have, for example, worked at a company during your studies, where you were working on projects relevant to our study field. This experience also counts, but you will need to submit suitable proof for this (e.g. in the form of a certificate of employment). For reference, 18 ECTS credits correspond to a workload of 540 hours. If you submit such proof of practical experience (which was not part of your degree program), it needs to indicate how much time you spent on it, and have it correspond to our 18 ECTS requirement. It also has to be clear to us what exactly you were working on.",
        "request_id": "5a5761fe621e62a7055eccddcfc281c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "7187416d-12c5-420b-a0ef-fcf7da979701",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_676.txt",
        "created": 1737369341,
        "question": "Am I eligible to apply to the Master in AI in Society program at TUM with a bachelor GPA of 2.4?",
        "answer": "Eligibility is calculated based on the grades of your best modules (there will be a form for you to fill inside the application process). It is not definitively stated whether a GPA of 2.4 will pass.",
        "request_id": "5a5761fe621e62a7055eccddcfc281c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "4db848f2-5966-402b-b9f3-f89a7d7273d0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_676.txt",
        "created": 1737369341,
        "question": "Will my age be an issue for application to the Master in AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Your age is definitely not a problem in any way.",
        "request_id": "5a5761fe621e62a7055eccddcfc281c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "c787b237-dec3-4350-826e-7bfd3d15477d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_678.txt",
        "created": 1737369352,
        "question": "Can I apply for the M.Sc. AI in Society program at TUM if I don't have a bachelor's thesis or a project with credits, but have extensive work experience?",
        "answer": "Yes, you can prove your practical expertise through work experience. This might include working on projects relevant to the study field during your employment. However, you will need to submit suitable proof for this, such as a certificate of employment. The proof of practical experience needs to indicate how much time you spent on it, and it should correspond to the 18 ECTS requirement of the program. It also has to be clear what exactly you were working on.",
        "request_id": "462fad64fc0dabf593696a0b0510ee2e"
    },
    {
        "id": "b6c307bb-c285-4340-b599-85fefff80db6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_679.txt",
        "created": 1737369480,
        "question": "Can you provide further information about the application process for the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "More information about the application process can be found on the website: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/. For an extensive overview over the required application documents and procedure, please see here: https://www.tum.de/studium/studienangebot/detail/ai-in-society.",
        "request_id": "bff0fcdecf0713a93064471763e4dc67"
    },
    {
        "id": "8be2643e-2437-4fcb-849e-f2ec8abbd68d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_681.txt",
        "created": 1737369484,
        "question": "How to Prepare the [REDACTED] and [REDACTED] be Included?",
        "answer": "[REDACTED] should be informative about the contents of the module.",
        "request_id": "18258af06b82adf51bfee5f4f748ed81"
    },
    {
        "id": "753ee018-225f-46cd-b946-f266614424cd",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_681.txt",
        "created": 1737369484,
        "question": "How should we study for the written exam?",
        "answer": "We will publish some more information about the written aptitude test in due time on our website.",
        "request_id": "18258af06b82adf51bfee5f4f748ed81"
    },
    {
        "id": "bd5e983b-5eb8-47c6-bdb2-dd2977b7c974",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_681.txt",
        "created": 1737369484,
        "question": "Is there any scholarship opportunity available for the program? International students are required to pay 4000 euros.",
        "answer": "Maybe this information can be helpful to you regarding scholarships and waivers: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/fees/tuition/scholarships-and-waivers",
        "request_id": "18258af06b82adf51bfee5f4f748ed81"
    },
    {
        "id": "d5a587dd-bc49-4adc-8744-a68f7fcd5148",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_681.txt",
        "created": 1737369484,
        "question": "[REDACTED] courses taken in bachelor degree studies replace IELTS or TOEFL? For example; Is it sufficient to have taken 21 ECTS credits in English for applying to this program?",
        "answer": "Please find the relevant information here under \u201cVerification of [REDACTED] by Language of Instruction\u201d: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/application/application-info-portal/admission-requirements/language-certificates",
        "request_id": "18258af06b82adf51bfee5f4f748ed81"
    },
    {
        "id": "b9ecea41-a3a2-4e07-b5b3-aebb1b668817",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_682.txt",
        "created": 1737369358,
        "question": "Why was the request for 'Preliminary review documentation (VPD) or Confirmation that the application for a VPD by uni-assist has been submitted in due form and time' not there before?",
        "answer": "Applications are reviewed on a rolling basis. Meaning that if something is missing in your application, you will be contacted again.",
        "request_id": "e7b6974ca86817559a486dcf0f7df8ec"
    },
    {
        "id": "e2eeb492-d77a-4feb-a141-08deaaab99fb",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_682.txt",
        "created": 1737369358,
        "question": "What exactly is wrong with my CV?",
        "answer": "As far as I can see in the system, your CV is fine. There is no issue marked.",
        "request_id": "e7b6974ca86817559a486dcf0f7df8ec"
    },
    {
        "id": "6c4d1fca-25eb-4c13-ad37-e6aafcc1b319",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_682.txt",
        "created": 1737369358,
        "question": "When doing the application for AI & Society, there is no place to insert the VPD. So, can I assume that I don't have to upload the VPD?",
        "answer": "If you were not asked for a VPD anywhere, it should be fine.",
        "request_id": "e7b6974ca86817559a486dcf0f7df8ec"
    },
    {
        "id": "d7a152a4-fe0e-40e4-8d42-aa46698ec64e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_682.txt",
        "created": 1737369358,
        "question": "How long more or less does it take to get an answer in the application?",
        "answer": "This might happen over the next 2-3 weeks.",
        "request_id": "e7b6974ca86817559a486dcf0f7df8ec"
    },
    {
        "id": "e4ea562b-3fc4-4bf6-8fbf-a0270b4a6487",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_682.txt",
        "created": 1737369358,
        "question": "What should I do about the VPD requirement in my application?",
        "answer": "You have indicated that you have applied for the VPD in full. Your proof of this has been received and provisionally OK. The document is now only set to 'not OK' so that you can upload the final VPD here. Uni-assist will email you the final VPD once it is complete. Please upload the final VPD for TUM here as soon as you receive it. However, if we then discover that your documents have not been received by [REDACTED] in full by the deadline, you will be excluded from the application process. Depending on how old your previous VPD is, you can submit it here again (we accept VPDs that are up to 3 years old). Otherwise, you must submit a new VPD.",
        "request_id": "e7b6974ca86817559a486dcf0f7df8ec"
    },
    {
        "id": "4c750a01-7145-4e61-bc91-e638a56e47fe",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_687.txt",
        "created": 1737369377,
        "question": "What is the deadline for the application process?",
        "answer": "The deadline for the application process is May 31st.",
        "request_id": "f3d8a77413a3e5a56b8074d0a9eb64f5"
    },
    {
        "id": "b12142ec-e6f2-45fb-b6c8-2fb83b1e23a9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_687.txt",
        "created": 1737369377,
        "question": "Can changes be made to the application after it has been completed?",
        "answer": "No, once the application has been completed, it cannot be changed, even within the exclusion period.",
        "request_id": "f3d8a77413a3e5a56b8074d0a9eb64f5"
    },
    {
        "id": "744d3af6-6cae-4396-a927-a8bd59fd3c93",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_687.txt",
        "created": 1737369377,
        "question": "Can the certificate and the Bachelor's degree be submitted later?",
        "answer": "Yes, the certificate and the Bachelor's degree can be submitted up to 5 weeks after the start of the lecture. However, this only applies to the submission of the certificate itself. It is not intended that examination achievements from the Bachelor's degree, which are only completed after the application deadline, can be submitted later.",
        "request_id": "f3d8a77413a3e5a56b8074d0a9eb64f5"
    },
    {
        "id": "73661018-0ff1-4aba-af43-135705b6f7e7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_687.txt",
        "created": 1737369377,
        "question": "Can examination achievements be submitted after the exclusion period?",
        "answer": "No, examination achievements cannot be submitted after the exclusion period.",
        "request_id": "f3d8a77413a3e5a56b8074d0a9eb64f5"
    },
    {
        "id": "dc9ebfea-c653-4f88-9fc4-c7e6734df56c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_687.txt",
        "created": 1737369377,
        "question": "Can applicants submit proof of practical experience in the form of their Bachelor's thesis if it is not completed at the time of application?",
        "answer": "No, it is not intended that examination achievements from the Bachelor's degree, which are only completed after the application deadline, can be submitted later.",
        "request_id": "f3d8a77413a3e5a56b8074d0a9eb64f5"
    },
    {
        "id": "7191456b-6e5a-4a30-86b9-5956f9affc4c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_688.txt",
        "created": 1737369386,
        "question": "What is the application deadline for the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The application deadline is May 31st.",
        "request_id": "d4e7f977dfb9c31399f799a2c6072c62"
    },
    {
        "id": "23be8667-94c5-4e03-a480-0a1bbda97595",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_688.txt",
        "created": 1737369386,
        "question": "What documents are required for the application to the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "All required documents, including the proof of practical experience worth at least 18 credits, need to be submitted.",
        "request_id": "d4e7f977dfb9c31399f799a2c6072c62"
    },
    {
        "id": "36dcdef2-a605-4bea-8f1a-5696a5d69467",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_688.txt",
        "created": 1737369386,
        "question": "Can applicants submit documents after the application deadline for the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "No, applicants cannot submit any documents after the deadline has passed.",
        "request_id": "d4e7f977dfb9c31399f799a2c6072c62"
    },
    {
        "id": "deb0242b-c555-4df5-b062-95a8bc339837",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_688.txt",
        "created": 1737369386,
        "question": "Can multiple practical projects be submitted as part of the application to the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Yes, it doesn\u2019t need to be one single project: you can submit several ones, which will then be summed up.",
        "request_id": "d4e7f977dfb9c31399f799a2c6072c62"
    },
    {
        "id": "8c38f804-3893-416e-80ff-70f31bc427ff",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_688.txt",
        "created": 1737369386,
        "question": "Can practical experience outside of the degree program be considered for the M.Sc. AI in Society program application?",
        "answer": "Yes, practical experience outside of your degree program can be considered. This might include work at a company during your studies, where you were working on projects relevant to the study field. However, suitable proof for this, such as a certificate of employment, needs to be submitted.",
        "request_id": "d4e7f977dfb9c31399f799a2c6072c62"
    },
    {
        "id": "bcf1170e-f84e-4114-882f-aa0fbba7f307",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_689.txt",
        "created": 1737369395,
        "question": "Why do different study programs handle their admission process differently?",
        "answer": "Different study programs have different requirements for their prospective students. For example, some programs put a high weight on the applicant\u2019s ability to complete practical projects and bring along background knowledge in certain fields, which are tested in the aptitude test.",
        "request_id": "4603cdaa9be7975013dfa1274df93516"
    },
    {
        "id": "5923592b-27a0-436f-be37-1aff4d2765d6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_689.txt",
        "created": 1737369395,
        "question": "What is the importance of the aptitude test in the admission process for the Master's program 'AI in Society'?",
        "answer": "The aptitude test is used to assess an applicant's ability to complete practical projects and their background knowledge in certain fields.",
        "request_id": "4603cdaa9be7975013dfa1274df93516"
    },
    {
        "id": "a5d018d7-4e0b-44ef-b1b5-255935d5785e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_690.txt",
        "created": 1737369403,
        "question": "Does the practical project need to be recognized with credits, i.e. does it have to be part of my university course?",
        "answer": "Technically, we can count practical projects that were not part of a university module. However, you would then need to provide us with an official documentation that those practical projects in total spanned at least 540 hours for completion (540h correspond to 18 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "181fe643a047826703535b847d1b8a04"
    },
    {
        "id": "fc4abee1-ec62-4fad-88d2-93b47f44cdb5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_690.txt",
        "created": 1737369403,
        "question": "Would individual projects or volunteer experience be able to also contribute to the requirement?",
        "answer": "Individual projects can contribute to the requirement if you can provide official documentation that those practical projects in total spanned at least 540 hours for completion (540h correspond to 18 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "181fe643a047826703535b847d1b8a04"
    },
    {
        "id": "0a843a79-aaf0-4df3-917f-5442691e890d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_690.txt",
        "created": 1737369403,
        "question": "Can the project be part of a course or does it have to stand individually?",
        "answer": "The project can be part of a course. You don\u2019t need to submit your project reports to prove your completion of the module. Instead, you submit your Transcript of Records as part of the application procedure (this module should then of course be listed in this Transcript), as well as fill out a form which states the name of the project module, as well as the module/project description.",
        "request_id": "181fe643a047826703535b847d1b8a04"
    },
    {
        "id": "2762cd10-477e-4a1e-b02d-d68381aad3e1",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_690.txt",
        "created": 1737369403,
        "question": "How can I prove the projects that I did in the courses?",
        "answer": "You don\u2019t need to submit your project reports to prove your completion of the module. Instead, you submit your Transcript of Records as part of the application procedure (this module should then of course be listed in this Transcript), as well as fill out a form which states the name of the project module, as well as the module/project description.",
        "request_id": "181fe643a047826703535b847d1b8a04"
    },
    {
        "id": "6cf124ec-1254-473b-b630-6792ba8728b9",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_691.txt",
        "created": 1737369413,
        "question": "Do the 18 ECTS from a practical project, required for the Master's program AI in Society, have to come from a single project or can they be composed of two different projects?",
        "answer": "The credits for the practical project do not have to come from a single module. They can be summed up from several modules, so that is not a problem.",
        "request_id": "83419d542f82a0a0e43a32f4bd3545a5"
    },
    {
        "id": "b4016325-d70c-4dfa-8648-a3d17f9c25e3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_691.txt",
        "created": 1737369413,
        "question": "Is it a problem for the application if my bachelor's thesis is not yet completed at the time of my application, so I will not have a grade or ECTS for it yet?",
        "answer": "If you do not have the credits for the bachelor's thesis at the time of application, it is a problem insofar as you cannot use these as proof for the practical project. It is also not possible to submit evidence for the 'Practical Project' requirement afterwards. These must be available at the end of the application -- I ask for your understanding.",
        "request_id": "83419d542f82a0a0e43a32f4bd3545a5"
    },
    {
        "id": "5098b769-e88a-4770-8ea9-52d70266f897",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_691.txt",
        "created": 1737369413,
        "question": "Can I make up for the missing 6 ECTS through professional experience or other relevant (extracurricular) activities?",
        "answer": "You may be able to prove the missing 6 ECTS through professional experience or other relevant (extracurricular) activities.",
        "request_id": "83419d542f82a0a0e43a32f4bd3545a5"
    },
    {
        "id": "e879e533-b16c-41c2-8465-939f84ef1a06",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_692.txt",
        "created": 1737369423,
        "question": "Do I need to submit an English proficiency certificate for the M.Sc. AI in Society program if my degree\u2019s language of instruction was English?",
        "answer": "If your degree\u2019s language of instruction was English, you do not have to submit additional proof of English proficiency.",
        "request_id": "11fe91b91a2ac8e2dc4ed02af129d52c"
    },
    {
        "id": "0295fb3b-c1ed-4526-aa67-d95ec6babafe",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_692.txt",
        "created": 1737369423,
        "question": "Can I be exempted from submitting an English proficiency certificate for the M.Sc. AI in Society program if I studied in the UK for the last year of my double degree bachelor program and obtained 60 ECTS including the bachelor's thesis?",
        "answer": "If your degree\u2019s language of instruction was English, you do not have to submit additional proof of English proficiency.",
        "request_id": "11fe91b91a2ac8e2dc4ed02af129d52c"
    },
    {
        "id": "6d54d17f-5675-423d-8e33-ee844f97d603",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_697.txt",
        "created": 1737369434,
        "question": "What should an applicant with pre-diploma qualifications do when having difficulties applying to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The applicant should ask their universities if they can issue the relevant ECTS or, if not possible, the respective SWS for their degree. If these documents can be obtained, they should be uploaded or sent to the admissions team.",
        "request_id": "e68f70b28cf9b1a7bc3ed48c17abe4c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "6205caee-52af-4c5c-8c0c-0892c585446f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_697.txt",
        "created": 1737369434,
        "question": "How should an applicant with a diploma degree proceed when applying to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The applicant should upload the documents they have or can obtain. If they can submit a grade transcript or semester study plans that further highlight the thematic content of the studies, that would be helpful.",
        "request_id": "e68f70b28cf9b1a7bc3ed48c17abe4c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "d56b652d-bb49-4b40-ba3c-9411b314d778",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_697.txt",
        "created": 1737369434,
        "question": "How does the aptitude committee assess practical experience for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The aptitude committee decides if an applicant has suitable/sufficient practical experience. Applicants should submit evidence of their work, such as employment references.",
        "request_id": "e68f70b28cf9b1a7bc3ed48c17abe4c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "33228105-c8b7-4de2-be2f-bb3c136e0820",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_697.txt",
        "created": 1737369434,
        "question": "What should be done if an applicant with a diploma degree cannot provide ECTS credits?",
        "answer": "The applicant should not be formally rejected because they have a diploma degree and therefore cannot provide ECTS credits. The diploma engineer is a highly renowned degree comparable to a master's degree. The applicant should be allowed into the aptitude process just like applicants with a bachelor's degree if the submitted documents show that they have the necessary competencies.",
        "request_id": "e68f70b28cf9b1a7bc3ed48c17abe4c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "6a1cd43f-1394-4496-b8e7-91e402c9b55c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_697.txt",
        "created": 1737369434,
        "question": "How should grades from a diploma degree be considered in the application process for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "In case of doubt, the overall average grade should be used for the points for the grade (Annex 2, No. 5.1.1 a) Sentence 10).",
        "request_id": "e68f70b28cf9b1a7bc3ed48c17abe4c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "6c104633-7432-43d5-b04c-37d2ea000d49",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_699.txt",
        "created": 1737369450,
        "question": "Will the Aptitude test and interview be online?",
        "answer": "It is not yet decided if an online version of the aptitude test will be offered, but it is currently planned. The interview can be conducted online if there is no way of conducting it in person.",
        "request_id": "a931bae6744425486a6322b8f368e5bb"
    },
    {
        "id": "64f5c1e0-6a83-42d5-8aac-2ee92f41c92a",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_699.txt",
        "created": 1737369450,
        "question": "Do you have the dates more or less when it will happen?",
        "answer": "Exact dates are not available, but it is expected to happen mid-June. The exact date will be communicated at least one week in advance.",
        "request_id": "a931bae6744425486a6322b8f368e5bb"
    },
    {
        "id": "b9ae3038-e94c-4be2-8c8e-25a551bc2c29",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_700.txt",
        "created": 1737369455,
        "question": "What should I do if the document for listing undergraduate modules does not provide enough space for all my modules?",
        "answer": "You should download the document twice and use the extra rows from the second copy. Then upload both forms. It would be great if you could fuse the two documents into one PDF before uploading.",
        "request_id": "ee40e0b09cff12ae43f3de71c11b7faa"
    },
    {
        "id": "030c85c8-fe24-4759-9b89-71e989a962d6",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_701.txt",
        "created": 1737369130,
        "question": "Is it needed to ask for the VPD when I have already a Master's degree from TUM?",
        "answer": "If you were not asked for a VPD anywhere, it should be fine.",
        "request_id": "2632858e51e6feebeacb4804340ba082"
    },
    {
        "id": "b6b168a0-3954-4201-a906-5975827232dc",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_701.txt",
        "created": 1737369130,
        "question": "When doing the application for AI & Society, there is no place to insert the VPD. So, can I assume that I don't have to upload the VPD?",
        "answer": "If you were not asked for a VPD anywhere, it should be fine.",
        "request_id": "2632858e51e6feebeacb4804340ba082"
    },
    {
        "id": "ad28b9b6-16f4-4b3d-971e-500550496280",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_701.txt",
        "created": 1737369130,
        "question": "How long more or less does it take to get an answer in the application?",
        "answer": "Applications are reviewed on a rolling basis. If something is missing in your application, you will be contacted again. If everything is fine, you will also get informed. This might happen over the next 2-3 weeks.",
        "request_id": "2632858e51e6feebeacb4804340ba082"
    },
    {
        "id": "db670cce-4aa7-438a-a977-72203939ff6e",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_702.txt",
        "created": 1737369138,
        "question": "What is the application procedure for the M.Sc. \u201cAI in Society\u201d at TUM?",
        "answer": "All relevant information for the application procedure can be found on the following websites: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/degree-programs/detail/ai-in-society and https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/",
        "request_id": "db9bd10b2e9c828b5df109f8873d7b58"
    },
    {
        "id": "8f820314-f905-4fab-a2d0-5e4aca9ad004",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_702.txt",
        "created": 1737369138,
        "question": "Do I need to go through the college for one year to have access to the course or do I have access directly to it from my current situation?",
        "answer": "You need to apply with a Bachelor\u2019s degree. If during the application period (until May 31st) you will not have finished your bachelor\u2019s degree yet, 140 ECTS credits of your Bachelor\u2019s studies are sufficient, assuming that you will finish your Bachelor\u2019s degree still before the start of the Master\u2019s.",
        "request_id": "db9bd10b2e9c828b5df109f8873d7b58"
    },
    {
        "id": "e8b6a461-2100-4e58-bfe2-c193595e5362",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_703.txt",
        "created": 1737369147,
        "question": "Do I fulfill the requirement for the practical project for the M.Sc. AI in Society at TUM if I sum all of the credits for which I had a project and it is over 18 ECTS?",
        "answer": "You should submit the entire modules as proof for the practical project requirement. Your case might become a question for the admission committee to decide upon. For now, count the entire modules containing those practical projects inside of them.",
        "request_id": "ea36d6faa582e6f2421e310f7cd3a6c9"
    },
    {
        "id": "4daa5667-2cde-4879-8b50-9a51efda34c0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_704.txt",
        "created": 1737369151,
        "question": "Can a bachelor's thesis in the field of data analysis, which is worth 12 ECTS, be recognized as equivalent to the 'practical project' requirement of at least 18 credits for the AI in Society master's program?",
        "answer": "The bachelor's thesis can be counted towards the practical project requirement, but as it only covers 12 ECTS, it is not entirely sufficient. Additional practical-oriented modules from the bachelor's program or relevant experience outside of studies, if properly documented, can be used to cover the remaining 6 ECTS. For example, if the experience is from a relevant part-time student job, an employment certificate would be a good proof. To cover the missing 6 ECTS, a proof that this experience has covered at least 6x30h = 180h is required, along with a description of this project.",
        "request_id": "962ad954b62d71698316412086f5d5e0"
    },
    {
        "id": "daa08cd8-f98e-4d19-878a-a9a255ef2715",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_705.txt",
        "created": 1737369178,
        "question": "Can you tell where I can find the list of the admission requirements for the AI and society master?",
        "answer": "The following links should work and contain all relevant information: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/, https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/, https://www.tum.de/en/studies/degree-programs/detail/ai-in-society.",
        "request_id": "29a66442d332cb325d7465ffc487435b"
    },
    {
        "id": "e6f381f3-dbd8-4ab2-ae9b-8bde63408e91",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_705.txt",
        "created": 1737369178,
        "question": "Could you send me a link of the website that doesn\u2019t work for you?",
        "answer": "The website link that doesn\u2019t work is https://www.sot.tum.de/en/sot/404-notfound-sot-en/.",
        "request_id": "29a66442d332cb325d7465ffc487435b"
    },
    {
        "id": "44bde722-483d-46a8-92bc-35a20710cd7d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_706.txt",
        "created": 1737369185,
        "question": "Where can I find the list of the admission requirements for the AI and Society master's program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The admission requirements for the AI and Society master's program at TUM can be found at the following links: https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/, https://www.sot.tum.de/sot/studium/ai-in-society/application/, https://www.tum.de/en/studies/degree-programs/detail/ai-in-society.",
        "request_id": "3e11155830c0d19766b2f8c424cf827d"
    },
    {
        "id": "08837e37-6585-4d67-9f97-2d2acc71826d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_706.txt",
        "created": 1737369185,
        "question": "What happens when the website page showing the additional admission requirements doesn't work?",
        "answer": "If the website page showing the additional admission requirements doesn't work, you can reach out for assistance and you will be provided with working links that contain all relevant information.",
        "request_id": "3e11155830c0d19766b2f8c424cf827d"
    },
    {
        "id": "395b1cef-7450-4ffa-9d02-2be0646d5116",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_707.txt",
        "created": 1737369192,
        "question": "Could you send me a link of the website that doesn\u2019t work for you? Does it not load?",
        "answer": "Here is the website link that doesn\u2019t work. It just show and error404. https://www.sot.tum.de/en/sot/404-notfound-sot-en/",
        "request_id": "849b1ee6c99e518b95963c3aab07f265"
    },
    {
        "id": "45f62c87-f4c0-40e8-bcd5-2ff9ae1bf8a4",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_708.txt",
        "created": 1737369197,
        "question": "What is the minimum mathematics/statistics background required for the program?",
        "answer": "The examination regulation requires 5 ECTS of mathematics and/or statistics obtained as part of previous study programs.",
        "request_id": "92ad552a11a60010d41398c83f416cb0"
    },
    {
        "id": "d6f6cf1a-ce90-4947-942f-4d1ca7916bca",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_708.txt",
        "created": 1737369197,
        "question": "Can the mathematics/statistics requirement be fulfilled through participation in online courses?",
        "answer": "No, the requirement cannot be made up for through participation in online courses.",
        "request_id": "92ad552a11a60010d41398c83f416cb0"
    },
    {
        "id": "706520d0-c98b-42c6-9cc3-0ecec793bc6f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_708.txt",
        "created": 1737369197,
        "question": "Do the attached transcripts fulfil the minimum requirements of mathematics/statistics background?",
        "answer": "No, the attached transcripts do not fulfil the minimum requirements of mathematics/statistics background.",
        "request_id": "92ad552a11a60010d41398c83f416cb0"
    },
    {
        "id": "8bc9f314-8a83-486c-aa99-855ac545eae3",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_709.txt",
        "created": 1737369204,
        "question": "Is it possible to use multiple practical projects (each 4-8 ECTS) as valid proof if they together are \u2265 18 ECTS?",
        "answer": "Yes, it does not have to be a single project over 18 ECTS, it can also be accumulated from several projects.",
        "request_id": "ef2c8881a69270bb6442f57b16ee3d1e"
    },
    {
        "id": "a0289f3b-28db-4888-ad8f-fd076d1dcd38",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_711.txt",
        "created": 1737369212,
        "question": "How should applicants with pre-diploma qualifications proceed when applying to the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "Applicants should ask their universities if they can issue the relevant ECTS or, if not possible, the respective SWS for their degree. If these documents can be obtained, they should be uploaded or sent to the admissions team.",
        "request_id": "a60d9172d0edbe59e2c15744c792081b"
    },
    {
        "id": "e23317d8-b594-4182-957f-d2f88ec7c482",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_711.txt",
        "created": 1737369212,
        "question": "How does the aptitude committee assess practical experience for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "The aptitude committee decides if an applicant has suitable/sufficient practical experience. Applicants should submit evidence of their work, such as employment references.",
        "request_id": "a60d9172d0edbe59e2c15744c792081b"
    },
    {
        "id": "fd7a3310-f567-4dfe-bb21-cacb5f13f606",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_714.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "Does the practical project need to be recognized with credits, i.e. does it have to be part of my university course?",
        "answer": "Technically, practical projects that were not part of a university module can be counted.",
        "request_id": "96f47c692a6d21033b0f7d77e1e5c92f"
    },
    {
        "id": "3d5326df-c8a4-4527-9285-5a8dbe7f8145",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_714.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "Would individual projects or volunteer experience be able to also contribute to the requirement?",
        "answer": "Individual projects can contribute to the requirement, but they need to be officially documented, showing that they spanned at least 540 hours for completion (540h correspond to 18 ECTS).",
        "request_id": "96f47c692a6d21033b0f7d77e1e5c92f"
    },
    {
        "id": "85c77952-d50c-4f3d-8075-6f46774b07ed",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_714.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "Can the project be part of a course or does it have to stand individually?",
        "answer": "The email does not provide a clear answer to this question.",
        "request_id": "96f47c692a6d21033b0f7d77e1e5c92f"
    },
    {
        "id": "6c2fa310-c9a4-4fb9-b2c4-1875027b9c51",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_714.txt",
        "created": 1737369221,
        "question": "If from my university, I do not officially have 18 credits for a practical project in social science, is there a way to make up for this requirement?",
        "answer": "Yes, by providing official documentation of practical projects that in total spanned at least 540 hours for completion.",
        "request_id": "96f47c692a6d21033b0f7d77e1e5c92f"
    },
    {
        "id": "852fc67a-9ce1-433a-8e6e-5ffb9b3b6fa5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_715.txt",
        "created": 1737369230,
        "question": "What should I do if my foreign university's courses are not provided in the form of modules and I have more courses than the provided rows in the 'List of best 140 Credits' form for the 'AI in Society' master program application?",
        "answer": "You can download the respective form two times to fill in all your courses, then mark which is the first, and which is the second (e.g. insert \u201c1\u201d and \u201c2\u201d somewhere on the PDF), and upload both of them. You may need to merge these two PDFs back into one.",
        "request_id": "c1084bbeaa145a10ced85b0b6aa9e16e"
    },
    {
        "id": "1614eaf7-9417-4f3b-8ecb-4fc7f7e60646",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_716.txt",
        "created": 1737369235,
        "question": "When is the application deadline for the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Applications are open until May 31st.",
        "request_id": "a9a5a808acb623551e69366a51e34372"
    },
    {
        "id": "fb541a8a-582b-44a6-87b1-5b85373d7e39",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_716.txt",
        "created": 1737369235,
        "question": "When will the review of application documents take place for the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The review of application documents will take place after the application deadline of May 31st.",
        "request_id": "a9a5a808acb623551e69366a51e34372"
    },
    {
        "id": "b2457d07-700a-45ef-aaff-1153a81f633d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_716.txt",
        "created": 1737369235,
        "question": "When will applicants be invited to the written aptitude test for the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Applicants will be invited to the written aptitude test after the review of their application documents, which will be after May 31st.",
        "request_id": "a9a5a808acb623551e69366a51e34372"
    },
    {
        "id": "119d90a3-19b3-4cd7-b8ad-148a39b09ac0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_716.txt",
        "created": 1737369235,
        "question": "What format should the documentation of the completed project take for the M.Sc. AI in Society application?",
        "answer": "To prove your completion of a practical project, you will find a form to fill out inside the application process. There you will be asked to enter the module title and module description. These should be translated into English and inserted in the form.",
        "request_id": "a9a5a808acb623551e69366a51e34372"
    },
    {
        "id": "421927d2-1fb0-4e79-ada6-987da4858a24",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_716.txt",
        "created": 1737369235,
        "question": "Is the original thesis document, accompanied by an English introduction summarizing it, sufficient as proof of the project's completion for the M.Sc. AI in Society application?",
        "answer": "You do not need to submit your thesis for the application. For proof, you will have to provide your Transcript of Records when you\u2019re applying. This module should also be listed there.",
        "request_id": "a9a5a808acb623551e69366a51e34372"
    },
    {
        "id": "d3db1e36-2f99-450a-937e-7cea67adb00b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_717.txt",
        "created": 1737369245,
        "question": "What format should the documentation of the completed project take?",
        "answer": "To prove your completion of a practical project, you will find a form to fill out inside the application process. There you will be asked to enter the module title and module description. Please translate these into English and insert in the form.",
        "request_id": "79b5194f6e53f0520bf1b4e047e8bc9d"
    },
    {
        "id": "41f6267f-0722-48f2-89cb-c02302bcf71f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_717.txt",
        "created": 1737369245,
        "question": "Since my thesis was not written in English, would the original thesis document, accompanied by an English introduction summarizing it, suffice as proof of the project's completion?",
        "answer": "For proof, you will also have to provide your Transcript of Records when you\u2019re applying. This module should also be listed there. It would be best if you could submit a Transcript of Records issued by your university in English. If your university does not provide this document in English automatically, please ask them to issue an [REDACTED] for you. You do not need to submit your thesis for the application.",
        "request_id": "79b5194f6e53f0520bf1b4e047e8bc9d"
    },
    {
        "id": "0e7f8111-6262-4256-8df3-9ce407fb9e63",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_718.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "Is it possible to get a waiver for the requirement to provide an IELTS or TOEFL certificate if my Master's program was conducted entirely in English?",
        "answer": "If your language of instruction was English, this is already sufficient.",
        "request_id": "7f329b262a75265b8582fc057c061cf5"
    },
    {
        "id": "5267f2a4-f5e1-4292-a3f5-c7f4cdffcf70",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_718.txt",
        "created": 1737369253,
        "question": "If I am eligible for a waiver of the English proficiency certificate, would it be necessary for my university to provide a document verifying that English was the language of instruction during my Master's studies?",
        "answer": "If you wish to submit a confirmation of your language of instruction as proof of your English language proficiency, the confirmation has to be issued by an administrative unit of the university on official university paper and has to bear a seal and an original signature.",
        "request_id": "7f329b262a75265b8582fc057c061cf5"
    },
    {
        "id": "956731a9-9f44-4013-9184-deb08826680f",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_719.txt",
        "created": 1737369259,
        "question": "Does the practical project for the AI for society program need to be recognized with credits, i.e. does it have to be part of my university course?",
        "answer": "The recognition of qualifications achieved outside of a university is possible. If the content condition of engineering/natural science knowledge + political-social knowledge + practical application is fulfilled and a volume of at least 18 credits = 540 hours can be proven, it could be recognized as a practical project.",
        "request_id": "f533bd7dd79ff6cc39856efd6deb7623"
    },
    {
        "id": "48bb0c10-1681-439b-9f09-1a40d27e03b0",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_719.txt",
        "created": 1737369259,
        "question": "Would individual projects or volunteer experience be able to also contribute to the requirement for the AI for society program?",
        "answer": "If the content condition of engineering/natural science knowledge + political-social knowledge + practical application is fulfilled and a volume of at least 18 credits = 540 hours can be proven, individual projects or volunteer experience could be recognized as a practical project.",
        "request_id": "f533bd7dd79ff6cc39856efd6deb7623"
    },
    {
        "id": "6248164c-aa47-4e2c-815e-54452788e715",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_719.txt",
        "created": 1737369259,
        "question": "If from my university, I do not officially 18 credits for a practical project in social science, is there a way to make up for this requirement for the AI for society program?",
        "answer": "If the content condition of engineering/natural science knowledge + political-social knowledge + practical application is fulfilled and a volume of at least 18 credits = 540 hours can be proven, it could be recognized as a practical project.",
        "request_id": "f533bd7dd79ff6cc39856efd6deb7623"
    },
    {
        "id": "c05f7da8-bfab-4286-9a78-d38b568f1b47",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_719.txt",
        "created": 1737369259,
        "question": "What kind of proof is needed to verify the hours spent on a practical project for the AI for society program?",
        "answer": "A credible documentation of practical experience is important. Verifiable documents that confirm content and scope should be able to be presented.",
        "request_id": "f533bd7dd79ff6cc39856efd6deb7623"
    },
    {
        "id": "0d5a54b2-1843-41a3-a5af-d6b6d2ed47ce",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_721.txt",
        "created": 1737369277,
        "question": "How can I apply for a Master\u2019s program at TUM?",
        "answer": "To be admitted to any study program, you need to apply through TUM\u2019s official application website. Professors cannot admit you themselves. More information can be found at: https://www.tum.de/en/studies/application/application-info-portal/online-application",
        "request_id": "601b3da9b16eb8e5f7846c9a8d1a1d1c"
    },
    {
        "id": "c20844f9-27d6-4c70-86ce-6ec8475eba07",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_721.txt",
        "created": 1737369277,
        "question": "Who will send the link to the application portal for the MSc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Ms. [REDACTED] will send a link to the application portal.",
        "request_id": "601b3da9b16eb8e5f7846c9a8d1a1d1c"
    },
    {
        "id": "00447c1d-1be5-4209-b44c-d29779508491",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_723.txt",
        "created": 1737369288,
        "question": "Are there any limitations on who can apply for the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "There are no limitations on who can apply, per se. It does not matter which Bachelor\u2019s program you have studied specifically. It only matters that you fulfil the requirements.",
        "request_id": "464b56589ffccb64a1d68cbc77c1a915"
    },
    {
        "id": "a44bc3e9-d39f-4133-861b-b75e1ff21386",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_723.txt",
        "created": 1737369288,
        "question": "What are the requirements for applying to the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The requirements include having passed at least 5 ECTS from the fields of mathematics / statistics, as well as having completed a practical project worth at least 18 ECTS.",
        "request_id": "464b56589ffccb64a1d68cbc77c1a915"
    },
    {
        "id": "db54ddcb-e806-426e-bb2d-26fa4741002b",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_723.txt",
        "created": 1737369288,
        "question": "What does the requirement of 'List of [REDACTED]' mean for the M.Sc. AI in Society program application?",
        "answer": "The 'List of [REDACTED]' requirement asks you to submit your best 140 ECTS credits, meaning, listing the modules where you got the best grades, overall worth 140 credits. The information about 90 credits is referring to something different and is not relevant for this Master\u2019s.",
        "request_id": "464b56589ffccb64a1d68cbc77c1a915"
    },
    {
        "id": "95a49ef9-c7c2-40d0-b88c-668fe8e6e28d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_724.txt",
        "created": 1737369295,
        "question": "What are the requirements for the practical project for the MSc. AI in Society application?",
        "answer": "If you have completed at least 18 ECTS (your bachelor's thesis can also be counted) in a/multiple practical project(s), which involve a) some sort of technical tools and b) some societal aspect, we highly encourage you to apply. If you have the 18 ECTS, but aren't quite sure if the topics of your projects fit perfectly, please apply regardless.",
        "request_id": "adea039894224f577f0aba2f7405ecac"
    },
    {
        "id": "af1fa93f-c575-40a8-be07-9f1bd4b1dbac",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_728.txt",
        "created": 1737369317,
        "question": "Is it valid to upload the proof of classes that I have taken that relate to the field of AI and society for the 'Proof of successful participation in a practical project relevant to the course of study within at least 18 credits including module description' requirement?",
        "answer": "The practical project should be one you have completed as part of your studies and must be worth at least 18 ECTS credits. If you additionally participated in a relevant project outside of your studies, you can incorporate it in an optional motivational letter.",
        "request_id": "eb95cfa0d0d47f404f42b19a6182e9e9"
    },
    {
        "id": "51dce0fa-699a-497f-9090-1540c0c683b2",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_728.txt",
        "created": 1737369317,
        "question": "Can I apply to this master with some documents that I already have from October of last year from my Bachelors degree in Colombia?",
        "answer": "If your 86% correspond to at least 140 ECTS credits, then this is sufficient. However, your completed modules also need to include at least 5 ECTS from the fields of mathematics or statistics.",
        "request_id": "eb95cfa0d0d47f404f42b19a6182e9e9"
    },
    {
        "id": "b4e728f6-dd65-4ce6-85a2-fd5d70e29560",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_728.txt",
        "created": 1737369317,
        "question": "Can I use a VPD from uni-assist from October last year for the application?",
        "answer": "If you still have a valid VPD, there is no need to get a new one. Please submit the one you already have.",
        "request_id": "eb95cfa0d0d47f404f42b19a6182e9e9"
    },
    {
        "id": "fa22f397-25bc-46ce-b1b4-93103a1df67c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_728.txt",
        "created": 1737369317,
        "question": "If I don't have the project that you are inquiring about, is it worthy giving it a try to the application?",
        "answer": "If you have completed projects during your studies that are roughly in the field we describe (even if not matching perfectly), we highly encourage you to apply.",
        "request_id": "eb95cfa0d0d47f404f42b19a6182e9e9"
    },
    {
        "id": "e050cc76-1856-45f8-a2e5-bb3a43d54672",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_729.txt",
        "created": 1737369331,
        "question": "As an applicant for the AI in Society program who has just registered for FAU's summer semester master's program, do I need to go through the transfer process or can I directly use my Bachelor degree to apply?",
        "answer": "You can directly apply with your bachelor\u2019s degree. You do not need to go through any additional transfer processes. However, if you complete relevant courses during your semester in FAU\u2019s program, feel free to list them as well. You will need to deregister from your old university.",
        "request_id": "91d5e0673e5c079097ba23ca7b07283d"
    },
    {
        "id": "1b4fe29f-9e3e-4232-a1b0-3c11556a6491",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_729.txt",
        "created": 1737369331,
        "question": "Do I need to add FAU's study experience to my resume when applying for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "If you complete relevant courses during your semester in FAU\u2019s program, feel free to list them as well.",
        "request_id": "91d5e0673e5c079097ba23ca7b07283d"
    },
    {
        "id": "97b5e438-8149-4baa-8223-c59f5aaa89ff",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_729.txt",
        "created": 1737369331,
        "question": "What is required to submit when applying for the AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "Submitting your bachelor\u2019s transcript of records is mandatory, and the best 140 ECTS credits based on your bachelor\u2019s degree will be counted.",
        "request_id": "91d5e0673e5c079097ba23ca7b07283d"
    },
    {
        "id": "7f5b11ad-e1b4-4c44-847c-d1ca8bb16d68",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_730.txt",
        "created": 1737369339,
        "question": "Can my bachelor's and master's theses be considered as practical projects for the AI in Society program at TUM?",
        "answer": "You should submit any relevant module that you have completed during your previous studies. Any practical project which you have received credits for will be counted if it is relevant content-wise.",
        "request_id": "f138955d62785d7e62daa318fea3540d"
    },
    {
        "id": "3e20b46e-54b2-4c47-8dab-1146a13e0022",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_731.txt",
        "created": 1737369342,
        "question": "While looking at the admission requirements for the AI in Society program, it says a practical project of at least 18 ECTS is required. Since the bachelor program of TUM Informatik only offers thesis of 15 credits, does this mean I will not be qualified, even if the content of the thesis project is qualified for the application?",
        "answer": "If your thesis spans 15 ECTS and fits well into the field of technology applied to social sciences, then we highly encourage you to apply anyways! You may have taken another practical course during your bachelor\u2019s studies that would provide the missing 3 ECTS \u2013 please list them all in the application process (even if they do not fit the required theme perfectly).",
        "request_id": "0b69680863228272b0d7c4aa787164f6"
    },
    {
        "id": "6fb16418-7105-4f01-b307-0c10246aed9c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_731.txt",
        "created": 1737369342,
        "question": "What should I do if the application process requires more information?",
        "answer": "There will be separate forms to fill in this information in a more organized manner soon. Check back inside the application platform in around a week and apply with the provided forms.",
        "request_id": "0b69680863228272b0d7c4aa787164f6"
    },
    {
        "id": "a5430751-e913-473f-ac1a-c2f836355b08",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_733.txt",
        "created": 1737369354,
        "question": "What is the format of the list of the best 140 ECTS along with the proof of the practical project worth at least 18 ECTS credits completed during bachelor\u2019s studies that I need to submit on my online application for the Master of Science - AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "The respective forms for the list of the best 140 ECTS and the proof of the practical project worth at least 18 ECTS credits will be provided inside the application platform in about a week.",
        "request_id": "28ba06ab02df33e73b36230450451889"
    },
    {
        "id": "29c04ed1-ee0d-4a7b-834f-d26243285962",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_734.txt",
        "created": 1737369359,
        "question": "How can I prove my project has 18 ECTS for the AI in Society MSc. program application?",
        "answer": "A form is being prepared that will allow you to enter information about your practical project in an organized manner. This form will also explain how to calculate whether your project's credits correspond to at least 18 ECTS credits. You will need to provide the module description of this project, which you may need to obtain from the instructor of the module.",
        "request_id": "3a72eb49edc92b4f7d91a9e9df3388e0"
    },
    {
        "id": "1860435e-0324-4f27-9ee2-e7e2799edf7d",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_734.txt",
        "created": 1737369359,
        "question": "Can projects that do not incorporate a social science perspective be counted towards the practical project requirement for the AI in Society MSc. program?",
        "answer": "Projects that do not incorporate some sort of social science perspective cannot be counted towards the practical project requirement. However, you are welcome to include them in the optional motivational letter.",
        "request_id": "3a72eb49edc92b4f7d91a9e9df3388e0"
    },
    {
        "id": "f23f53f6-e74c-4ac8-90f5-f83ddb58cf05",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_734.txt",
        "created": 1737369359,
        "question": "What should I do if there is no document regarding the content of the project in my university's system?",
        "answer": "You may need to reach out to the instructor of the module and ask for an official module description.",
        "request_id": "3a72eb49edc92b4f7d91a9e9df3388e0"
    },
    {
        "id": "823ceebf-c7c9-426e-ab69-c3e04ae961e7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_735.txt",
        "created": 1737369367,
        "question": "Is it valid to upload the proof of classes that I have taken that relate to the field of AI and society for the 'Proof of successful participation in a practical project relevant to the course of study within at least 18 credits including module description' requirement?",
        "answer": "The practical project should be a project you have completed as part of your studies, since it must be worth at least 18 ECTS credits. If you additionally participated in a relevant project outside of your studies, you are welcome to incorporate it in an optional motivational letter.",
        "request_id": "7bc518d0decc17d6df482432b926a25e"
    },
    {
        "id": "c5e16101-d8e7-4e20-9112-e95bd8ab64fa",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_735.txt",
        "created": 1737369367,
        "question": "Can I apply to the M.Sc. AI in Society program with some documents that I already have from October of last year from my Bachelors degree in Colombia?",
        "answer": "If your 86% correspond to at least 140 ECTS credits, then this is sufficient. However, your completed modules also need to include at least 5 ECTS from the fields of mathematics or statistics.",
        "request_id": "7bc518d0decc17d6df482432b926a25e"
    },
    {
        "id": "a1415ed4-57f4-46be-b769-e96d2a84a793",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_735.txt",
        "created": 1737369367,
        "question": "Can I use a VPD from uni-assist from October last year for my application to the M.Sc. AI in Society program?",
        "answer": "If you still have a valid VPD, there is no need to get a new one. Please submit the one you already have.",
        "request_id": "7bc518d0decc17d6df482432b926a25e"
    },
    {
        "id": "0837ff2d-22f0-4098-ba95-e6e2059fd3c5",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_737.txt",
        "created": 1737369378,
        "question": "Would my current MMT degree provide any exemptions or benefits during the application process to MSc AI in Society?",
        "answer": "An additional Master\u2019s degree (e.g. in MMT) does not provide particular benefits for you regarding the application process, except for the (optional) motivational letter you can hand in. If you can incorporate your previous studies into a motivation of why you are particularly interested in the study program, please feel free to do so.",
        "request_id": "541a746735b587afa488c38301b49d39"
    },
    {
        "id": "63401ed7-1d96-4c83-aef0-a0dcd2a5b7c7",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_737.txt",
        "created": 1737369378,
        "question": "Can I request for recognition of modules from the MMT program in the AIS program?",
        "answer": "Depending on your modules from the MMT program, you may hand in a request for recognition of those modules in case they are either the same lectures also taught in AIS, or equivalent content-wise. For this you have time until up to one year after admission to the AIS program.",
        "request_id": "541a746735b587afa488c38301b49d39"
    },
    {
        "id": "b5f7eac6-1d0e-4680-88f9-8c0069c6471c",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_737.txt",
        "created": 1737369378,
        "question": "Would I still be required to pay the standard application fee, or are there any fee waivers or reductions available for current international students?",
        "answer": "There are no particular exceptions for fees. For general information about fees for international students, refer to the TUM website.",
        "request_id": "541a746735b587afa488c38301b49d39"
    },
    {
        "id": "4b009572-261c-4ec1-ac9c-87b4e93d5151",
        "source_type": "email",
        "source_id": "email_738.txt",
        "created": 1737369387,
        "question": "Would my current MMT degree provide any exemptions or benefits during the application process to MSc AI in Society?",
        "answer": "It depends on whether there were modules completed in the MMT program that also appear in the AIS study plan. Including this information in the motivation letter might also be beneficial for the application process.",
        "request_id": "b99ce11c7fcc42c02dfe94887075b772"
    }
]
